<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!-- MY XSLT document to transform the RSS feed into an XHTML page. -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl" media="screen" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<image>
  		<url>https://extinction.fyi/img/extinction-fyi-logo.webp</url>
  		<title>extinction.fyi logo</title>
		<link>https://extinction.fyi</link>
		</image>
		<title>extinction.fyi</title>
		<link>https://extinction.fyi/</link>
 		<description>Documenting the climate emergency</description>
		<category>Climate change/Climate emergency/Climate action</category>


<!--
		<item>
			<title></title>
			<link></link>
			<source url=""></source>
			<description></description>
			<pubDate></pubDate>
		</item>
		
		Using special characters in XML - https://www.dvteclipse.com/documentation/svlinter/How_to_use_special_characters_in_XML.3F.html
-->
		<item>
			<title>Why Spy Agencies Say the Future Is Bleak</title>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/opinion/global-trends-intelligence-report.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/opinion/global-trends-intelligence-report.html">New York Times</source>
			<description>The world envisioned in the 144-page report, ominously subtitled &#34;A More Contested World,&#34; is rent by a changing climate, aging populations, disease, financial crises and technologies that divide more than they unite, all straining societies and generating &#34;shocks that could be catastrophic.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rise of atmospheric carbon dioxide continues unabated</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/apr/17/rise-atmospheric-carbon-dioxide-covid-climate</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/apr/17/rise-atmospheric-carbon-dioxide-covid-climate">The Guardian</source>
			<description>When carbon dioxide levels were last at this level, 3.6m years ago, sea levels were 20 metres higher and vast areas now covered in ice were forested. Land where many of our coastal cities now stand and much of our food is grown were deep under water. Large areas in the tropics would have been uninhabitable because they would have been too hot.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A New Threat to New York&#39;s Clean Energy Goals&#58; Bitcoin Mining</title>
			<link>https://www.nysfocus.com/2021/04/13/new-york-bitcoin-mining-threat/</link>
			<source url="https://www.nysfocus.com/2021/04/13/new-york-bitcoin-mining-threat/">New York Focus</source>
			<description>A decade ago, the bankrupt owner of the Greenidge power plant in Dresden, New York, sold the uncompetitive coal-fired relic for scrap and surrendered its operating permits. For the next seven years, the plant sat idle on the western shore of Seneca Lake, a monument to the apparent dead end reached by the state’s fossil fuel infrastructure. But today, Greenidge is back up and running as a Bitcoin mining operation. The facility hums with energy-hungry computers that confirm and record Bitcoin transactions, drawing power from the plant’s 106-megawatt generator now fueled by natural gas.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>New Google Earth feature shows 40 years of devastating climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/google-earth-update-climate-timelapse-b1831967.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/google-earth-update-climate-timelapse-b1831967.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>&#34;Our planet has seen rapid environmental change in the past half-century — more than any other point in human history. Many of us have experienced these changes in our own communities&#59; I myself was among the thousands of Californians evacuated from their homes during the state’s wildfires last year. For other people, the effects of climate change feel abstract and far away, like melting ice caps and receding glaciers,&#34; a Google representative said in the search giant’s announcement.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Therapists are reckoning with eco&#45;anxiety</title>
			<link>https://www.stuff.co.nz/environment/climate-news/300279032/therapists-are-reckoning-with-ecoanxiety</link>
			<source url="https://www.stuff.co.nz/environment/climate-news/300279032/therapists-are-reckoning-with-ecoanxiety">Stuff.nz</source>
			<description>There&#39;s growing recognition in the field of psychology that people are experiencing distress over climate change. More than 40 per cent of Americans felt &#34;disgusted&#34; or &#34;helpless&#34; about climate change, according to a survey published by researchers at Yale University. A 2020 poll from the APA found that more than half of respondents were somewhat or extremely anxious about the effects of climate change on their own mental health. Though not officially classified in the DSM-5, the tome therapists use to classify and treat mental illnesses, there&#39;s a name for this state of despair that has emerged from academic texts and media since as recently as 2007&#58; eco-anxiety.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>To save the planet, focus on corporate-tax free riders</title>
			<link>https://www.ft.com/content/663cba6f-391e-4789-908e-b560936f2eaf</link>
			<source url="https://www.ft.com/content/663cba6f-391e-4789-908e-b560936f2eaf">Financial Times</source>
			<description>Free riders matter in combating rising temperatures, because global emissions of greenhouse gases are the core problem. Countries and their populations know that if they make a special effort to be green, others will free ride or cheat in any deal, so there is no incentive to make the required effort. You can see the outcome clearly in the data. The concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere has not deviated from its steady upward march after 30 years of UN climate conferences.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate Research Station Abandoned Because It’s Falling Into the Sea</title>
			<link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/climate-research-station-abandoned-falling-into-sea</link>
			<source url="https://futurism.com/the-byte/climate-research-station-abandoned-falling-into-sea">Futurism</source>
			<description>Natural phenomena have always shaped and reshaped the coastline of Cape Cod. But the process has seemingly accelerated thanks to the impacts of global climate change, especially during recent storm seasons. At some points, according to the Guardian, up to six feet of land was getting swallowed up over the course of a single day.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Oil firm bosses&#39; pay &#39;incentivises them to undermine climate action&#39;</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/15/oil-firm-ceos-pay-is-an-incentive-to-resist-climate-action-study-finds</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/15/oil-firm-ceos-pay-is-an-incentive-to-resist-climate-action-study-finds">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The study tracks ExxonMobil, Chevron, Shell and BP &#45; four of the biggest &#34;carbon major&#34; oil companies &#45; since 1990. This was around the time the global public heard the first high-profile warning about the dangers of burning fossil fuels. Executives had been told of the threat many years earlier, but instead of working on a transition to cleaner, safer forms of energy, they ramped up production, played down risks and adopted public relations campaigns that misleadingly presented oil companies as part of the solution rather than the source of the problem.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Only 3 per cent of world surface is ecologically intact, research suggests</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/world-ecologically-intact-three-percent-b1831803.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/world-ecologically-intact-three-percent-b1831803.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Only 2.8 per cent of the world’s land surface is &#34;functionally intact&#34;, meaning there has been no loss of species to a point that would affect the healthy functioning of an ecosystem. This was 10 times lower than previous estimates. The research, published in the journal Frontiers in Forests and Global Change, also estimated estimated around 2.9 per cent of the world’s land surface can be considered &#34;faunally intact&#34; without any loss of animal species.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Wildlife in decline as report reveals shocking state of UK&#39;s woods and trees</title>
			<link>https://www.standard.co.uk/news/uk/wildlife-decline-report-state-uk-woods-trees-b929573.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.standard.co.uk/news/uk/wildlife-decline-report-state-uk-woods-trees-b929573.html">Evening Standard</source>
			<description>Climate change is affecting the pattern of the seasons, with spring occurring around 8.4 days earlier, impacting wildlife such as blue tits which can find their breeding cycles now mismatch their food supply for chicks. While native woods and trees can help curb carbon emissions and reverse declines in wildlife, failing to address the problems will undermine efforts to tackle both the climate and nature crises.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Green-collared jobs aren&#39;t going to create themselves &#45; the government needs a clear plan</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/green-jobs-climate-change-cop26-workforce-b1831241.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/green-jobs-climate-change-cop26-workforce-b1831241.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>If we look at the current workforce, more needs to be done to map out where we can repurpose skills and how to enable this shift to begin this year. Training on the job is crucial to support the transition but also re-focus skillsets towards net-zero roles. By being able to take time out of work to complete training and development alongside their current jobs, we can start to plug gaps in areas where skills can be transferred. It&#39;s a solution that can work for all people across different backgrounds and experiences.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change and the &#34;law of acceleration&#34;</title>
			<link>https://www.resilience.org/stories/2021-04-11/climate-change-and-the-law-of-acceleration/</link>
			<source url="https://www.resilience.org/stories/2021-04-11/climate-change-and-the-law-of-acceleration/">Resilience</source>
			<description>Climate scientists tell us we need not just a deceleration in growth of greenhouse gas emissions, but actual rapid declines to address climate change with any hope of success. Given how we think about acceleration, it’s hard to imagine that our global society will seek accelerated reductions in emissions as a primary goal.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>France approves ban on short-haul flights in climate push</title>
			<link>https://uk.finance.yahoo.com/news/france-approves-ban-on-some-domestic-flights-climate-change-135104389.html</link>
			<source url="https://uk.finance.yahoo.com/news/france-approves-ban-on-some-domestic-flights-climate-change-135104389.html">Yahoo Finance UK</source>
			<description>French officials moved late on Saturday to ban domestic flights on routes that are connected by train and can be travelled in less than two-and-a-half hours. The vote comes as governments around the world look at ways to lower carbon emissions and achieve net-zero targets. 
It forms part of a broader climate bill from France which looks to cut carbon emissions from 1990's levels by 40% by 2030.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Stability in the Middle East now depends on how serious we are about tackling climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/security-energy-climate-change-middle-east-b1828582.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/security-energy-climate-change-middle-east-b1828582.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>In the past, our predominant interests in the region were in counterterrorism and lucrative arms deals. The recent meeting between John Kerry, the US special presidential envoy for climate, and the UK’s own Cop26 president, Alok Sharma, demonstrated that the new common interest is climate change, and especially its link to security.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The &#39;30x30&#39; Campaign to Save the Biosphere</title>
			<link>https://www.worldpoliticsreview.com/articles/29565/the-30x30-campaign-to-save-the-planet-from-biodiversity-threats</link>
			<source url="https://www.worldpoliticsreview.com/articles/29565/the-30x30-campaign-to-save-the-planet-from-biodiversity-threats">World Politics Review</source>
			<description>Over the past two years, an extraordinary global campaign has emerged to protect 30 percent of Earth’s total surface from human exploitation by 2030. The members of this so-called 30x30 coalition, which now includes scores of governments, understand that climate change is only one half of the planet’s environmental crisis. The Paris Agreement, while imperative to curb greenhouse gas emissions, will do little by itself to save the planet’s collapsing biodiversity or preserve the massive ecosystems upon which humanity depends—and which we are fast degrading.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Those who worry about CO2 should worry about methane, too</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/04/03/those-who-worry-about-co2-should-worry-about-methane-too</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/04/03/those-who-worry-about-co2-should-worry-about-methane-too">The Economist</source>
			<description>The importance of tackling methane has become more apparent in the past decade and a half. After a plateau which began in 1999, concentrations of the gas in the atmosphere started rising again in 2007, a trend that continues to this day. At the moment, more than 300m tonnes are emitted every year as a consequence of human activity, and that rate is growing. As a result, methane concentrations are now more than two-and-a-half times what they were before the Industrial Revolution, and are rising faster than allowed for in all but the most pessimistic climate projections for the 21st century.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Could a House Work in a Post Climate Change Scenario&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.archdaily.com/959389/how-could-a-house-work-in-a-post-climate-change-scenario</link>
			<source url="https://www.archdaily.com/959389/how-could-a-house-work-in-a-post-climate-change-scenario">ArchDaily</source>
			<description>The residential units are intended for small-scale living; sustainable, self-sufficient, and technologically hyperconnected. To be built, each unit uses recycled materials of natural and local origin, following the logic of kilometer zero materials. Specifically, the architects propose the use of panels and laminates made with American agave wood, popularly known as "desert wood." Its fibers and roots can be reused to make thermal and acoustic insulation systems, thus avoiding artificial products.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change will hit &#39;endemic&#39; plants and animals the hardest, study warns</title>
			<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-will-hit-endemic-plants-and-animals-the-hardest-study-warns</link>
			<source url="https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-will-hit-endemic-plants-and-animals-the-hardest-study-warns">Carbon Brief</source>
			<description>An endemic species lives exclusively in one geographic region. Areas of high biodiversity are often “overflowing” with endemic &#34;flagship species&#34; &#91;...&#93; The authors find that land-based endemic species are projected to be 2.7 times &#34;more impacted&#34; by climate change than non-endemic native species, and 10 times more impacted than introduced species.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marine species increasingly can&#39;t live at equator due to global heating</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/08/marine-species-increasingly-cant-live-at-equator-due-to-global-heating</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/08/marine-species-increasingly-cant-live-at-equator-due-to-global-heating">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Analysis of the changing locations of almost 50,000 marine species between 1955 and 2015 found a predicted impact of global heating – species moving away from the equator – can now be observed at a global scale.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate disclosure could spark big investments&#58; US climate envoy</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/8/climate-disclosure-could-spark-big-investments-us-climate-envoy</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/8/climate-disclosure-could-spark-big-investments-us-climate-envoy">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>&#34;We have to make the invisible visible &#45; the transition risks that banks are carrying because they’re investing in high-carbon activities that over time are going to be phased out, and the physical risk, investments in highly vulnerable coastal areas, or in agriculture that could be affected by floods or by droughts,&#34; [Kristalina Georgieva, IMF Managing Director] said.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Carbon dioxide levels in atmosphere reach record high</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/07/carbon-dioxide-levels-in-atmosphere-reach-record-high</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/07/carbon-dioxide-levels-in-atmosphere-reach-record-high">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Prof Simon Lewis, from University College London, said: &#34;It is easy to forget just how much and just how fast fossil fuel emissions are affecting our planet. It took over 200 years to increase the amount of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere by 25%, and just 30 years to reach 50% above pre-industrial levels. This dramatic change is like a human meteorite hitting Earth.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Emotional leadership and environmental crises&#58; a view from nineteenth-century Vietnam</title>
			<link>https://blog.history.ac.uk/2021/04/emotional-leadership-and-environmental-crises-a-view-from-nineteenth-century-vietnam/</link>
			<source url="https://blog.history.ac.uk/2021/04/emotional-leadership-and-environmental-crises-a-view-from-nineteenth-century-vietnam/">On History</source>
			<description>In the nineteenth century court of the Nguyen dynasty, it would have been unimaginable to be emotionally detached from the environment, in part because the landscape was understood to be full of sentiment. Royal rule required responding to and mediating these emotional flows through sincere behaviour and ritual practice. Today we might discount the notion that rituals are efficacious in the natural world or that human beings can resonate with an emotional environment. And yet, in the current pandemic and climate emergency the idea of how nature &#34;treats us&#34; is more at play than ever before. In this sense, the problems faced by nineteenth century Vietnamese kings &#45; of how to connect with nature and utilise emotion effectively &#45; are ones we all share.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change&#58; Polar bears forced to eat seabird eggs as Arctic hunting ground shrinks</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/polar-bears-forced-to-eat-seabird-eggs-as-arctic-hunting-ground-shrinks-b1827744.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/polar-bears-forced-to-eat-seabird-eggs-as-arctic-hunting-ground-shrinks-b1827744.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Researchers looked both at predictions for climate heating and data on the increasing portion of the year that the bears&#39; must survive on their fat reserves. Earlier this month, a paper published in the journal Global Change Biology found that polar bears maintained highly specialized diets of soft blubber and flesh for hundreds of years &#45; even during previous periods of Arctic warming.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bitcoin Mining Could Use More Energy Than All of Italy by 2024</title>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en/article/dy8amw/bitcoin-mining-energy-consumption</link>
			<source url="https://www.vice.com/en/article/dy8amw/bitcoin-mining-energy-consumption">VICE</source>
			<description>A team of researchers from the University of Chinese Academy of Sciences in Beijing, Cornell University in the U.S. and University of Surrey in the U.K. warns that if people continue to mine Bitcoin unchecked, the energy consumption associated with those activities could reach 297 Twh per year by 2024, more than the 290 TwH in electricity consumed by Italy in 2019.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Does Carbon Offsetting Really Address the NFT Ecological Dilemma&#63;</title>
			<link>https://hyperallergic.com/634236/does-carbon-offsetting-really-address-the-nft-ecological-dilemma/</link>
			<source url="https://hyperallergic.com/634236/does-carbon-offsetting-really-address-the-nft-ecological-dilemma/">Hyperallergic</source>
			<description>Critics say voluntary offset markets &#45; unlike mandatory compliance offset programs &#45; are largely unregulated, making it challenging to verify whether reductions actually occur. Even when working perfectly, some worry that they function as a form of &#34;greenwashing&#34; by allowing companies to continue burning fossil fuels and emitting CO2. A forest conservation project in Brazil backed by FIFA for the 2014 World Cup was suspended after loggers destroyed more trees than all the credits sold, ProPublica reported. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global warming puts 99% of Great Barrier Reef coral at risk, study finds</title>
			<link>https://www.thenationalnews.com/world/oceania/global-warming-puts-99-of-great-barrier-reef-coral-at-risk-study-finds-1.1197755</link>
			<source url="https://www.thenationalnews.com/world/oceania/global-warming-puts-99-of-great-barrier-reef-coral-at-risk-study-finds-1.1197755">The National</source>
			<description>Coral bleaching in 2016, 2017 and 2020 has further damaged its health and affected its animal, bird and marine population, the International Union for Conservation of Nature said. Bleaching occurs when hotter water destroys the algae that the coral feeds on, causing it to turn white. The report also found that if Australia warmed up to 2°C, only 1 per cent of the reef is expected to survive.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Most countries are making progress on phasing out coal—but not fast enough to offset China&#39;s expansion</title>
			<link>https://energyandcleanair.org/most-countries-are-making-progress-on-phasing-out-coal/</link>
			<source url="https://energyandcleanair.org/most-countries-are-making-progress-on-phasing-out-coal/">Centre for Research on Energy and Clean Air</source>
			<description>Globally, the projected coal-fired capacity in 2030, if all proposed projects are realized and retirements aren’t accelerated further, is almost 2400 GW, while the amount of capacity consistent with the IPCC 1.5 degree pathways would be 1100 GW. An additional 1300 GW will need to be cancelled or retired: 450 GW in the OECD, 500 GW in China and 400 GW in the rest of the world, to meet the emission budgets consistent with limiting global warming to 1.5 degrees.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		
		
		<item>
			<title>How Big Meat Is Funding Climate Denial and Polluting the Planet</title>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/how-big-meat-is-funding-climate-denial-and-polluting-th-1846620142</link>
			<source url="https://earther.gizmodo.com/how-big-meat-is-funding-climate-denial-and-polluting-th-1846620142">Gizmodo</source>
			<description>The United Nations estimates that animal agriculture accounts for more than 14% of global emissions. A seminal 2018 report, which this new analysis builds on, found that the world’s top 35 beef and dairy producers alone account for 15% of all those emissions. One of the gnarliest issues with animal agriculture is, of course, methane produced from cows. Methane is a short-term greenhouse gas &#45; it doesn’t stay in the atmosphere as long as carbon dioxide &#45; but it is substantially more potent and can cause more damage while it’s in there. Research published last year found that global annual methane emissions increased 9% from 2000 to 2017—the equivalent of doubling the total carbon dioxide emissions of Germany or France—largely as a result of agriculture.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change is forcing Indians to migrate far from home</title>
			<link>https://lifestyle.livemint.com/news/big-story/climate-change-and-migration-indians-search-for-greener-pastures-111617348170986.html</link>
			<source url="https://lifestyle.livemint.com/news/big-story/climate-change-and-migration-indians-search-for-greener-pastures-111617348170986.html">Mint Lounge</source>
			<description>According to the Migration Data Portal, which provides comprehensive global migration statistics, &#34;in the first half of 2020 alone, disasters displaced 9.8 million people and remained the leading trigger of new internal displacements globally. Five countries accounted for nearly 75 per cent of the new internal displacements due to disasters in the first half of 2020 with India leading the pack, accounting for nearly three million people, followed by Bangladesh (2.5 million), Philippines (811,000), China (791,000) and Somalia (514,000).&#34; Delta regions that are home to 500 million people worldwide will contribute an inordinate share to such migration, since these areas are considered climate change hot spots, places where high levels of exposure to climate stressors coincide with high levels of vulnerability.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This is how badly climate change has hurt food production</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/2/this-is-how-badly-climate-change-has-hurt-food-production</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/2/this-is-how-badly-climate-change-has-hurt-food-production">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>The loss of productivity comes even as billions has been poured into improving agricultural production through the development of new seeds, sophisticated farm machinery and other technological advances. &#34;Even though globally agriculture is more productive, that greater productivity on average doesn’t translate into more climate resilience,&#34; said Ariel Ortiz&#45;Bobea, an author of the paper and associate professor at Cornell&#39;s Charles H. Dyson School of Applied Economics and Management. The damages to productivity growth aren’t evenly spread across regions. Warmer areas &#45; especially those in the tropics &#45; are more detrimentally affected. Ortiz&#45;Bobea said that coincides with many countries where agriculture makes up a bigger share of the economy.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>China sandstorms highlight threat of climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/03/china-sandstorms-highlight-threat-of-climate-crisis</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/03/china-sandstorms-highlight-threat-of-climate-crisis">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Since 1978 China has been trying to combat encroaching sands from the Gobi Desert region by planting a series of forest strips through its northern areas. This &#34;Great Green Wall&#34; has been somewhat effective at reducing erosion and slowing desert expansion, but does little to knock down high-altitude dust blown in from afar.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Green Investing Is &#34;Definitely Not&#34; Going to Save Our Behinds</title>
			<link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2021/04/green-investing-definitely-not-going-to-save-us-climate-blackrock/</link>
			<source url="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2021/04/green-investing-definitely-not-going-to-save-us-climate-blackrock/">Mother Jones</source>
			<description>BlackRock manages about $7 trillion in assets and, with one of Wall Street’s biggest voices sounding the alarm about the need to deal with the climate crisis, the news was viewed as a pivotal moment for the financial community. But for &#91;Tariq&#93; Fancy, who now runs the digital learning nonprofit Rumie in Toronto, Canada, BlackRock&#39;s move, and the ones it has inspired, contain a fundamental flaw: the climate crisis can never be solved by today&#39;s free markets. &#34;It’s not because they are evil, it’s because the system is built to extract profits,&#34; he said.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Democracy against climate change</title>
			<link>https://voxeurop.eu/en/democracy-against-climate-change/</link>
			<source url="https://voxeurop.eu/en/democracy-against-climate-change/">voxeurop</source>
			<description>The campaign is a citizens initiative for carbon pricing in the EU, born after the suggestion of 27 Nobel Prize winners to &#34;shift taxes from labour to CO2 emissions&#34;. The text asks for revenues to flow into the ecological transition, while taxes on workers are expected to lower.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change top challenge over the next decade, UNESCO global survey finds</title>
			<link>https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/03/1088812</link>
			<source url="https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/03/1088812">UN News</source>
			<description>The survey further showed that while 95 per cent of respondents extoll the importance of global cooperation in overcoming common challenges, only one in four felt confident that the world would be able to address these issues. UNESCO said that &#34;taken together, the results suggest not a lack of appreciation of the importance of multilateralism but rather a crisis of faith in its effectiveness.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Amazon Rain Forest Is in Worse Shape Than We Thought</title>
			<link>https://newrepublic.com/article/161686/amazon-rainforest-worse-shape-thought</link>
			<source url="https://newrepublic.com/article/161686/amazon-rainforest-worse-shape-thought">New Republic</source>
			<description>When you set fire to trees, for instance, as part of slash-and-burn farming or ranching, you&#39;re not just getting rid of a carbon-sucking machine. You&#39;re releasing methane, which is 84 times more potent than carbon dioxide and lingers in the atmosphere for a dozen years. You&#39;re changing the color of the earth’s surface from green to brown or black, which affects how the earth absorbs rather than reflects the sun&#39;s rays. And you&#39;re spraying black carbon into the atmosphere, which changes its reflectivity and traps more heat. All of these factors, the researchers found, work together in extremely complex and little-understood ways.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change: Net zero targets are &#39;pie in the sky&#39;</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56596200</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56596200">BBC News</source>
			<description>&#34;The developed world has occupied almost 80% of the carbon space already, you have 800 million people who don't have access to electricity. You can't say that they have to go to net zero, they have the right to develop, they want to build skyscrapers and have a higher standard of living, you can't stop it,&#34; &#91;Raj Kumar Singh, India's minister for power&#92; told the meeting &#91;organised by the International Energy Agency&#92;.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>It took the Suez Canal crisis to highlight the scale of the polluting shipping sector</title>
			<link>https://www.climatechangenews.com/2021/04/01/took-suez-canal-crisis-highlight-scale-polluting-shipping-sector/</link>
			<source url="https://www.climatechangenews.com/2021/04/01/took-suez-canal-crisis-highlight-scale-polluting-shipping-sector/">Climate Home News</source>
			<description>It&#39;s not just the size of the ships; the world&#39;s fleet has quadrupled in size since the 1980s. That&#39;s increased the strain on our oceans by exacerbating underwater noise levels, harming whales and dolphins. It has caused the rise of plastic waste dumping, oil discharge and the shuttle of invasive species around the globe, causing the extinction of native plants and marine animals.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Decarbonisation in a fraught geopolitical landscape</title>
			<link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/energy/decarbonisation-in-a-fraught-geopolitical-landscape-76246</link>
			<source url="https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/energy/decarbonisation-in-a-fraught-geopolitical-landscape-76246">DownToEarth</source>
			<description>Inevitably, because the path to decarbonisation (and digitalisation) has already transcended the realm of run-of-the-mill economic competition to become embroiled in fraught geopolitics, attention has squarely turned onto the indispensable inputs that are required to produce them. Both the global decarbonisation of the economy and the fourth industrial revolution rely on rare earths and a growing number of other critical minerals (CRMs), such as lithium and cobalt, that are all highly geographically concentrated and vulnerable to disruption. Moreover, the amounts needed will skyrocket moving forward.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What can we do about climate migration&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/w3ct0xbl</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/w3ct0xbl">The Climate Question</source>
			<description>The intensification of conditions due to climate change means more people are being driven from their homes and land by sea level rises, storms, cyclones, drought, erosion, landslides, flooding and salinisation of the land. It's estimated that by 2050, one in every seven people in Bangladesh will become a climate migrant.
</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Melting ice sheets caused global sea levels to rise up to 18 metres, scientists say</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/melting-ice-sheets-caused-global-sea-levels-to-rise-up-to-18-metres-scientists-say-12262567</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/melting-ice-sheets-caused-global-sea-levels-to-rise-up-to-18-metres-scientists-say-12262567">Sky News</source>
			<description>New analysis of geological records show that at the end of the last ice age around 14,600 years ago, meltwater from the former North American and Eurasian ice sheets was actually actually driving the rise, rather than the oft-suspected Antarctic ice sheet.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Why are people not doing more about climate change?</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56500739</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56500739">BBC News</source>
			<description>We commissioned a survey of 1,009 Scots, conducted by Savanta ComRes, which suggests price is putting many people off making greener lifestyle choices.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What would different levels of global warming look like?</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2021/03/30/what-would-different-levels-of-global-warming-look-like</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2021/03/30/what-would-different-levels-of-global-warming-look-like">The Economist</source>
			<description>The purpose of pledges to stabilise temperature rise at close to 1.5°C is to avoid the worst of these consequences. But despite the commitments made in the Paris agreement &#45; and, in the years since, various countries’ plans to reduce their greenhouse-gas emissions to zero &#45; the world is still on track to exceed 2°C of warming. (Even if all countries meet their targets, climate scientists predict that temperatures will rise by 2.3°-2.4°C above pre-industrial levels by the end of the century.) A seemingly small difference in degrees will have a big impact on how habitable the world remains.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Elite minority of frequent flyers &#39;cause most of aviation's climate damage&#39;</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/mar/31/elite-minority-frequent-flyers-aviation-climate-damage-flights-environmental</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/mar/31/elite-minority-frequent-flyers-aviation-climate-damage-flights-environmental">The Guardian</source>
			<description>In the US, 12% of people took 66% of all flights, while in France 2% of people took half of the flights, the report says. In China 5% of households took 40% of flights and in India just 1% of households took 45% of all the flights.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Economists want &#39;drastic&#39; action to stop climate change&#58; Survey</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/3/30/economists-want-drastic-action-to-stop-climate-change-survey</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/3/30/economists-want-drastic-action-to-stop-climate-change-survey">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>The world saw more than 7,300 major natural disasters between 2000 and 2019, which killed some 1.2 million people and cost $3 trillion in damages, according to the UN Office on Disaster Risk Reduction. That compares with about 4,200 disasters, leading to 1.19 million killed and $1.6 trillion in losses during the 20 years previous, the data show.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Japan sees earliest cherry blossom since 1400s &#45; and scientists say it's down to climate change</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/japan-sees-earliest-cherry-blossom-since-1400s-and-scientists-say-its-down-to-climate-change-12260765</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/japan-sees-earliest-cherry-blossom-since-1400s-and-scientists-say-its-down-to-climate-change-12260765">Sky News</source>
			<description>Traditionally, cherry blossom season starts in early to mid-April with residents in Kyoto holding &#34;hanami&#34; celebrations underneath trees to watch the flowers bloom. The full bloom, or Sakura in Japanese, historically occurs on 17 April &#45; but in more recent times, warmer and earlier springs have meant earlier blooms, according to climate change experts.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Half a billion people may face heat of 56°C by 2100</title>
			<link>https://climatenewsnetwork.net/half-a-billion-people-may-face-heat-of-56c-by-2100/</link>
			<source url="https://climatenewsnetwork.net/half-a-billion-people-may-face-heat-of-56c-by-2100/">Climate News Network</source>
			<description>A new computational study in Geophysical Research Letters warns that the 1.5°C target could be passed by 2040, in just two decades. And with higher average temperatures over longer periods, there will inevitably be higher than average extremes of temperature, more often, for longer periods, and over wider ranges.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Renewables met 97% of Scotland&#39;s electricity demand in 2020</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56530424</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56530424">BBC News</source>
			<description>Scotland has some of the most ambitious climate targets in the world, with its Climate Change Bill setting out a legally binding target of reaching net-zero emissions by 2045.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Last thing we need is a &#39;cosy consensus&#39; on climate crisis, warns Ed Miliband</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/mar/29/last-thing-we-need-is-a-cosy-consensus-on-climate-crisis-warns-ed-miliband</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/mar/29/last-thing-we-need-is-a-cosy-consensus-on-climate-crisis-warns-ed-miliband">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The summit this year is seen as a last chance to keep to the goals of the Paris agreement and also to limit temperature rises to well below 2C above pre-industrial levels, with an aspiration to stay below 1.5C within reach. It will be the UK&#39;s most important moment on the world stage for generations, he said, warning that the latest emission figures from the UN, which make clear the world is on course for a catastrophic 3C of warming, were being ignored by too many politicians. &#34;It is like these numbers are the embarrassing uncle we want to pretend does not exist &#45; so let’s talk about everything else, let’s talk about 2050, let’s talk about 2060 ... but we don’t have the luxury of time ... The pressure, the action has got to be now.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Britain decarbonised faster than any other rich country</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/britain/2021/02/15/how-britain-decarbonised-faster-than-any-other-rich-country</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/britain/2021/02/15/how-britain-decarbonised-faster-than-any-other-rich-country">The Economist</source>
			<description>Although gas helped decarbonise Britain&#39;s grid, it is a hindrance when it comes to heating and transport. That is because Britain has one of the world’s most robust and extensive infrastructures for moving gas around; 85% of its 29m homes are heated with gas boilers. In Germany 47% are. Decades of investment in the gas grid mean that Britain&#39;s electricity grid is not as robust as it needs to be in order to carry the extra power required to replace gas in the heating of Britain’s homes. If it is to charge all the cars and run all the heat pumps, the grid will need to be upgraded at a cost of tens of billions of pounds.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>The hard truths of climate change — by the numbers</title>
			<link>https://www.nature.com/immersive/d41586-019-02711-4/index.html?utm_source=pocket-chrome-recs</link>
			<source url="https://www.nature.com/immersive/d41586-019-02711-4/index.html?utm_source=pocket-chrome-recs">Nature</source>
			<description>So far, there is little evidence that political leaders are willing or able to meet their collective Paris targets. Even so, some veteran climate experts see hope in the strikes, marches and other protests that are taking place around the world. &#34;Civil disobedience erupts when injustice has been collectively determined to be unbearable,&#34; says Christiana Figueres, who helped to usher in the Paris agreement as head of the UN climate convention in 2015. &#34;And that is where we are today.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Over 30 million people &#39;one step away from starvation&#39;, UN warns</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/mar/24/over-30-million-people-one-step-away-from-starvation-un-warns</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/mar/24/over-30-million-people-one-step-away-from-starvation-un-warns">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Acute hunger is being driven by conflict, climate shocks and the Covid pandemic, and, in some places, compounded by storms of desert locusts.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cutting Your Carbon Footprint Matters a Lot — If You’re Rich</title>
			<link>https://www.motherjones.com/environment/2021/03/cutting-your-carbon-footprint-matters-a-lot-if-youre-rich/</link>
			<source url="https://www.motherjones.com/environment/2021/03/cutting-your-carbon-footprint-matters-a-lot-if-youre-rich/">Mother Jones</source>
			<description>Individual responsibility has become something of a flashpoint in the climate discourse. On the one hand, oil companies love to harp on about personal carbon footprints as a way of distracting from their much larger contributions to the climate crisis, both through the fossil fuel products they make and their longstanding, ongoing efforts to delay climate action and misinform the public. At the same time, prominent journalists and scientists have waved off individual climate actions as a distraction from the systemic changes that are needed to solve the crisis—changes like overhauling our electricity and transit systems through governmental investments in clean energy, better regulation, and carbon pricing. They&#39;re joined by a growing chorus of climate justice advocates who rightly point out that asking poor people to make difficult dietary shifts or give up the car they need to get to work is completely unfair.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK government scraps green homes grant after six months</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/27/uk-government-scraps-green-homes-grant-after-six-months</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/27/uk-government-scraps-green-homes-grant-after-six-months">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The abandonment of the £1.5bn programme, which offered households grants of up to £5,000 or £10,000 to put in insulation or low-carbon heating, leaves the UK without a plan for tackling one of the biggest sources of greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>What Happened to a Climate Change Denier&#39;s 10-Year Wager?</title>
			<link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/21/03/27/1831204/what-happened-to-a-climate-change-deniers-10-year-wager</link>
			<source url="https://news.slashdot.org/story/21/03/27/1831204/what-happened-to-a-climate-change-deniers-10-year-wager">Slashdot</source>
			<description>In January of 2011, Slashdot reported on AccuWeather meteorologist Joe Bastardi&#39;s wager for climate scientists. He bet the earth would &#34;cool .1 to .2 Celsius in the next ten years, according to objective satellite data.&#34;... The wager would have come due in January of 2021. As it turns out, the linear trend of global mean temperatures shows the earth actually warmed by just over 0.5C over the period according to satellite data.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Dimming the sun'&#58; &#36;100m geoengineering research programme proposed</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/25/top-us-scientists-back-100m-geoengineering-research-proposal</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/25/top-us-scientists-back-100m-geoengineering-research-proposal">The Guardian</source>
			<description>&quot;The US solar geoengineering research programme should be all about helping society make more informed decisions,&quot; said Prof Chris Field of Stanford University, who was chair of the committee that wrote the report. &quot;Based on all of the evidence from social science, natural science, and technology, this research programme could either indicate that solar geoengineering should not be considered further, or conclude that it warrants additional effort.&quot;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The World Is Stuck With Decades of New Plastic It Can't Recycle</title>
			<link>https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-world-is-stuck-with-decades-of-new-plastic-it-can-t-recycle</link>
			<source url="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-world-is-stuck-with-decades-of-new-plastic-it-can-t-recycle">Quartz</source>
			<description>Recycling is not the solution. Only 9% of all plastic produced gets recycled—and even that low number is likely a gross overestimation. Plastic waste exported from the country where it was discarded counts as “recycled,” regardless of its actual fate. And virgin plastic is so cheap that there is no financial incentive for companies to use recycled plastic in their products. In short, plastic recycling is a myth—and always has been.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		

		<item>
			<title>Pollution from fossil fuel combustion deadlier than previously thought</title>
			<link>https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/hsph-in-the-news/pollution-from-fossil-fuel-combustion-deadlier-than-previously-thought</link>
			<source url="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/hsph-in-the-news/pollution-from-fossil-fuel-combustion-deadlier-than-previously-thought">Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health</source>
			<description>A new study found that fine particulate pollution generated by the burning of fossil fuels was responsible for one in five early deaths worldwide in 2018—far more than previously thought. Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health’s Aaron Bernstein said that the people most at risk are those “who can least afford it.”</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK government falters in delivering green recovery</title>
			<link>https://energymonitor.ai/policy/green-deals/uk-government-falters-delivering-green-covid-19-recovery-plan</link>
			<source url="https://energymonitor.ai/policy/green-deals/uk-government-falters-delivering-green-covid-19-recovery-plan">Energy Monitor</source>
			<description>Meanwhile, the Climate Change Committee, the body that advises government on how to meet its statutory emissions reduction goals, has suggested the UK needs to scale up public and private investment to £50bn a year by 2030 to achieve its net-zero goals. Looking across the Atlantic, the Institute of Public Policy Research (IPPR) has suggested that, to mirror President Joe Biden’s $1.9trn stimulus proposal, the UK should embark on a recovery programme worth £190bn.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hundreds of millions of people could be affected by heatwaves within 30 years - study</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/hundreds-of-millions-of-people-could-be-affected-heatwaves-within-30-years-study-12254585</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/hundreds-of-millions-of-people-could-be-affected-heatwaves-within-30-years-study-12254585">Sky News</source>
			<description>Earlier this month, Oxford University researchers estimated that there had already been 1,500 UK deaths attributable to climate change events. Scientists linked the deaths to heatwaves in 2003 and 2018, which saw record temperatures broken in cities such as Glasgow and Belfast.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Small nuclear power plants no use in climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://climatenewsnetwork.net/small-nuclear-power-plants-no-use-in-climate-crisis/</link>
			<source url="https://climatenewsnetwork.net/small-nuclear-power-plants-no-use-in-climate-crisis/">Climate News Network</source>
			<description>There is a clear crossover between civil and nuclear industries in the US, the UK, China, Russia and France. This is made more obvious because of the few countries that have renounced nuclear weapons − for example only Germany, Italy and Spain have shown no interest in building any kind of nuclear station. This is simply because renewables are cheaper and produce low carbon power far more quickly.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How bad for the climate is bingeing Netflix?</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/netflix-stream-binge-emissions-study-b1820762.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/netflix-stream-binge-emissions-study-b1820762.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Using the data, Netflix has revealed some stats on its emissions for the first time. The company says that one hour of streaming uses less than 100g CO2 equivalent (emissions from all greenhouse gases, not just CO2). Wired reports that this is similar to driving a car for a quarter of a mile, or running a 1,000-watt air-conditioning unit for 15 minutes in the US (and for 40 minutes in Europe).</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
  		<item>
    			<title>UK seeks to drill more oil and gas from North Sea</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56503588</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56503588">BBC News</source>
			<description>Mel Evans from Greenpeace said: “This is a colossal failure. The UK will make a fool of itself in the run-up to hosting the COP26 global climate talks if our energy minister signs off on new oil and gas licences that serve to rip up the Paris Agreement (the world deal to hold global temperature rise to 1.5C)."</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Big banks’ trillion-dollar finance for fossil fuels ‘shocking’, says report</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/24/big-banks-trillion-dollar-finance-for-fossil-fuels-shocking-says-report</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/24/big-banks-trillion-dollar-finance-for-fossil-fuels-shocking-says-report">The Guardian</source>
			<description>A commitment to be net zero by 2050 has been made by 17 of the 60 banks, but the report describes the pledges as “dangerously weak, half-baked, or vague”, arguing that action is needed today. Some banks have policies that block finance for coal, the dirtiest fossil fuel, but almost two-thirds of funding is for oil and gas companies.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unpaid environmental damages from fossil fuels are a $600B annual subsidy</title>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/unpaid-environmental-damages-from-fossil-fuels-are-a-600b-annual-subsidy</link>
			<source url="https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/unpaid-environmental-damages-from-fossil-fuels-are-a-600b-annual-subsidy">Ars Technica</source>
			<description>The producers' slice of the pie comes in at $71 billion in 2018 and averaged $62 billion over the study period. Gasoline was the largest portion of that, averaging $25 billion, with coal and natural gas varying with the changing usage pattern. Here, the split was quite different, with gasoline and diesel coming in at under $50 billion, natural gas at about $20 billion, and coal at about $10 billion.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ending Fossil Fuel Subsidies the Wrong Way Could End Up Hurting the Poor</title>
			<link>https://truthout.org/articles/elite-led-efforts-to-end-fossil-fuel-subsidies-have-a-hidden-neoliberal-agenda</link>
			<source url="https://truthout.org/articles/elite-led-efforts-to-end-fossil-fuel-subsidies-have-a-hidden-neoliberal-agenda">Truthout</source>
			<description>If the dollar value of subsidies has indeed been inflated for political and ideological purposes, then the same can be said of the emissions reductions estimates that derive from them. The IMF maintains that, if users paid the “full price” for fossil-based energy, consumption would fall and a more efficient use of energy would eventually follow. But the relationship between prices, fossil fuel use, and emissions reductions is based on what economists call “elasticities.” Research has shown that the “price-demand ratio” can be quite pronounced when consumers have alternative energy options. But when alternatives don’t exist—which is often the case—increases in prices produce a “low to moderate” reduction in demand. According to the IMF, “Consistent, country-level models of how fossil fuel use responds to price reform are not yet available on a wide scale.” In other words, the IMF’s assertion that “getting energy prices right” will dramatically curtail energy use is politically convenient, but it is not always supported by the data.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>JP Morgan warns of end to human life in climate report</title>
			<link>https://www.telegraph.co.uk/environment/2020/02/21/jp-morgan-warns-end-human-life-leaked-climate-report</link>
			<source url="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/environment/2020/02/21/jp-morgan-warns-end-human-life-leaked-climate-report">The Telegraph</source>
			<description>According to JP Morgan's research, titled 'Risky business: the climate and the macroeconomy', the impact of climate change will be broad and devastating. The economists call on world leaders to introduce a global carbon tax to prevent a meltdown, saying no other measure is likely to be enough.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Climate Anxiety Is an Overwhelmingly White Phenomenon</title>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-unbearable-whiteness-of-climate-anxiety</link>
			<source url="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-unbearable-whiteness-of-climate-anxiety">Scientific American</source>
			<description>Instead of asking “What can I do to stop feeling so anxious?”, “What can I do to save the planet?” and “What hope is there?”, people with privilege can be asking “Who am I?” and “How am I connected to all of this?” The answers reveal that we are deeply interconnected with the well-being of others on this planet, and that there are traditions of environmental stewardship that can be guides for where we need to go from here.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It’s Time to Replace Ambition with Adaptation</title>
			<link>https://forge.medium.com/its-time-to-replace-ambition-with-adaptation-945880f183f1</link>
			<source url="https://forge.medium.com/its-time-to-replace-ambition-with-adaptation-945880f183f1">Forge</source>
			<description>Facing a world that seems to get worse by the hour, an urgent climate emergency that is certain to dismantle our global supply chains in a way that makes Covid-19 look quaint, and a new understanding of how to live at a slower pace, we have to ask: Does following our personal and narrowly defined ambition, at the cost of all other skills and possibly our own health, make much sense anymore?</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bitcoin Is Terrible For The Planet. Now There Are Better Choices</title>
			<link>https://www.wbur.org/cognoscenti/2021/03/22/bitcoin-crytocurrency-environment-climate-energy-fred-hewett</link>
			<source url="https://www.wbur.org/cognoscenti/2021/03/22/bitcoin-crytocurrency-environment-climate-energy-fred-hewett">WBUR</source>
			<description>Bitcoin still commands strong support in libertarian circles, and that’s significant because right-wing ideologies are historically disdainful of government action to address climate change. David Golumbia’s "The Politics of Bitcoin" illuminates the deep connections between crypto-anarchist Bitcoin pioneers and the free-market fundamentalism that still pervades a substantial segment of the Bitcoin community.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Climate Crisis Is Worse Than You Can Imagine. Here’s What Happens If You Try.</title>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/the-climate-crisis-is-worse-than-you-can-imagine-heres-what-happens-if-you-try</link>
			<source url="https://www.propublica.org/article/the-climate-crisis-is-worse-than-you-can-imagine-heres-what-happens-if-you-try">ProPublica</source>
			<description>So how, with our limited human minds, do we attend enough to make real progress? How do we not flinch and look away? The truth of what is happening shakes the foundations of our sense of self. It asserts a distorting gravity, bending our priorities and warping our whole lives. The overt denialists are easy villains, the monsters who look like monsters. But the rest of us, much of the time, wear pretty green masks over our self-interest and denial, and then go about our days. Then each morning we wake to a new headline like: “The planet is dying faster than we thought.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India Targets Climate Activists With the Help of Big Tech</title>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/02/27/india-climate-activists-twitter-google-facebook</link>
			<source url="https://theintercept.com/2021/02/27/india-climate-activists-twitter-google-facebook">The Intercept</source>
			<description>For tech companies like Facebook, Google, Twitter, and Zoom, India under Modi has turned into a harsh moment of truth. In North America and Europe, these companies are going to great lengths to show that they can be trusted to regulate hate speech and harmful conspiracies on their platforms while protecting the freedom to speak, debate, and disagree that is integral to any healthy society. But in India, where helping governments hunt and imprison peaceful activists and amplify hate appears to be the price of access to a huge and growing market, “all of those arguments have gone out the window,” one activist told me. And for a simple reason: “They are profiting from this harm.”</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Fossilized plants discovered a mile beneath Greenland ice sheet</title>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/environment/fossilized-plants-greenland-ice-sheet</link>
			<source url="https://newatlas.com/environment/fossilized-plants-greenland-ice-sheet">New Atlas</source>
			<description>Finding these frozen plants may sound like an intriguing curiosity, but the researchers say there’s a concerning implication to the discovery. It suggests that the Greenland Ice Sheet is more susceptible to climate change than anticipated – which is a problem, considering it contains enough ice that, if it were to completely melt, it would raise sea levels by 7.2 m (24 ft) alone. Worse still, a recent report found that the ice sheet has lost 3.8 trillion tonnes of ice since 1992, and the rate is accelerating.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Soothe Yourself With a Picture Book About the Internet Dying</title>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/soothe-yourself-with-a-picture-book-about-the-internet-dying</link>
			<source url="https://www.wired.com/story/soothe-yourself-with-a-picture-book-about-the-internet-dying">WIRED</source>
			<description>Illustrated by Rinee Shah and written in the style of Genesis (as in the Book of, not the band), &#39;OFF&#58; The Day the Internet Died (A Bedtime Fantasy)&#39; invites readers to imagine weeks, decades, centuries without the internet. The characters take walks IRL; they play Minecraft with sticks and leaves; they get “way into” D&#38;D.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The economics of covering California’s water system with solar panels</title>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/the-economics-of-covering-californias-water-system-with-solar-panels</link>
			<source url="https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/the-economics-of-covering-californias-water-system-with-solar-panels">Ars Technica</source>
			<description>There are a number of things, however, that make these calculations more complicated than the economic analysis would suggest. For example, the cabling over the canals could potentially complicate maintenance, even if said maintenance wouldn't have to happen as often. And the canals aren't always located near sites that would be easy to connect to California's power grid. Unlike a more compact site, wiring up a long, stretched-out row of panels could add considerably to the cost.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Methane Spewing Mines Are as Bad For The Climate as Their Coal</title>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-19/coal-mines-seen-posing-additional-climate-threat-with-gas-leaks</link>
			<source url="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-19/coal-mines-seen-posing-additional-climate-threat-with-gas-leaks">Bloomberg</source>
			<description>Global Energy Monitor examined potential methane releases at 432 proposed new or expanded coal mines, and found that at the gassiest of them the leaks could account for half of their total greenhouse gas impact. If all were built, about 13.5 million tons of methane would be released annually, doing the damage of an equivalent of more than 1 billion tons of CO2.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Oil firms knew decades ago fossil fuels posed grave health risks, files reveal</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/oil-industry-fossil-fuels-air-pollution-documents</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/oil-industry-fossil-fuels-air-pollution-documents">The Guardian</source>
			<description>In an internal technical report in 1968, Shell [warned] that air pollution "may, in extreme situations, be deleterious to health" and [acknowledged] the oil industry “reluctantly” must accept that cars "are by far the greatest sources of air pollution". The report states that sulphur dioxide, given off by the burning of oil, can cause “difficulty in breathing” while nitrogen dioxide, also given off by vehicles and power plants, can cause lung damage and that “there will be a clamor to reduce [nitrogen dioxide] emissions, probably based on suspected long-term chronic effects”.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Global heating : the vital statistics from a warming world</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/ng-interactive/2020/oct/05/climate-data-dashboard-carbon-atmosphere-sea-level-arctic-ice</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/ng-interactive/2020/oct/05/climate-data-dashboard-carbon-atmosphere-sea-level-arctic-ice">The Guardian</source>
			<description>This page will track a selection of the planet’s vital signs, from carbon dioxide levels to Arctic sea ice, and act as a reference point. The graphs are fed from data sources including Nasa, the US National Snow and Ice Data Center and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. They will automatically update and follow the Earth’s climate trajectory, providing a visual representation of the climate crisis.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The perfect storm: Global food prices hit six-year high</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/program/counting-the-cost/2021/3/13/the-perfect-storm-global-food-prices-hit-six-year-high</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/program/counting-the-cost/2021/3/13/the-perfect-storm-global-food-prices-hit-six-year-high">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>Increasing demand from China, adverse weather conditions and pandemic-hit supply chains are all pushing up food prices.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Peer-reviewed research in psychology on the impacts of discussing difficult futures such as societal collapse</title>
			<link>http://iflas.blogspot.com/2021/02/peer-reviewed-research-in-psychology-on.html</link>
			<source url="http://iflas.blogspot.com/2021/02/peer-reviewed-research-in-psychology-on.html">IFLAS</source>
			<description>This paper presents a review of psychology research that can help people begin to assess the different ways they can responsibly support each other to talk about their thoughts and feelings on their perceptions of societal disruption and collapse, at home and abroad, due to environmental and climate change. It includes a summary of a review of published studies in psychology on matters of anticipating difficult futures, including vulnerability, disruption, disaster, suffering and mortality. The claims by both specialists and non-specialists that collapse anticipation is necessarily harmful to mental health and social engagement is shown to be theoretically and empirically weak.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Feeding cows seaweed could cut their methane emissions by 82&#37;, scientists say</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/cows-seaweed-methane-emissions-scientists</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/cows-seaweed-methane-emissions-scientists">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Agriculture makes up about 10&#37; of emissions in the US, much of it from cows that belch, and to a lesser extent, fart out methane. This has led to some climate campaigners to urge people to eat less meat but the UC Davis researchers said that existing meat production could be made better for the climate by putting seaweed on the menu for cattle.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Net zero 'not enough' to combat climate change, Environment Agency warns</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/net-zero-not-enough-to-combat-climate-change-environment-agency-warns-12247271</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/net-zero-not-enough-to-combat-climate-change-environment-agency-warns-12247271">Sky News</source>
			<description>Speaking at the Whitehall and Industry Group's Net Zero Roundtable, Sir James warned the increased frequency of extreme weather events such as flooding and droughts, along with coastal erosion and damage to biodiversity, was as a result of average global temperatures rising to 1C above pre-industrial temperatures.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>We’re Hurtling Toward Global Suicide</title>
			<link>https://newrepublic.com/article/161575/climate-change-effects-hurtling-toward-global-suicide</link>
			<source url="https://newrepublic.com/article/161575/climate-change-effects-hurtling-toward-global-suicide">New Republic</source>
			<description>A strange sort of faith lies at the core of mainstream climate advocacy—a largely unexamined belief that the very system that got us into this mess is the one that will get us out of it. For a community putatively committed to scientific empiricism, this is an extraordinary conviction. Despite reams of increasingly apocalyptic research, and despite 25 years of largely fruitless international climate negotiations, carbon emissions have continued to rise, and temperatures along with them. We are at nearly 1.2 degrees Celsius of warming already—more than 2 degrees Fahrenheit over preindustrial averages—and three-tenths of a degree away from blowing the Paris accord’s aspiration to limit warming to a still-calamitous 1.5 degrees Celsius. Scientists now expect us to hit that threshold in about 10 years, and large swaths of the Arctic have been in actual flames for two summers running, but most governments with the option to do so are still feeding the beast that got us here.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Revenge of the nerds&#58; Disaster risk reduction and climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.thenewhumanitarian.org/opinion/2021/3/18/revenge-of-the-nerds-disaster-risk-reduction-and-climate-change</link>
			<source url="https://www.thenewhumanitarian.org/opinion/2021/3/18/revenge-of-the-nerds-disaster-risk-reduction-and-climate-change">The New Humanitarian</source>
			<description>Investing in disaster risk reduction isn’t a matter of saving for a rainy day&#59;	it’s jerking the wheel to avoid the boulder that is quite clearly on the road ahead. People should not have to be starving, buried under rubble, or flooded out of their homes before the world pays attention.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It's unavoidable&#58; we must ban fossil fuels to save our planet. Here's how we do it</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/mar/09/its-unavoidable-we-must-ban-fossil-fuels-to-save-our-planet-heres-how-we-do-it</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/mar/09/its-unavoidable-we-must-ban-fossil-fuels-to-save-our-planet-heres-how-we-do-it">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Since we have already drawn down over 120 Gt of CO2 from this carbon budget, we have now less than 300 Gt left. Combining the proved fossil fuel reserves reported in British Petroleum’s Statistical Review of World Energy with CO2 emission factors from the IPCC yields 3,600 Gt of CO2 emissions. This means that we can only afford to burn one twelfth of the fossil fuels we have already found. And this does not account for any greenhouse gas emissions from the ongoing melting of permafrost. The Arctic region alone is estimated to have 1,500 Gt of carbon stored in its soils, some of which is already being converted to CO2 by microbes and released into the atmosphere.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Met Office&#58; Atmospheric CO2 now hitting 50&#37; higher than pre-industrial levels</title>
			<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/met-office-atmospheric-co2-now-hitting-50-higher-than-pre-industrial-levels</link>
			<source url="https://www.carbonbrief.org/met-office-atmospheric-co2-now-hitting-50-higher-than-pre-industrial-levels">Carbon Brief</source>
			<description>As human-driven emissions have increased, the rise in CO2 has accelerated. It took over 200 years to reach a 25&#37; increase by 1986. By 2011 – 25 years later – the increase reached 40&#37;. Now after one more decade it is reaching 50&#37;.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trillions For Oil, Millions For EVs&#58; The Big Lie Of Ineffectual Government</title>
			<link>https://jalopnik.com/trillions-for-oil-millions-for-evs-the-big-lie-of-ine-1846476419</link>
			<source url="https://jalopnik.com/trillions-for-oil-millions-for-evs-the-big-lie-of-ine-1846476419">Jalopnik</source>
			<description>Ignoring the fact that every dollar spent subsidizing oil diverts money away from other societally valuable enterprises &#45; say public health, mass transit or feeding the hungry &#45; the dollars are still staggering. Internationally, depending on the price of oil, governments provide up to $1 trillion in subsidies, each year. Add costs related to climate change and other despoiling of the environment, plus war and negative health impacts, and, according to a 2015 study by the International Monetary Fund, the unpaid costs of fossil fuels clock in each year at around $5.3 trillion annually &#45; or a breathtaking $10 million a minute. Don’t hold us to it, but that’s more money even than Jeff Bezos makes.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Mediocrity Is The Enemy Of The Solution</title>
			<link>https://cleantechnica.com/2020/12/16/mediocrity-is-the-enemy-of-the-solution</link>
			<source url="https://cleantechnica.com/2020/12/16/mediocrity-is-the-enemy-of-the-solution">CleanTechnica</source>
			<description>Photosynthesis is only 1&#37; efficient. Solar panels are 20&#37; efficient. Thus, a solar panel needs 1/20th the land as a biofuel to produce the same energy. On top of that, an electric car uses 1/4th the energy as an internal-combustion engine car to go the same distance. Thus, a battery-electric car running on solar energy uses 1/80th the land as an ethanol-fueled car.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Aral Sea</title>
			<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aral_Sea</link>
			<source url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aral_Sea">Wikipedia</source>
			<description>Formerly the fourth largest lake in the world with an area of 68,000 km2 (26,300 sq mi), the Aral Sea began shrinking in the 1960s after the rivers that fed it were diverted by Soviet irrigation projects...  The Aral Sea region is heavily polluted, with consequent serious public health problems. UNESCO has added historical documents concerning the Aral Sea to its Memory of the World Register as a resource to study the environmental tragedy.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>S2E53: Paul Kingsnorth on the shared roots of climate crisis, transhumanism, &#38; immortality</title>
			<link>https://nori.com/podcasts/reversing-climate-change/S2E53-Paul-Kingsnorth-on-the-shared-roots-of-climate-crisis--transhumanism---immortality-era5om</link>
			<source url="https://nori.com/podcasts/reversing-climate-change/S2E53-Paul-Kingsnorth-on-the-shared-roots-of-climate-crisis--transhumanism---immortality-era5om">Reversing Climate Change</source>
			<description>Paul shares his take on capitalism versus distributism, describing how systems of radical local democracy would root us in community and prevent the kind of scale that leads to tyranny.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Industrial Fishing Creates More CO2 Emissions Than Air Travel</title>
			<link>https://time.com/5947430/bottom-trawling-carbon-emissions-study</link>
			<source url="https://time.com/5947430/bottom-trawling-carbon-emissions-study">TIME</source>
			<description>According to calculations conducted by the report’s 26 authors, bottom trawling is responsible for one gigaton of carbon emissions a year—a higher annual total than (pre-pandemic) aviation emissions. Not only does the practice contribute to climate change, it is extremely damaging to ocean biodiversity—the “equivalent of ploughing an old-growth forest into the ground, over and over and over again until there is nothing left” according to lead author Enric Sala, a marine biologist who is also National Geographic’s Explorer in Residence.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Buying a Tesla in Bitcoins cancels 4 times the CO2 savings for its whole lifetime</title>
			<link>https://medium.com/crypto-lucid/buying-a-tesla-in-bitcoins-cancels-4-times-the-co2-savings-for-its-whole-lifetime-c28b042e3b9a</link>
			<source url="https://medium.com/crypto-lucid/buying-a-tesla-in-bitcoins-cancels-4-times-the-co2-savings-for-its-whole-lifetime-c28b042e3b9a">Crypto Lucid</source>
			<description>Suppose you want to buy this car with gold. It would take 3 to 5 &#91;times&#93; less energy to mine this gold than to mine the same value in Bitcoins.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
