<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!-- MY XSLT document to transform the RSS feed into an XHTML page. -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl" media="screen" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<image>
  		<url>https://extinction.fyi/img/extinction-fyi-logo.webp</url>
  		<title>extinction.fyi logo</title>
		<link>https://extinction.fyi</link>
		</image>
		<title>extinction.fyi</title>
		<link>https://extinction.fyi/</link>
 		<description>Documenting the climate emergency</description>
		<category>Climate change/Climate emergency/Climate action</category>


<!--
		<item>
			<title></title>
			<link></link>
			<source url=""></source>
			<description></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 9 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		Using special characters in XML - https://www.dvteclipse.com/documentation/svlinter/How_to_use_special_characters_in_XML.3F.html
-->
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change threatens age-old indigenous food systems, says UN</title>
			<link>https://news.trust.org/item/20210625103957-8jpk8/</link>
			<source url="https://news.trust.org/item/20210625103957-8jpk8/">Reuters</source>
			<description>In some cases, an increased monetization of the local economy led indigenous communities to move away from barter, food sharing and communal systems. The opportunity to make money made some communities switch from sustainable practices to over-fishing or over-hunting, leading to a loss of biodiversity, said the report.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Countdown to Glasgow&#58; This is why climate activists are taking on big banks</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/cop26-glasgow-climate-activists-banks-b1872162.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/cop26-glasgow-climate-activists-banks-b1872162.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Whether it’s investors who back their climate strategies (as they duly did at Shell and Total’s Annual General Meetings last month) to insurers and banks who mitigate the risks and provide the capital for projects, there would be no fossil fuel extraction without the backing of financial institutions.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Yellowstone&#58; report reveals extent of climate threat to oldest US national park
</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/yellowstone-national-park-climate-crisis</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/yellowstone-national-park-climate-crisis">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The analysis shows that temperatures in the park are now as high or higher as during any period in the last 20,000 years and are very likely the warmest in the past 800,000 years. Since 1950, Yellowstone has experienced an average temperature increase of 2.3F, with the most pronounced warming taking place at elevations above 5,000ft.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>The Effects of Climate Change</title>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/24/briefing/climate-change-drought-us-heat-wave.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/24/briefing/climate-change-drought-us-heat-wave.html">The New York Times</source>
			<description>In Arizona and Nevada, it’s been so hot that doctors warned people they could get third-degree burns from the asphalt. Wildfires raged in Montana and Utah. Power grids in Texas strained as officials asked residents to limit appliance use to avoid blackouts.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change has driven 16&#37; drop in ‘snow meltwater’ from Asia’s high mountains</title>
			<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-has-driven-16-drop-in-snow-meltwater-from-asias-high-mountains</link>
			<source url="https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-has-driven-16-drop-in-snow-meltwater-from-asias-high-mountains">Carbon Brief</source>
			<description>The new study finds that, between 1979-99 and 1999-2019, “snow meltwater supply” to rivers in high-mountain Asia dropped by an average of 16&#37;. It adds that, even if warming is limited to 1.5C, there will be further losses of around 6&#37; by the end of the century. Meanwhile, an extremely high future warming scenario would drive a 40&#37; drop in meltwater supply.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global warming below 1.7C is ‘not plausible’, reveals our study of the social drivers of decarbonisation</title>
			<link>https://theconversation.com/global-warming-below-1-7-c-is-not-plausible-reveals-our-study-of-the-social-drivers-of-decarbonisation-163104</link>
			<source url="https://theconversation.com/global-warming-below-1-7-c-is-not-plausible-reveals-our-study-of-the-social-drivers-of-decarbonisation-163104">The Conversation</source>
			<description>None of the drivers show enough momentum to bring about deep decarbonisation by 2050, and two drivers, consumption patterns and corporate responses, actively inhibit it. Our final assessment&#58; even if a partial decarbonisation is currently plausible, deep decarbonisation by the year 2050 is not.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate-driven coastal flooding in the US likely to get worse suddenly</title>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/06/climate-driven-coastal-flooding-in-the-us-likely-to-get-worse-suddenly/</link>
			<source url="https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/06/climate-driven-coastal-flooding-in-the-us-likely-to-get-worse-suddenly/">Ars Technica</source>
			<description>Infrastructure we are building at present is unlikely to reach its end of life before flooding becomes far more frequent. Housing, roads, and other facilities that we are currently using will likely need to be protected or abandoned. And coastal states may want to start setting aside money to deal with the flooding that will invariably occur.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The worst is yet to come&#58; 10 takeaways from draft UN report</title>
			<link>https://www.dailysabah.com/life/environment/the-worst-is-yet-to-come-10-takeaways-from-draft-un-report</link>
			<source url="https://www.dailysabah.com/life/environment/the-worst-is-yet-to-come-10-takeaways-from-draft-un-report">Daily Sabah</source>
			<description>The mammoth 4,000-page document by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), seen exclusively by Agence France-Presse (AFP), warns that unless warming is rapidly capped, some of the damage done to our planet may become irreversible.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>‘Merciless’ temperatures push Moscow to hottest June day in 142 years, as heatwave hits Russia</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/moscow-record-temperature-arctic-heatwave-b1871351.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/moscow-record-temperature-arctic-heatwave-b1871351.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>On average Russia is experiencing temperature rises 2.5 times faster than the rest of the world, as the climate crisis has exacerbated heating at the Earth’s poles.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Has lockdown actually had a positive effect on the environment&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/sustainable-living/covid-lockdown-environment-co2-emissions-b1870703.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/sustainable-living/covid-lockdown-environment-co2-emissions-b1870703.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Professor Sovacool believes that now is an ideal time for governments to push for green initiatives, such as discouraging the use of cars and encouraging more people to return to public transport and other green alternatives.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
<item>
			<title>Melting ice&#58; What's the big deal?</title>
			<link>https://www.dw.com/en/melting-ice-whats-the-big-deal/a-56872079</link>
			<source url="https://www.dw.com/en/melting-ice-whats-the-big-deal/a-56872079">Deutsche Welle</source>
			<description>Right now, cities like Santiago in Chile are watching a big part of their drinking water supply literally dry up as glaciers in the nearby Andes retreat. Meanwhile, the European Alps that supply so much fresh water across the region have shrunk by about half since 1900 and will be almost ice free by century's end if nothing more is done to curb warming.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>		
                </item>
<item>
			<title>Plants in deserts are dying off due to climate change ‘and nothing is replacing them’</title>
			<link>https://uk.news.yahoo.com/climate-change-plants-deserts-153433768.html</link>
			<source url="https://uk.news.yahoo.com/climate-change-plants-deserts-153433768.html">Yahoo News UK</source>
			<description>The research shows how desert areas – where researchers had hoped plants might be more resilient – can be blighted by climate change.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>		
                </item>

		<item>
			<title>Climate change decimating Yemen's bee farms</title>
			<link>https://www.middleeastmonitor.com/20210621-climate-change-decimating-yemens-bee-farms/</link>
			<source url="https://www.middleeastmonitor.com/20210621-climate-change-decimating-yemens-bee-farms/">Middle East Monitor</source>
			<description>As the poorest and most water-insecure country in the Middle East and North Africa, Yemen has been left without the tools to face the volatility to come, analysts said. &#34;Even though its own (CO2) emissions are low, its farmers and beekeepers are among the most affected and the least prepared for climate change,&#34; said the UNDP's Ali.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Smaller bodies, longer wings, earlier migrations&#58; Untangling the multiple impacts of climate warming on birds</title>
			<link>https://phys.org/news/2021-06-smaller-bodies-longer-wings-earlier.html</link>
			<source url="https://phys.org/news/2021-06-smaller-bodies-longer-wings-earlier.html">Phys.org</source>
			<description>Many studies of plant and animal adaptive responses to climate warming have looked at either phenological or morphological changes, but few have been able to examine both at the same time. The depth of the Field Museum dataset enabled the U-M-led team to examine multiple responses to climate warming simultaneously and to test for connections between them.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Head of Independent Sage to launch international climate change group</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/head-of-independent-sage-to-launch-international-climate-change-group</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/head-of-independent-sage-to-launch-international-climate-change-group">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The Climate Crisis Advisory Group, comprising 14 experts from 10 nations and every continent, aims to have more of an international reach and provide the global public with regular analysis about efforts to tackle the global heating and biodiversity crises.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change&#58; Government failing to ensure UK can cope with what is already happening</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-government-failing-to-ensure-uk-can-cope-with-what-is-already-happening-12333316</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-government-failing-to-ensure-uk-can-cope-with-what-is-already-happening-12333316">Sky News</source>
			<description>The UK is even less prepared to deal with climate change already hitting the country than it was five years ago, thanks to a &#34;failing&#34; government response, its own independent advisers have warned.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change is remaking South Asia’s monsoon</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/asia/2021/06/19/climate-change-is-remaking-south-asias-monsoon</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/asia/2021/06/19/climate-change-is-remaking-south-asias-monsoon">The Economist</source>
			<description>While the monsoon has long made mankind in South Asia, man is now remaking the monsoon.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>In pictures&#58; How blistering heatwave is fuelling extreme 'mega drought' in western US</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/in-pictures-how-blistering-heatwave-is-fuelling-extreme-mega-drought-in-western-us-12336472</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/in-pictures-how-blistering-heatwave-is-fuelling-extreme-mega-drought-in-western-us-12336472">Sky News</source>
			<description>In the past week, Arizona, Nevada and other areas have experienced the highest level of hot weather in history, and about 43 million people are under a high temperature warning.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 20 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		
		<item>
			<title>How is the record-breaking US heatwave linked to the climate crisis&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/heatwave-2021-us-california-weather-b1868489.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/heatwave-2021-us-california-weather-b1868489.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>A growing body of evidence suggests that, across the world, heatwaves are becoming both more frequent and more intense as a result of the climate crisis. A number of high-profile scientific studies have linked human-caused warming to recent heatwaves in regions from the Arctic circle to Australia.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change&#58; UN virtual talks make little progress</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-57520510</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-57520510">BBC News</source>
			<description>The UN subsidiary bodies meeting was meant to clear the decks ahead of the major COP26 gathering in Glasgow in November. But technical glitches, and multiple time zones scuppered attempts to find common ground. Ministers from 40 countries will meet in July to push the process forward.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Belgium’s climate failures violate human rights, court rules</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/18/belgium-climate-policy-violates-human-rights-court-rules</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/18/belgium-climate-policy-violates-human-rights-court-rules">The Guardian</source>
			<description>By not taking all “necessary measures” to prevent the “detrimental” effects of climate change, the court said, Belgian authorities had breached the right to life (article 2) and the right to respect for private and family life (article 8).</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>60 per cent of world’s rivers stop flowing for at least one day a year</title>
			<link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2281222-60-per-cent-of-worlds-rivers-stop-flowing-for-at-least-one-day-a-year/</link>
			<source url="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2281222-60-per-cent-of-worlds-rivers-stop-flowing-for-at-least-one-day-a-year/">New Scientist</source>
			<description>Even more rivers could start to run dry in the future as climate change drives more severe, frequent droughts in some regions, says Ton Snelder at LWP, a water management consulting firm in New Zealand, who co-authored the study.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Earth is now trapping ‘unprecedented’ amount of heat, Nasa finds</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/earth-heat-trap-nasa-b1867601.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/earth-heat-trap-nasa-b1867601.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>The amount of energy Earth traps has almost doubled in the last decade and a half, aiding to more rapid global warming, a recent study has revealed.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate activists take Norway to human rights court over Arctic oil plans</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/climate-activists-take-norway-european-human-rights-court-arctic-oil-drilling-plans</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/climate-activists-take-norway-european-human-rights-court-arctic-oil-drilling-plans">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The activists, Greenpeace and Young Friends of the Earth, want the court to rule that Oslo’s 2016 decision to grant 10 Barents Sea oil exploration licences violated article 112 of Norway’s constitution, which guarantees the right to a healthy environment.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Polarstern team warns Arctic may be past tipping point</title>
			<link>https://www.dw.com/en/polarstern-team-warns-arctic-may-be-past-tipping-point/a-57902491</link>
			<source url="https://www.dw.com/en/polarstern-team-warns-arctic-may-be-past-tipping-point/a-57902491">DW Akademie</source>
			<description>The scientist who led the international MOSAiC expedition to the North Pole on Tuesday warned that the point could have already been reached at which irreversible global warming is triggered. During its expedition, the German research vessel &#34;Polarstern&#34; drifted through the Arctic on an ice floe for a year to also be able to research the winter at the North Pole, and the effects of climate change.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate crisis to hit Europe’s coffee and chocolate supplies</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/15/climate-crisis-to-hit-europes-coffee-and-chocolate-supplies</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/15/climate-crisis-to-hit-europes-coffee-and-chocolate-supplies">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The scientists predicted a sharp rise in drought risk for EU agricultural imports overall. Only 7&#37; were vulnerable over the last 25 years, but this grows to 37&#37; in the next 25 years, even if carbon emissions are cut sharply. Shortages of supply could result in higher prices, they said.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK warned it is unprepared for climate chaos</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-57487943</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-57487943">BBC News</source>
			<description>The authors of the report on adaptation, or "climate-proofing", warn that global warming can cause damage running into tens of billions of pounds over short periods - and they say they're frustrated at the lack of government action.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Loss of biodiversity poses as great a risk to humanity as climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/technology-quarterly/2021/06/15/loss-of-biodiversity-poses-as-great-a-risk-to-humanity-as-climate-change</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/technology-quarterly/2021/06/15/loss-of-biodiversity-poses-as-great-a-risk-to-humanity-as-climate-change">The Economist</source>
			<description>Since the 1990s, alarmed by studies showing rapid declines in animal and plant species around the globe, ecologists have talked of an impending mass extinction. It would be the sixth in the Earth’s history, but one unlike any that has come before. Surveys show that the loss of biodiversity is the result of a combination of factors: climate change, pollution, human exploitation of land, sea, plants and animals, and the displacement of some species into new territories where they play havoc with existing ecosystems. Uniquely in Earth’s history, each of these drivers of ecological change is caused by a single species: Homo sapiens.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>If you don’t have a climate plan, you don’t have a business plan</title>
			<link>https://www.fastcompany.com/90647008/if-you-dont-have-a-climate-plan-you-dont-have-a-business-plan</link>
			<source url="https://www.fastcompany.com/90647008/if-you-dont-have-a-climate-plan-you-dont-have-a-business-plan">Fast Company</source>
			<description>Investors know smart investments when they see them. Long-term investment in aggressive climate action represents one of the best ways for large companies to create long-term shareholder value, regain a position of unmatched economic strength among rivals like China, and build a valuable reputation for supporting prosperous, healthy communities grounded in millions of new jobs in the clean energy sector.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CBI boss says world is ‘way off track’ in fight against climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/cbi-boss-says-world-is-way-off-track-in-fight-against-climate-change</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/cbi-boss-says-world-is-way-off-track-in-fight-against-climate-change">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The CBI is holding a conference on the long-term goal of reaching net zero emissions by 2050. The organisation has set out its recommendations on achieving the targets, which include seven new gigafactories to build batteries and other components for electric vehicles, a plan for a nationwide network of electric vehicle charging and a review into fuel duty by the end of this year.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		
		<item>
			<title>How does war contribute to climate change&#63;</title>
			<link>https://ceobs.org/how-does-war-contribute-to-climate-change/</link>
			<source url="https://ceobs.org/how-does-war-contribute-to-climate-change/">Conflict and Environment Observatory</source>
			<description>The indirect emissions from active conflicts are the hardest to quantify, but perhaps the most significant given that they extend across many sectors, and into the future. In the early phases of fighting, the main emissions will arise from damaged infrastructure, the loss of vegetation, and delivering humanitarian aid. Monitoring indirect emissions first requires that we understand the relationship between societal change and the environment as many of these changes relate to the coping strategies employed by the civilian population.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Swiss CO2 law defeated at the ballot box</title>
			<link>https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/business/switzerland-votes-on-controversial-co2-law-/46695016</link>
			<source url="https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/business/switzerland-votes-on-controversial-co2-law-/46695016">swissinfo.ch</source>
			<description>The CO2 law, which was based on the &#34;polluter pays&#34; principle,  was the result of a broad compromise and a long battle in parliament. Initial opinion polls suggested the CO2 law had strong popular support (60&#37;), but the &#34;No&#34; camp gained significant ground in the final weeks ahead of the vote.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The rush to ‘go electric’ comes with a hidden cost: destructive lithium mining</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/electric-cost-lithium-mining-decarbonasation-salt-flats-chile</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/electric-cost-lithium-mining-decarbonasation-salt-flats-chile">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Indeed, the extraction and primary processing of metals and other minerals are responsible for 90% of biodiversity loss and 26% of global carbon emissions. One report estimates that the mining sector produces 100bn tons of waste every year. Extraction and processing are typically water- and energy-intensive, and contaminate waterways and soil. Alongside these dramatic changes to the natural environment, mining is linked to human rights abuses, respiratory ailments, dispossession of indigenous territory and labour exploitation. Once the minerals are wrested from the ground, mining companies tend to accumulate profits and leave behind poverty and contamination. These profits only multiply along the vast supply chains that produce electric vehicles and solar panels. Access to these technologies is highly unequal, and the communities who suffer the harms of extraction are frequently denied its benefits.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>David Attenborough Tells G7 Climate Change Decisions 'Most Important in Human History'</title>
			<link>https://www.newsweek.com/david-attenborough-tells-g7-climate-change-decisions-most-important-human-history-1600133?piano_t=1</link>
			<source url="https://www.newsweek.com/david-attenborough-tells-g7-climate-change-decisions-most-important-human-history-1600133?piano_t=1">Newsweek</source>
			<description>&#34;Our climate is warming fast. That is beyond doubt. Our societies and nations are unequal and that is sadly plain to see. But the question science forces us to address specifically in 2021 is whether as a result of these intertwined facts we are on the verge of destabilizing the entire planet&#63; &#34;If that is so, then the decisions we make this decade - in particular the decisions made by the most economically advanced nations— are the most important in human history.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 13 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Storms await companies that err on climate</title>
			<link>https://www.ft.com/content/f02537ef-0cbd-4566-8f0c-a1dfe798f54a</link>
			<source url="https://www.ft.com/content/f02537ef-0cbd-4566-8f0c-a1dfe798f54a">Financial Times</source>
			<description>Until recently, reinsurers and banks have borne most of the market risk of climate change. Now things are changing. Individual companies are being held explicitly responsible for the risks of global warming. A court in The Hague has ordered Royal Dutch Shell to cut its emissions. The International Energy Agency says energy groups must stop new oil and gas projects in order to reach net zero emissions by 2050.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 13 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tackle climate change and species destruction together, say scientists</title>
			<link>https://www.channel4.com/news/tackle-climate-change-and-species-destruction-together-say-scientists</link>
			<source url="https://www.channel4.com/news/tackle-climate-change-and-species-destruction-together-say-scientists">Channel 4</source>
			<description>A new report by 50 of the world’s leading experts has warned that the rapid decline of natural ecosystems and climate change are not separate challenges, but must both be tackled at the same time, and they say the future of human society depends on it.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 13 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Emission Control</title>
			<link>https://revealnews.org/podcast/emission-control/</link>
			<source url="https://revealnews.org/podcast/emission-control/">Reveal</source>
			<description>If we want to quickly combat climate change, we need to deal with “the other” greenhouse gas: methane. Methane leaks are heating up the planet and harming people who live where gas drilling takes place. </description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 12 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Boris Johnson Takes Private Jet to Climate Summit—But Hypocrisy Isn’t the Problem</title>
			<link>https://www.treehugger.com/boris-johnson-jet-climate-summit-hypocrisy-isnt-the-problem-5188721</link>
			<source url="https://www.treehugger.com/boris-johnson-jet-climate-summit-hypocrisy-isnt-the-problem-5188721">Treehugger</source>
			<description>In general, I’ve tended to side with Greta Thunberg when she said she didn’t care if climate advocate celebrities flew by private jet. I’m not saying we don’t need to curb private aviation. (We do.) And I’m also not saying that choosing to fly commercial, or travel overland, wouldn’t be good. (It would.) It’s just the focus on their hypocrisy is too often used to distract or deflect from systems-level discussions. </description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 12 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>European airlines have been lobbying against EU climate plans</title>
			<link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2280172-european-airlines-have-been-lobbying-against-eu-climate-plans/</link>
			<source url="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2280172-european-airlines-have-been-lobbying-against-eu-climate-plans/">New Scientist</source>
			<description>InfluenceMap, a think tank that monitors corporate lobbying around climate change, used freedom of information requests and research to draw up its new report. It reveals that while the 10 European airlines looked at for this report have received around €30 billion in government bailouts during the pandemic – some of which came with conditions attached to encourage climate-friendly actions – most have simultaneously lobbied to delay new proposals to cut aviation emissions.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 12 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>G-7 Stock Markets Imply Catastrophic Global Warming of 3°C</title>
			<link>https://www.inkl.com/news/g-7-stock-markets-imply-catastrophic-global-warming-of-3-c</link>
			<source url="https://www.inkl.com/news/g-7-stock-markets-imply-catastrophic-global-warming-of-3-c">Bloomberg Business</source>
			<description>At 3ºC of warming, &#34;the climate emergency will have become irreversible and will have a catastrophic human and economic impact in every country, on every continent,&#34; said Alberto Carrillo Pineda, director of science-based targets at the climate disclosure nonprofit CDP and a member of the steering committee for the SBTi. It will change &#34;life as we know it.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Halogen lightbulb sales to be banned in UK under climate change plans</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-57407233</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-57407233">BBC News</source>
			<description>The move will cut 1.26 million tonnes of carbon emissions a year and deliver consumers savings, officials say.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Shell’s CEO Pens LinkedIn Blog Blaming You for Climate Change</title>
			<link>https://gizmodo.com/shell-s-ceo-pens-linkedin-blog-blaming-you-for-climate-1847072051</link>
			<source url="https://gizmodo.com/shell-s-ceo-pens-linkedin-blog-blaming-you-for-climate-1847072051">Gizmodo</source>
			<description>&#34;People would fill up their cars and delivery trucks at other service stations,&#34; he wrote. That’s right, the CEO of Shell, the historic second-largest investor-owned carbon polluter on Earth, is blaming you for this climate change mess.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>‘It was sad having to leave’&#58; Climate crisis splits Alaskan town in half</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/08/it-was-sad-having-to-leave-climate-crisis-splits-alaskan-town-in-half</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/08/it-was-sad-having-to-leave-climate-crisis-splits-alaskan-town-in-half">The Guardian</source>
			<description>As a result of global warming, the arctic permafrost is thawing more quickly than expected, causing building foundations to deteriorate. For communities like Newtok along a river or coast, climate change can also accelerate erosion. In some years, more than 100ft of Newtok’s coast has broken away into the encroaching water, and in 2004, the US Army Corps of Engineers predicted that Newtok would be completely lost by 2019.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 9 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Carbon capture&#58; Climate solution or prolonging humanity's fossil fuel dependency&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.dw.com/en/carbon-capture-climate-solution-or-prolonging-humanitys-fossil-fuel-dependency/a-57767082</link>
			<source url="https://www.dw.com/en/carbon-capture-climate-solution-or-prolonging-humanitys-fossil-fuel-dependency/a-57767082">Deutsche Welle</source>
			<description>Capturing and burying CO2 is heralded as the technological fix to mitigate climate change. But many oil and gas majors are using the technology to produce more fossil fuels.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 9 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change&#58; 167 million homes could be wiped out by 2040, warns charity</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-167-million-homes-could-be-wiped-out-by-2040-warns-charity-12327968</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-167-million-homes-could-be-wiped-out-by-2040-warns-charity-12327968">Sky News</source>
			<description>According to government figures, five million UK properties are at risk from floods from the river or sea. The Met Office has warned that extended periods of extreme winter rainfall are now seven times more likely, due to human-induced climate change.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 9 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate policy models need to get real about people — here’s how</title>
			<link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-01500-2</link>
			<source url="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-01500-2">Nature</source>
			<description>As a first step, we — a group of political economists and IAM specialists — identified eight key areas in which insights from our disciplines can improve models’ relevance for real-world policy and investment choices... We also assessed numerous potential reforms... so that researchers can examine the trade-offs between making models tractable and making them more useful for real-world decisions.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 2 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global carbon dioxide levels continued to rise despite pandemic</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/08/carbon-dioxide-levels-pandemic-emissions</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/08/carbon-dioxide-levels-pandemic-emissions">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The laboratory at Mauna Loa, which sits on a volcano in the middle of the Pacific Ocean, combines two complementary observations to come up with the all-important value for carbon dioxide. The current level hasn’t existed on Earth since the Pliocene era, between 4.1m and 4.5m years ago – and global seas were 78ft higher than current day levels.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 2 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change&#58; Oceans are in a 'death spiral' with world leaders 'dragging their feet', Greenpeace warns</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-oceans-are-in-a-death-spiral-with-world-leaders-dragging-their-feet-greenpeace-warns-12327285</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-oceans-are-in-a-death-spiral-with-world-leaders-dragging-their-feet-greenpeace-warns-12327285">Sky News</source>
			<description>The conservation group Oceana has used satellite tracking data to calculate that boats spent 68,000 hours 'bottom trawling' in the UK's marine protected areas in 2020. That's a rise of 10&#37; on the year before. The practice is legal, even though the conservation zones are designed to protect seabed habitats such as reefs and corals.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 2 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Wealthy nations breaking climate pledge with gas dash in global south</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/wealthy-nations-breaking-climate-pledge-with-gas-dash-in-global-south</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/wealthy-nations-breaking-climate-pledge-with-gas-dash-in-global-south">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Many relatively progressive nations are sending contradictory signals. The UK, which is hosting the next major United Nations climate conference – Cop26 in Glasgow – continues to issue new domestic licences for oil and gas drilling in the North Sea, even after halting funding support overseas.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 7 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Alok Sharma is beginning to look like an emperor with net zero clothes</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/climate-change-fossil-fuels-cop26-alok-sharma-b1855750.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/climate-change-fossil-fuels-cop26-alok-sharma-b1855750.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>A recent report by Greenpeace and WWF found that CO2 emissions from investments in 2019 by just 25 UK banks and investors equated to nearly twice the entire emissions of the UK economy. It is finally officially clear – there can be no new oil fields, no new gas fields and absolutely no new coal mines if we are to have any possibility of avoiding a catastrophic climate crisis. For anybody to argue otherwise is just another form of climate denialism or greenwashing.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 7 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World's Peasant Farmers Unveil 'Anti-Imperialist Manifesto' in Defense of Nature</title>
			<link>https://www.commondreams.org/news/2021/06/02/worlds-peasant-farmers-unveil-anti-imperialist-manifesto-defense-nature</link>
			<source url="https://www.commondreams.org/news/2021/06/02/worlds-peasant-farmers-unveil-anti-imperialist-manifesto-defense-nature">Common Dreams</source>
			<description>The manifesto—published in English, Spanish, and French—slams imperialists of the Global North, including and especially the United States, for continuing to &#34;attack peripheral countries looking to privatize common goods that the people, the real owners of natural resources, used to take care of in each country.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 7 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Is the climate crisis causing more heatwaves&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/heatwaves-global-warming-summer-deaths-b1859696.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/heatwaves-global-warming-summer-deaths-b1859696.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Climate change has likely doubled the probability of heatwaves, according to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). Since 1998, the area of land that has been impacted by more than 30 heatwaves per year has doubled.  </description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 6 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Italian climate activists sue government over inaction</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/italian-climate-activists-sue-government-over-inaction</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/italian-climate-activists-sue-government-over-inaction">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The plaintiffs, among them environmental associations, Italian citizens, foreign residents and young activists with the Italy wing of the Fridays for Future activist group, argue that successive governments have failed to seriously address the climate crisis despite the country being vulnerable to extreme weather events.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 6 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Euro 2020&#58; What is the climate cost of tournament staged in 11 countries&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51806842</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51806842">BBC Sport</source>
			<description>At a time when the world is attempting to tackle the threat of &#34;irreversible&#34; climate change, is it really sensible that players, officials and fans will be criss-crossing the continent like never before&#63;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 6 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>World Environment Day 2021&#58; Greenwashing will not help anybody
</title>
			<link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/energy/world-environment-day-2021-greenwashing-will-not-help-anybody-77297</link>
			<source url="https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/energy/world-environment-day-2021-greenwashing-will-not-help-anybody-77297">Down To Earth</source>
			<description>The problem is not that there isn’t enough public money to finance restoration initiatives. The problem is that there isn’t enough political will to finance environment. Any proposition of radical change threatens this position and hence the invention of environmental fads like carbon offsets, Reducing Emissions from Deforestation and forest Degradation or REDD+ and net zero.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 5 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We need to treat climate change as the emergency that it is</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/opinions/2021/6/3/we-need-to-treat-climate-change-as-the-emergency-that-it-is</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/opinions/2021/6/3/we-need-to-treat-climate-change-as-the-emergency-that-it-is">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>Good journalism leads the conversation, and there is certainly plenty of climate news worth covering these days. In a pair of stunning developments last week, a court in The Netherlands ordered the Royal Dutch Shell oil company to reduce its own and its customers’ greenhouse gas emissions by 45 percent by 2030 in accordance with the Paris Agreement. Meanwhile, shareholders of ExxonMobil and Chevron rebelled against management’s refusal to take strong climate action. A week earlier, the International Energy Agency declared that all new fossil fuel development must stop to prevent irreversible climate destruction. The climate emergency is upending politics, economics and virtually every other subject journalists cover, and newsrooms need to catch up.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 5 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World Environment Day&#58; What action can I take to tackle the climate crisis&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/world-environment-day-2021-facts-activities-b1859053.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/world-environment-day-2021-facts-activities-b1859053.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Many lists suggesting how best to tackle the climate crisis focus heavily on what buying decisions to make, such as reducing meat consumption, cutting numbers of flights, driving less and using less plastic. While they are all excellent and valid suggestions, they often serve to shift the blame from the producers of pollutants to the humans buying these products or services.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 5 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate crisis will collapse our financial system, IMF official warns</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/climate-change-wall-street-imf-b1859419.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/climate-change-wall-street-imf-b1859419.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>&#34;The climate crisis is slow in the making, but it’s potentially disastrous,&#34; Tobias Adrian, director of the IMF’s monetary and capital markets department, told CNN recently, adding, &#34;There are many countries where you see the climate catastrophe is catastrophic for the financial system.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 4 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate tipping points could topple like dominoes, warn scientists</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/03/climate-tipping-points-could-topple-like-dominoes-warn-scientists</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/03/climate-tipping-points-could-topple-like-dominoes-warn-scientists">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The new research examined the interactions between ice sheets in West Antarctica, Greenland, the warm Atlantic Gulf Stream and the Amazon rainforest. The scientists carried out 3m computer simulations and found domino effects in a third of them, even when temperature rises were below 2C, the upper limit of the Paris agreement.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 4 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>High earners and well educated worry most about climate (but still fly)</title>
			<link>https://www.dutchnews.nl/news/2021/06/high-earners-and-well-educated-worry-most-about-climate-but-still-fly/</link>
			<source url="https://www.dutchnews.nl/news/2021/06/high-earners-and-well-educated-worry-most-about-climate-but-still-fly/">DutchNews.nl</source>
			<description>Some 3,648 people over the age of 18 took part in the survey which looked at attitudes to climate change, the switch to renewable energy, sustainable housing and mobility, as well as meat consumption and a climate conscious life style.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 4 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>How much can science really tell us about the future of climate change&#63;</title>
			<link>https://aeon.co/videos/how-much-can-science-really-tell-us-about-the-future-of-climate-change</link>
			<source url="https://aeon.co/videos/how-much-can-science-really-tell-us-about-the-future-of-climate-change">Aeon</source>
			<description>There are a few basic facts about climate change that we can be near-certain about: the global temperature is rising, this change is being driven by humans, and it represents a serious threat to a great many living things on the planet – humans included. But due to countless complexities and uncertainties, the trajectory of the global temperature in our deep past and, more pressingly, our near future is riddled with known unknowns. In Degrees of Uncertainty, the US video essayist Neil Halloran takes a data-centric deep dive into the climate crisis, emphasising the vital importance of rejecting fatalism when it comes to solving the problem. In doing so, he also charts the evolution of science itself since the age of enlightenment, and makes a case for science demanding scrutiny from an informed public, especially journalists.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 3 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World must rewild on massive scale to heal nature and climate, says UN</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/03/rewild-on-massive-scale-to-heal-nature-and-climate-says-un-decade-on-ecosystem-restoration-aoe</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/03/rewild-on-massive-scale-to-heal-nature-and-climate-says-un-decade-on-ecosystem-restoration-aoe">The Guardian</source>
			<description>&#34;Even if we feel the science is not mature enough, it should not really stop us from taking action. What you have as a model approach in one ecosystem might not apply in others. So there are many different sorts of ways about it,&#34; said Corli Pretorius, deputy director of the Unep World Conservation Monitoring Centre. &#34;It depends so much on the local context. This is not only about the environment&#58; it is for people as well, through safeguarding livelihoods, giving people access to nature in urban areas or improving health.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 3 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Six tough questions about Greenpeace’s climate campaign, answered by experts</title>
			<link>https://www.greenpeace.org.uk/news/climate-campaign-questions-cop26/</link>
			<source url="https://www.greenpeace.org.uk/news/climate-campaign-questions-cop26/">Greenpeace</source>
			<description>There’s no doubt: 2021 is a big year in the fight against climate change. The UK is hosting major international climate negotiations, and it’s an opportunity to steer the world away from a dangerous future. This should be a moment to take the lead. But right now the government’s half-hearted carbon-cutting efforts aren’t setting a good example. Greenpeace is campaigning to make the government do better, and we’ve all got a part to play. But these issues can be confusing.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 3 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change threatening iconic British species says WWF</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-threatening-iconic-british-species-says-wwf-12322723</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-threatening-iconic-british-species-says-wwf-12322723">Sky News</source>
			<description>In the UK, puffin populations have crashed over the last two decades, and the birds face multiple threats. Overfishing has reduced their food source, and now a rise in extreme weather events caused by climate change is cutting the time puffins can spend finding food.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 2 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Brecon Beacons landslips rise 'a clear climate change warning'</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-wales-57308780</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-wales-57308780">BBC News</source>
			<description>The National Trust, which has described climate change as the &#34;single biggest threat&#34; to the land and properties it cares for, has also spent a year mapping looming hazards across Wales. The research shows the Brecon Beacons getting warmer and wetter - both increasing the risk of landslides - and is among the most high-risk areas.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 2 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The 7 climate tipping points that could change the world forever</title>
			<link>https://grist.org/climate-tipping-points-amazon-greenland-boreal-forest/</link>
			<source url="https://grist.org/climate-tipping-points-amazon-greenland-boreal-forest/">Grist</source>
			<description>The particular danger, according to the Nature paper’s authors, is that even though change in a tipping element may happen slowly on a human timescale, once a certain threshold in the system is crossed, it can become unstoppable. This means that even if the planet’s temperature is stabilized, the transition of certain Earth systems from one state to another could pick up speed, like a rollercoaster car that’s already gone over the apex of a track. </description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 2 June 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>What your red meat habit is doing to the planet</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/red-meat-beef-carbon-footprint-b1854133.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/red-meat-beef-carbon-footprint-b1854133.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Farming animals is responsible for 14.5 per cent of global greenhouse gas emissions and the production of red meat accounts for 41 per cent of those emissions, according to the United Nations Food and Agricultural Organization... Per gram of protein, beef emits 20 times more emissions than pulses such as beans and lentils, and four times more than dairy products.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 1 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Human-induced global heating ‘causes over a third of heat deaths’</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/31/human-induced-global-heating-causes-over-third-heat-deaths</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/31/human-induced-global-heating-causes-over-third-heat-deaths">The Guardian</source>
			<description>A study, published in the journal Nature Climate Change, used data from 732 locations in 43 countries to calculate the number of deaths attributed to heat levels higher than the ideal temperature for human health, which varies across locations... Overall, they found 37&#37; of all heat-related deaths in the locations studied were attributable to human activity – but the largest climate change-induced contributions (more than 50&#37;) were in southern and western Asia (Iran and Kuwait), south-east Asia (the Philippines and Thailand) and Central and South America.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 1 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Youngsters suffering from 'eco-anxiety' as campaigners demand more climate change teaching in schools</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/youngsters-suffering-from-eco-anxiety-as-campaigners-demand-more-climate-change-teaching-in-schools-12321819</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/youngsters-suffering-from-eco-anxiety-as-campaigners-demand-more-climate-change-teaching-in-schools-12321819">Sky News</source>
			<description>&#34;They only tell you the science behind it, they don't tell you about the socio-economic consequences of it. And that just leaves us in ignorance about the actual practical problems of climate change,&#34; said Adam Waters, 17.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 1 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate&#58; World at risk of hitting temperature limit soon</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-57261670</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-57261670">BBC News</source>
			<description>In the last decade, it was estimated that the chance of any one year reaching the 1.5C threshold was only 20&#37;. This new assessment puts that risk at 40&#37;.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Weight of the world&#58; how climate activists handle anxiety and distress</title>
			<link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/lifestyle/healthandwellbeing/arid-40298210.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.irishexaminer.com/lifestyle/healthandwellbeing/arid-40298210.html">Irish Examiner</source>
			<description>Through programmes like Good Grief Network - 10-Steps to Personal Resilience &#38; Empowerment in a Chaotic Climate, Neto now tries to help others move past eco-distress. &#34;It’s not therapy. It’s peer-to-peer support. These groups certainly help me feel I’ve got choice – I can channel my righteous anger to make a difference in whatever small way I can.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australia court rules government has duty to protect youth from climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.jurist.org/news/2021/05/australia-court-rules-government-has-duty-to-protect-youth-from-climate-change/#</link>
			<source url="https://www.jurist.org/news/2021/05/australia-court-rules-government-has-duty-to-protect-youth-from-climate-change/#">Jurist</source>
			<description>The landmark decision comes after eight Australian teenagers filed a claim with the Federal Court, seeking an injunction to &#34;restrain an apprehended breach of the duty,&#34; that they believed the Commonwealth Minister for the Environment owes them and other Australian children. As a result of the age of the applicants, the proceedings were brought by their representative, 86 year-old Sister Marie Brigid Arthur, who is a Sister of the Brigidine Order of Victoria.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 128 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Shell and ExxonMobil feel heat of climate action</title>
			<link>https://dailybusinessgroup.co.uk/2021/05/shell-and-exxonmobil-feel-heat-of-climate-action/</link>
			<source url="https://dailybusinessgroup.co.uk/2021/05/shell-and-exxonmobil-feel-heat-of-climate-action/">Daily Business</source>
			<description>Climate activists have scored a milestone victory over big oil following a court ruling against Shell and investor action to force boardroom changes at ExxonMobil. A Dutch court ordered Shell to drastically cut its carbon footprint, while ExxonMobil was forced to accept activists on to its board. The landmark court ruling in The Hague marks the first time a fossil fuel company has been held accountable for its contribution to climate change and forced to reduce greenhouse gas emissions throughout its whole supply chain.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rapid heating of Indian Ocean worsening cyclones, say scientists</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/rapid-heating-of-indian-ocean-worsening-cyclones-say-scientists</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/rapid-heating-of-indian-ocean-worsening-cyclones-say-scientists">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Between 2001 and 2021, 28 cyclones formed in the Arabian Sea, along with a marked increase in storm intensity, fuelled by rising sea surface temperatures which reached as high as 31C (88F). A 2016 Nature study found anthropogenic global heating had contributed to the increased frequency of extremely severe cyclonic storms over the Arabian Sea.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What is the Climate Clock in New York&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/new-york-climate-change-clock-b1854953.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/new-york-climate-change-clock-b1854953.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>A giant digital display in New York’s Union Square is counting down second by second how much time humanity has to solve the climate crisis before it slips past a point of irreversible change. At the time of writing, it shows that the world must achieve zero emissions within six years, 219 days, one hour, six minutes and two seconds. By the time you read this, it will have ticked down further.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change&#58; New tests to see how carbon dioxide can be removed from the air</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/newsround/57226466</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/newsround/57226466">Newsround</source>
			<description>The UK has set a target to net zero carbon emissions which would involved big changes to the way we live our lives, how we heat our homes and how we manage the emissions we do produce. This new study aims to test out would involve large areas of land being dedicated to removing rid of carbon dioxide (CO2) from the air.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Friday essay&#58; searching for sanity in a world hell-bent on destruction</title>
			<link>https://theconversation.com/friday-essay-searching-for-sanity-in-a-world-hell-bent-on-destruction-160447</link>
			<source url="https://theconversation.com/friday-essay-searching-for-sanity-in-a-world-hell-bent-on-destruction-160447">The Conversatoin</source>
			<description>One does not need to be a conspiracy theorist to recognise, with Foucault, that power shapes knowledge. If profits and economic growth are the benchmarks of success in a society, it simply may not be profitable to expose a society as insane, and even members of an insane society may sooner choose wilful blindness than look too deeply into the subconscious of their own culture.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biodiversity may take millions of years to recover from human impacts</title>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/environment/freshwater-biodiversity-mass-extinction-human-impacts/</link>
			<source url="https://newatlas.com/environment/freshwater-biodiversity-mass-extinction-human-impacts/">New Atlas</source>
			<description>Earth’s many ecosystems are incredibly complex and remarkably fragile. The expansion and industrialization of the human race has triggered mass habitat destruction, the introduction of pollution and invasive species, and has prompted a steady but dramatic shift in our planet’s climate.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate Change Threatens Africa’s Cultural Heritage</title>
			<link>https://blog.ucsusa.org/adam-markham/climate-change-threatens-africas-cultural-heritage</link>
			<source url="https://blog.ucsusa.org/adam-markham/climate-change-threatens-africas-cultural-heritage">Union of Concerned Scientists</source>
			<description>All these changes threaten cultural heritage in Africa, including the tangible—such as historic buildings, archaeological sites and museum collections— and the intangible, including seasonal festivals, sacred sites and traditional fishing practices and foodways. To take just one example, the water levels of Lake Malawi have dropped in recent decades and rainfall there has become more unpredictable with longer drier periods and more extreme weather events, putting at risk traditional fishing practices that rely on some of the highest freshwater fish biodiversity on the planet. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>British banks finance 805m tonnes of CO2 production a year</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/25/british-banks-finance-805m-tonnes-of-co2-production-a-year</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/25/british-banks-finance-805m-tonnes-of-co2-production-a-year">The Guardian</source>
			<description>&#91;The report&#93; highlights the financial industry as one of the UK’s largest contributors to the climate crisis, and means that if the City were its own country, it would outrank Germany as the ninth largest emitter of CO2 in the world. Germany was responsible for emitting 776m tonnes of carbon in 2018, according to the latest available data.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fly infertility shows we’re underestimating how badly climate change harms animals</title>
			<link>https://theconversation.com/fly-infertility-shows-were-underestimating-how-badly-climate-change-harms-animals-161410</link>
			<source url="https://theconversation.com/fly-infertility-shows-were-underestimating-how-badly-climate-change-harms-animals-161410">The Conversation</source>
			<description>As the planet warms, animals may further evolve to withstand the effects of heat on fertility. But the speed at which a species can adapt may be too slow to ensure their survival. Our research has shown both tropical and widespread species of flies could not increase their fertility when exposed to simulated global warming, even after 25 generations.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The climate crisis requires a new culture and politics, not just new tech</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/24/climate-change-crisis-culture-politics-technology</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/24/climate-change-crisis-culture-politics-technology">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Many indigenous groups got to know their natural environments intimately and sustained themselves over millennia, often despite harsh conditions. They came to understand the limits of what these environments could support, and they grasped that caring for the environment was simultaneously an act of self-care. Pacific islanders would designate no-go areas of the ocean to avoid overfishing, while high-altitude farmers in the Andes would rely on terraces that reduced erosion to grow their crops. It is not a coincidence that as much as 80% of the world’s remaining biodiversity is located within territories inhabited by indigenous peoples.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It’s Not Just Up to You to Solve Climate Change</title>
			<link>https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/it-s-not-just-up-to-you-to-solve-climate-change-1.1607765</link>
			<source url="https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/it-s-not-just-up-to-you-to-solve-climate-change-1.1607765">Bloomberg News</source>
			<description>The individual responsibility narrative was honed in tobacco-industry messaging and began migrating to fossil fuels in the mid-2000s, Supran and Oreskes write. Case in point&#58; the ultimate metaphor of individual responsibility, the &#34;carbon footprint,&#34; entered common parlance around that time via BP Plc’s &#34;beyond petroleum&#34; campaign. Between 2005 and 2007, BP was spending at least $100 million a year on marketing alone, according to a figure cited in the One Earth study.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We can’t plant our way out of the climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://www.fastcompany.com/90639454/we-cant-plant-our-way-out-of-the-climate-crisis</link>
			<source url="https://www.fastcompany.com/90639454/we-cant-plant-our-way-out-of-the-climate-crisis">Fast Company</source>
			<description>&#34;I think the emphasis on planting trees is risky or even a misplaced dream unless we first put priority on reducing or halting climate change, because the trees are going to be stressed—they are getting stressed now,&#34; says Jonathan Overpeck, a climate scientist at the University of Michigan and one of the authors of an op-ed in Science arguing that the world needs to rethink how much we rely on tree planting as a climate solution.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Overpopulation is not the problem it once was, says Marco Magrini</title>
			<link>http://geographical.co.uk/opinion/item/4017-overpopulation-is-not-be-the-problem-it-once-was-says-marco-magrini</link>
			<source url="http://geographical.co.uk/opinion/item/4017-overpopulation-is-not-be-the-problem-it-once-was-says-marco-magrini">Geographical</source>
			<description>A new book has shed fresh light on the old overpopulation dilemma, this time from a completely different point of view. In 'Count Down', Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai epidemiologist Shanna Swan argues that the human race could gradually disappear because of increasing infertility. It may sound like something out of a dystopian novel, but the evidence is stark&#58; in the past 40 years, global sperm counts have halved, while female fertility has also dropped. &#34;The current state of reproductive affairs can’t continue much longer without threatening human survival&#34;, Swan writes... She explicitly compares the fertility crisis to climate change: two invisible and long-term threats. But there’s more. For the most part, they both spring from the same evil – fossil fuels. The main culprits of the falling sperm count are oil-derived molecules, in particular phthalates and bisphenol-A used in plastics, fertilisers and cosmetics, which disrupt the endocrine system.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK minister in charge of climate summit criticised for taking 25 flights in three months</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alok-sharma-cop-26-flights-carbon-emissions-b1852338.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alok-sharma-cop-26-flights-carbon-emissions-b1852338.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Alok Sharma had urged people to make &#34;small changes in the way we go about our day-to-day lives&#34; in order to cut their carbon emissions. But an analysis by the Daily Telegraph newspaper found that Mr Sharma took 25 flights in three months, travelling up to 73,853 miles between January 31 and May 12.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>We Need to Change How We Talk About Climate Action</title>
			<link>https://www.jacobinmag.com/2021/05/climate-change-green-new-deal-technology</link>
			<source url="https://www.jacobinmag.com/2021/05/climate-change-green-new-deal-technology">Jacobin</source>
			<description>Progressives must avoid being seen as the advocates of heavy-handed restrictions if we want action on climate change. The counter-argument should be: fossil fuel companies are stifling innovation and closing down your options for a good future. The market’s not going to deliver better choices on its own. If you want an open future, with new technologies and new possibilities, join us.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change is becoming less a battle of nations than rich vs poor</title>
			<link>https://www.ft.com/content/4788beae-9035-4449-b5cd-200dc7b6ea9d</link>
			<source url="https://www.ft.com/content/4788beae-9035-4449-b5cd-200dc7b6ea9d">Financial Times</source>
			<description>The UN’s 2020 Emissions Gap report says that limiting temperature rises to 1.5C, as envisaged by the 2015 Paris Agreement, would require the richest 1 per cent to cut their carbon footprint by 2030 “by at least a factor of 30”. Almost everything the wealthy do involves higher emissions, from living in bigger houses to running larger cars and flying more often, especially by private jet. Eating meat comes into it, as does owning a swimming pool. Not to mention a holiday home. Or homes.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Richest nations agree to end support for coal production overseas</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas">The Guardian</source>
			<description>After nearly two days of wrangling at a meeting of the G7 environment and energy ministers, hosted virtually by the UK on Thursday and Friday, all reaffirmed their commitment to limiting global heating to 1.5C, and committed to phasing out coal and fully decarbonising their energy sectors in the 2030s... The G7 communique contains a caveat, the Guardian understands, at the behest of the Japanese government, that would allow financing for coal in “limited circumstances at the discretion of each country”. It is understood this will only be used in exceptional circumstances.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Students in mass walk-out over climate action</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/video/students-in-mass-walk-out-over-climate-action-12312827</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/video/students-in-mass-walk-out-over-climate-action-12312827">Sky News</source>
			<description>Thousands of students in Australia have walked out of school to protest against the government's lack of climate action.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>'Zombie fires'&#58; The blazes that refuse to die</title>
			<link>https://www.nzherald.co.nz/world/zombie-fires-the-blazes-that-refuse-to-die/X2L55JIBPDWSP6ZBMMQYBDHJLU/</link>
			<source url="https://www.nzherald.co.nz/world/zombie-fires-the-blazes-that-refuse-to-die/X2L55JIBPDWSP6ZBMMQYBDHJLU/">NZ Herald</source>
			<description>Most of us think of forest fires as being contained within a single year. And for the most part, they are. But in the Arctic-boreal forests of Alaska, Siberia, Canada's Northwest Territories and similar landscapes, fires can burn deep into the carbon-rich soil where they linger and lurk, often undetected.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate disasters ‘caused more internal displacement than war’ in 2020</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/climate-disasters-caused-more-internal-displacement-than-war-in-2020</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/climate-disasters-caused-more-internal-displacement-than-war-in-2020">The Guardian</source>
			<description>There were at least 55 million internally displaced people (IDPs) by the end of last year, according to figures published by the Norwegian Refugee Council’s Internal Displacement Monitoring Centre (IDMC)... During a year that was the warmest on record, 5 million more people were displaced than in 2019.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australian government ‘mute’ on more ambitious plan to address climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://globalvoices.org/2021/05/20/australian-government-mute-on-more-ambitious-plan-to-address-climate-crisis/</link>
			<source url="https://globalvoices.org/2021/05/20/australian-government-mute-on-more-ambitious-plan-to-address-climate-crisis/">Global Voices</source>
			<description>The government is committed to a gas-fired recovery and handouts to fossil fuel emitters. In fact, funding for a new gas-fired plant has been announced just a day after the International Energy Agency recommended that there be no new investment in coal or gas projects.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Renewables 'tops UK public wish-list for green revolution'</title>
			<link>https://renews.biz/69618/renewables-tops-uk-public-wish-list-for-green-revolution/</link>
			<source url="https://renews.biz/69618/renewables-tops-uk-public-wish-list-for-green-revolution/">Renews</source>
			<description>The UK public want renewables to be at the top of government’s plans for green growth, according to a YouGov poll for RenewableUK. YouGov asked a weighted sample of 1700 people to rank the 10 key areas outlined in Prime Minister Boris Johnson's Ten Point Plan for a Green Industrial Revolution. Five times as many people supported the prioritisation of renewable energy as the top choice than any other green industry.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ditch new fossil fuel spending to reach net zero emissions - IEA</title>
			<link>https://uk.news.yahoo.com/radical-change-needed-reach-net-050753826.html</link>
			<source url="https://uk.news.yahoo.com/radical-change-needed-reach-net-050753826.html">Reuters</source>
			<description>The number of countries which have pledged to reach net zero has grown, but even if their commitments are fully achieved, there will still be 22 billion tonnes of carbon dioxide worldwide in 2050 which would lead to temperature rise of around 2.1C by 2100, the IEA said in its "Net Zero by 2050" report.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sport 2050&#58; 60-minute matches and rolling subs - a World Cup like no other?</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/56972365</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/56972365">BBC Sport</source>
			<description>Limited numbers of travelling fans, indoor stadiums and games at night when it's cooler - will the 2050 World Cup look a lot different to a "traditional" tournament as a result of climate change&#63;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Extreme Heat Risks May Be Widely Underestimated and Sometimes Left Out of Major Climate Reports</title>
			<link>https://insideclimatenews.org/news/16052021/extreme-heat-risks-climate-change/</link>
			<source url="https://insideclimatenews.org/news/16052021/extreme-heat-risks-climate-change/">Inside Climate News</source>
			<description>Last week’s updates to the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency’s Climate Indicators website, which had been delayed for years by the Trump administration, showed that major U.S. cities experienced three times as many heat waves—four or more days with temperatures that should only occur every 10 years—in the 2010s as during the 1960s. The season in which heat waves occur has lengthened by 47 days. In addition to heat exhaustion, recent research also showed that extreme heat dramatically increases the chances of pre-term births.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What I Learned in Space about the Climate Emergency</title>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-i-learned-in-space-about-the-climate-emergency/</link>
			<source url="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/what-i-learned-in-space-about-the-climate-emergency/">Scientific American</source>
			<description>You don’t see political borders from space—only humanity as a whole. We’re facing one of the greatest challenges in the history of humankind, but we are a very capable and resilient species. We can meet this challenge by leveraging solar power and new advances in battery storage. This is our century’s moonshot, and we need to rise to the challenge.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>‘I’m seen as the fool’&#58; the farmers putting trees back into the UK’s fields</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/im-seen-as-the-fool-the-farmers-putting-trees-back-into-the-uks-fields</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/im-seen-as-the-fool-the-farmers-putting-trees-back-into-the-uks-fields">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Studies outside Britain suggest silvopasture’s benefits include sequestering additional carbon, reducing flooding, increasing drought-resilience, improving animal health and weight and boosting biodiversity... The trial, involving seven farms in Devon and scientists from Rothamsted Research and the Organic Research Centre, is the brainchild of Luke Dale-Harris of the charity Farming and Wildlife Advisory Group. It is being co-funded by the Woodland Trust and Innovative Farmers, a Soil Association programme helping farmers participate in agricultural research.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The other climate risk investors need to talk about</title>
			<link>https://www.ft.com/content/c586e4cd-9fb7-47a3-8b43-3839e668fe3a</link>
			<source url="https://www.ft.com/content/c586e4cd-9fb7-47a3-8b43-3839e668fe3a">Financial Times</source>
			<description>Indeed, while many in the media have seized on &#34;greenwashing&#34; — companies embracing sustainable practices for public relations purposes — a far greater danger is &#34;brown-spinning&#34;&#58; selling off the highest-emitting components of businesses to private equity and hedge fund actors at a discount. This can reduce disclosure, shield polluters and marginalise the voice of the investor.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>COP26&#58; Climate summit in Glasgow is last hope for limiting global warming, leader warns</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/this-years-climate-summit-in-glasgow-is-last-hope-for-limiting-global-warming-minister-to-warn-12305905</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/this-years-climate-summit-in-glasgow-is-last-hope-for-limiting-global-warming-minister-to-warn-12305905">Sky News</source>
			<description>Kate Blagojevic, head of climate at Greenpeace UK, said: &#34;The UK can't claim climate leadership overseas whilst at home the government continues to entertain a new coal mine in Cumbria or maintains the planning block on English onshore wind. With only six months left the clock is ticking, if the government wants to be climate leaders it's time they act like it.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change is speeding up the degradation of ancient rock art</title>
			<link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2277535-climate-change-is-speeding-up-the-degradation-of-ancient-rock-art/</link>
			<source url="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2277535-climate-change-is-speeding-up-the-degradation-of-ancient-rock-art/">New Scientist</source>
			<description>The researchers suggest that the increasing severity and frequency of El Niño-induced droughts – a result of climate change that has led to more consecutive dry days and higher temperatures – as well as the moisture during the monsoon season have provided ideal conditions to accelerate the degradation of the rock paintings.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate emissions shrinking the stratosphere, scientists reveal</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/12/emissions-shrinking-the-stratosphere-scientists-find</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/12/emissions-shrinking-the-stratosphere-scientists-find">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The thickness of the atmospheric layer has contracted by 400 metres since the 1980s, the researchers found, and will thin by about another kilometre by 2080 without major cuts in emissions. The changes have the potential to affect satellite operations, the GPS navigation system and radio communications.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>If Paris Goals Are Not Met, Sea Level Rise May Become Unstoppable By 2060</title>
			<link>https://cleantechnica.com/2021/05/12/if-paris-goals-are-not-met-sea-level-rise-may-become-unstoppable-by-2060/</link>
			<source url="https://cleantechnica.com/2021/05/12/if-paris-goals-are-not-met-sea-level-rise-may-become-unstoppable-by-2060/">CleanTechnica</source>
			<description>Once the train of events is set in motion, dramatic ice loss would occur over the next several centuries. &#34;In the century after 2100, it’s potentially catastrophic,&#34; &#91;Robert DeConto, an expert in polar climate change at the University of Massachusetts&#93; says. &#34;If we did nothing at all to reduce emissions we could get 5 metres of sea level rise just from Antarctica by 2200, at which point you’d have to remap the world from space. It would be unimaginable.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ghost Forest &#39;Tree Farts&#39; Contribute To Greenhouse Gas Emissions</title>
			<link>https://www.eurasiareview.com/13052021-ghost-forest-tree-farts-contribute-to-greenhouse-gas-emissions/</link>
			<source url="https://www.eurasiareview.com/13052021-ghost-forest-tree-farts-contribute-to-greenhouse-gas-emissions/">Eurasia Review</source>
			<description>A new study from North Carolina State University finds that greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from standing dead trees in coastal wetland forests &#45; colloquially called &#34;tree farts&#34; &#45; need to be accounted for when assessing the environmental impact of so-called &#34;ghost forests.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Sir David Attenborough warns world faces &#39;crippling problems&#39; due to climate change</title>
			<link>https://uk.news.yahoo.com/david-attenborough-climate-change-warning-163126120.html</link>
			<source url="https://uk.news.yahoo.com/david-attenborough-climate-change-warning-163126120.html">Yahoo News UK</source>
			<description>He said: &#34;If we continue on our current path, we will face the collapse of everything that gives us our security&#58; food production, access to fresh water, habitable ambient temperature, and ocean food chains, and if the natural world can no longer support the most basic of our needs, then much of the rest of civilization will quickly break down.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What happened when Italy criminalised environmental protest</title>
			<link>https://theconversation.com/what-happened-when-italy-criminalised-environmental-protest-158014</link>
			<source url="https://theconversation.com/what-happened-when-italy-criminalised-environmental-protest-158014">The Conversation</source>
			<description>Developments in Italy and the UK both point at the creeping and dangerous ways in which some governments are clamping down on the right to protest. That these regulations are mostly targeting environmental protesters is no surprise&#58; public awareness has substantially grown over the past years and more and more people are being mobilised. Attempts to constrain such mobilisation should be resisted as they are unnecessary, disproportionate and ultimately inconsistent with efforts to tackle global climate change.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Campaigners Launch High Court Challenge Over North Sea Oil and Gas Drilling</title>
			<link>https://www.desmog.com/2021/05/12/climate-high-court-north-sea-oil-gas/</link>
			<source url="https://www.desmog.com/2021/05/12/climate-high-court-north-sea-oil-gas/">DeSmog</source>
			<description>According to campaigners, BP received a net payment of £675 million between 2015-2019 from the UK government after tax, while the UK reportedly paid Shell £70 million during that time. This cost will mount further if new oil and licenses are issued, in what campaigners say directly contravenes the UK’s commitment to reach net zero emissions by 2050.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change: Promises will mean rise of 2.4C &#45; study</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56984691</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56984691">BBC News</source>
			<description>Based on current national policies the estimated warming is 2.9C &#45; that's nearly twice what governments agreed it should be when they sealed the big climate deal in Paris in 2015.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Kids are taking governments to court over climate. And they are starting to win</title>
			<link>https://edition.cnn.com/2021/05/09/europe/climate-lawsuits-governments-intl-cmd/index.html</link>
			<source url="https://edition.cnn.com/2021/05/09/europe/climate-lawsuits-governments-intl-cmd/index.html">CNN</source>
			<description>Climate lawsuits are becoming an increasingly popular and powerful tool for climate change activists. A January report released by the United Nations Environment Programme found that the number of climate litigation cases filed around the world nearly doubled between 2017 and 2020.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Humans already have the tools to combat climate change but we lack leadership</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/humans-already-have-the-tools-to-combat-climate-change-but-we-lack-leadership</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/humans-already-have-the-tools-to-combat-climate-change-but-we-lack-leadership">The Guardian</source>
			<description>When you look at the true cost of the damage to the atmosphere, politicians’ claims that action on carbon reduction is too expensive become bizarre. When we burn fossil fuels, we’ve never factored in the ultimate cost of the damage to the atmosphere caused by excess CO2. In many countries, if you pollute a waterway, you have to clean it up or pay a substantial fee for the damage – that cost has to be factored in to the cost of running your business. In the case of emitting CO2 into the atmosphere, you can do that for little or no upfront and immediate cost. Are we offended by people polluting waterways because it is literally in your face whereas CO2 is a transparent gas&#63;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>How the cult of Bill Gates is leading us towards a climate disaster</title>
			<link>https://www.varsity.co.uk/opinion/21359</link>
			<source url="https://www.varsity.co.uk/opinion/21359">Varsity</source>
			<description>Ultimately, Gates’s technological &#39;solutions&#39; to the climate crisis are flawed, because they do not fundamentally change anything about the way our society functions. In doing so, they justify the status quo, based on destructive extractivism and excessive consumption. For instance, Gates’ solution for the emissions caused by aviation is to replace jet fuels with biofuels &#45; but this is a replacement, not a solution. It does not address the root causes, and is likely to cause more problems that it solves. It’s evident that Gates has the most to lose from more radical solutions to the climate crisis, which attempt to address our capitalist society’s obsession with economic growth, its ignorance of ecological boundaries, and its inherent inequalities. Gates does not want a new normal. He wants very much the same normal &#45; just with less carbon emissions.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 9 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fevers are plaguing the oceans &#45; and climate change is making them worse</title>
			<link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-01142-4</link>
			<source url="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-01142-4">Nature</source>
			<description>The effects of marine heatwaves can reverberate up the food chain, says Pippa Moore, a marine-community ecologist at Newcastle University, UK. Warm, low-nutrient water in the Northwest Pacific during a 2013–16 marine heatwave known as The Blob devastated phytoplankton growth. Then, Chinook salmon (Oncorhynchus tshawytscha) populations plunged, and as many as one million seabirds died in the Gulf of Alaska. Marine heatwaves have also caused massive amounts of coral bleaching in reefs around the world over the past several decades.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 9 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The World Is Waking Up to the Truth That Natural Gas Is Dirty</title>
			<link>https://newrepublic.com/article/162337/un-methane-report-natural-gas-dirty</link>
			<source url="https://newrepublic.com/article/162337/un-methane-report-natural-gas-dirty">New Republic</source>
			<description>Methane is shorter-lived than carbon dioxide in the atmosphere but as much as 86 times as potent a warming agent over the 20-year period after it’s emitted. It’s as much as 34 times more potent over 100 years. And despite suggestions to the contrary, it’s not planet-friendly when it’s burned, either&#59; used as fuel, it emits roughly half as much carbon dioxide as coal but is hardly carbon-neutral. In 2020, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Agency reported that methane rose more, over a single year, than since record-keeping began in the 1980s. Human-caused methane emissions—which account for more than half of the total—stem largely from just three sectors&#58; agriculture (40 percent), waste (20 percent), and fossil fuels (35 percent).</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 9 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>How to spot the difference between a real climate policy and greenwashing guff</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/06/difference-real-climate-policy-greenwashing-emissions</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/06/difference-real-climate-policy-greenwashing-emissions">The Guardian</source>
			<description>So what to make of it all&#63; Don’t think there is no real climate action&#58; renewable energy and electric cars are accelerating rapidly. And companies’ pledges can sometimes be impressive, for example Burger King committing to less meat and more plants in the patties it serves up. But until every government and corporate decision has to pass the bullshit test – does it really cut carbon now – then we are kidding ourselves if we think we are treating the climate crisis like the emergency it is.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 7 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sea level rise uncertainties&#58; Why all eyes are on Antarctica</title>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/meeting-paris-agreement-ambition-could-save-a-lot-of-sea-level-rise/</link>
			<source url="https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/05/meeting-paris-agreement-ambition-could-save-a-lot-of-sea-level-rise/">Ars Technica</source>
			<description>A pair of new studies published in Nature this week mark a new state of the art in ice modeling. Big questions about what we can expect are still there, and so planning for future sea level rise is still very much a matter of weighing risk under uncertainty.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 7 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cutting methane quickly is key to curbing dangerous warming, U.N. report says</title>
			<link>https://www.latimes.com/environment/story/2021-05-06/un-cutting-methane-quickly-key-to-curbing-dangerous-warming</link>
			<source url="https://www.latimes.com/environment/story/2021-05-06/un-cutting-methane-quickly-key-to-curbing-dangerous-warming">Los Angeles Times</source>
			<description>If human-caused methane emissions are cut by nearly in half by 2030, a half degree (0.3 degrees Celsius) of warming can be prevented by mid-century, according to Thursday’s report by the United Nations Environment Programme. The report said the methane reduction would be relatively inexpensive and achievable &#45; by plugging leaks in pipelines, stopping venting of natural gas during energy drilling, capturing gas from landfills and reducing methane from belching livestock and other agricultural sources, which is the biggest challenge.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 7 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>By owning a pet, you are doing more damage to the environment than you might realise</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/pets-uk-ownership-cats-dogs-carbon-environmental-impact-b1249610.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/pets-uk-ownership-cats-dogs-carbon-environmental-impact-b1249610.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>When pets can emit twice the carbon emissions of our homes&#39; electricity and kill up to 200 million wild prey in the UK every year, we cannot stay silent. Unfortunately, in many cases pet ownership is simply another form of destructive consumerism.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 5 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World's Biggest Banks Make Climate Change Promises, Invest in Fossil Fuels Anyway</title>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en/article/93yyke/worlds-biggest-banks-make-climate-change-promises-invest-in-fossil-fuels-anyway</link>
			<source url="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93yyke/worlds-biggest-banks-make-climate-change-promises-invest-in-fossil-fuels-anyway">VICE</source>
			<description>Even the most hardened cynic could be forgiven for feeling a flicker of optimism about the climate crisis recently. In the past six months alone, the United States has rejoined the Paris Agreement, China has pledged to go carbon neutral by 2060 and some of the world’s largest banks have promised to align their activities with global climate targets. But ambitions for the future are still failing to align with actions in the present.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 5 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New York wants to halt Bitcoin mining until its environmental impact is assessed</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/bitcoin-new-york-trading-environment-b1842631.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/bitcoin-new-york-trading-environment-b1842631.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>&#34;Cryptocurrency mining threatens not only New York’s climate goals, under the CLCPA, but also global energy policy, such as the Paris Agreement,&#34; Senate Bill S6486 says. Accordingly, &#34;there shall be a three-year moratorium on the operation of cryptocurrency mining centers in the state, including, but not limited to cryptocurrency mining centers located in converted fossil fuel power plants.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 5 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change: Rewilding UK's seas is &#39;as urgent as restoring forests&#39; in reducing emissions, campaigners say</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-rewilding-uks-seas-is-as-urgent-as-restoring-forests-in-reducing-emissions-campaigners-say-12294229</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/climate-change-rewilding-uks-seas-is-as-urgent-as-restoring-forests-in-reducing-emissions-campaigners-say-12294229">Sky News</source>
			<description>Restoring the seas around Britain is as important to achieving net zero carbon emissions as reforesting, campaigners have said. Around 205 million tonnes of carbon are stored in the UK&#39;s coastal waters, 50 million more than is held in all of the country's standing forests, according to a report by the Marine Conservation Society (MCS) and Rewilding Britain.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 4 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Melting ice reveals first world war relics in Italian Alps</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/04/melting-ice-reveals-first-world-war-relics-in-italian-alps</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/04/melting-ice-reveals-first-world-war-relics-in-italian-alps">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Luca Pedrotti, a scientific coordinator at Stelvio national park, said the melting glacier was also changing the vegetation dynamic in the area, while rising temperatures had led to a reduction of wildlife populations, including chamois, a species of goat-antelope, and grouse. &#34;Some species really suffer as they are very adapted to the cold Alpine environment,&#34; said Pedrotti. &#34;So they have to go higher and higher in search of cold temperatures and better-quality food.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 4 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bad weather forecasts are a climate crisis disaster</title>
			<link>https://www.wired.co.uk/article/solar-weather-forecasting</link>
			<source url="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/solar-weather-forecasting">WIRED</source>
			<description>Here’s the problem. On a sunny spring day in Great Britain, solar power can account for about 30 per cent of all the electricity being produced on the island. The exact number varies a lot, but under ideal conditions &#45; solar panels perform best on cool but sunny days &#45; they might churn out nine gigawatts (GW) of energy, a huge chunk of the 30GW average energy demand. So far, so good. But if a big cloud swoops down over the southwest, where many of Great Britain’s solar panels are situated, a significant portion of that renewable energy suddenly disappears from the grid – the equivalent of an entire gas power station instantly going offline. Hundreds of megawatts of energy gone, just like that.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 4 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Explainer&#58; Will global warming &#39;stop&#39; as soon as net-zero emissions are reached&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/explainer-will-global-warming-stop-as-soon-as-net-zero-emissions-are-reached</link>
			<source url="https://www.carbonbrief.org/explainer-will-global-warming-stop-as-soon-as-net-zero-emissions-are-reached">Carbon Brief</source>
			<description>Melting glaciers and ice sheets and rising sea levels all occur slowly and lag behind surface temperature warming. A zero-emissions world would still result in rising sea levels for many centuries to come, with some estimates suggesting that at least 80cm of additional sea level rise is &#34;locked in&#34;. To stop these impacts may, ultimately, require reducing global temperatures through net-negative global emissions, not just stopping temperature from rising by reaching net-zero.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 3 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>High street shops in England and Wales repurposed as climate emergency centres</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/03/high-street-shops-in-england-and-wales-repurposed-as-climate-emergency-centres</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/03/high-street-shops-in-england-and-wales-repurposed-as-climate-emergency-centres">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The sustainable centres are run by communities themselves and offer a range of activities that focus on both addressing the climate emergency and bringing people together, from hedgehog protectors to church groups. They include art exhibitions, exercise classes, sustainable living workshops, bike repair facilities and vegetarian and vegan cafes.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 3 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Watching a coral reef die as climate change devastates one of the most pristine tropical island areas on Earth</title>
			<link>https://apnews.com/article/climate-coral-reefs-climate-change-science-corals-1242fce9917857cac9dfed6589fc3655</link>
			<source url="https://apnews.com/article/climate-coral-reefs-climate-change-science-corals-1242fce9917857cac9dfed6589fc3655">Associated Press</source>
			<description>Research shows marine heat waves are now about 20 times more likely than they were just four decades ago, and they tend to be hotter and last longer. We&#39;re at the point now that some places in the world are anticipating coral bleaching every couple of years.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 3 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate Visualizations That Really Stick</title>
			<link>https://www.yesmagazine.org/opinion/2021/04/14/climate-visualizations-that-really-stick</link>
			<source url="https://www.yesmagazine.org/opinion/2021/04/14/climate-visualizations-that-really-stick">YES&#33; Magazine</source>
			<description>A recent Danish&#47;Swedish study about carbon labeling suggests that just knowing a bit more about our emissions really shifts our purchasing habits. Participants reduced the climate impacts of their choices by 25&#37; after choosing to learn about the emissions intensity of their products.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How will climate change affect marine megafauna&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.worldwildlife.org/magazine/issues/summer-2021/articles/how-will-climate-change-affect-marine-megafauna</link>
			<source url="https://www.worldwildlife.org/magazine/issues/summer-2021/articles/how-will-climate-change-affect-marine-megafauna">WWF</source>
			<description>For one, it will affect ocean predators’ food sources, as prey succumb to the heat or swim to more hospitable waters &#45; generally moving toward the poles &#45; with predators in pursuit. It will also alter habitats (think melting polar ice, but also violent storms burying seagrass beds or tearing up coral reefs). And shifting water conditions—including temperature, acidity, and current patterns—could decrease some species’ ability to reproduce or lead to more disease outbreaks.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New beer is made to taste like climate change &#45; and it tastes terrible</title>
			<link>https://thehill.com/changing-america/sustainability/climate-change/551198-new-beer-is-made-to-taste-like-climate-change</link>
			<source url="https://thehill.com/changing-america/sustainability/climate-change/551198-new-beer-is-made-to-taste-like-climate-change">Changing America</source>
			<description>&#34;To illustrate what the future of beer will look like if we don’t get more companies to commit to aggressive climate action, we’ve brewed up Torched Earth Ale. This beer uses the kind of ingredients that would be available in a climate-ravaged future...and they’re less than ideal,&#34; says the company...The 5.2 percent alcohol by volume beer uses hop extracts and dandelions instead of fresh hops and smoke tainted water instead of purified water along with various malt extracts.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>The problem with corporate climate targets</title>
			<link></link>
			<source url="">Tortoise</source>
			<description>Corporate emissions targets are just &#34;talk&#34;. As Tortoise’s Responsibility100 Index shows, what companies say they do and what they actually do are very different things. If we have a chance of limiting the climate crisis, we need companies to do even better than they currently promise to.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Preparing for more extreme climate impacts and disasters</title>
			<link>https://post.parliament.uk/preparing-for-more-extreme-climate-impacts-and-disasters/</link>
			<source url="https://post.parliament.uk/preparing-for-more-extreme-climate-impacts-and-disasters/">UK Parliamentary Office of Science and Technology</source>
			<description>In 2018, globally, around 108 million people required help from the international humanitarian system as a result of storms, floods, droughts and wildfires. By 2030, it is estimated that this number could increase by almost 50% at a cost of around US$20 billion a year. These growing risks highlight the need to improve the implementation and effectiveness of early warning systems worldwide to strengthen countries’ resilience to multiple weather-, climate- and water-related hazards. For example, the heatwave in Siberia in 2020 triggered widespread fires, with 1.15 million hectares burning in late June, associated with a release of about 56 million tonnes of carbon dioxide, more than the annual emissions of some industrialised countries such as Switzerland and Norway.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Declassified Satellite Images Show Glaciers Are Melting Faster Than Ever</title>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/declassified-satellite-images-show-glaciers-are-melting-1846789832</link>
			<source url="https://earther.gizmodo.com/declassified-satellite-images-show-glaciers-are-melting-1846789832">Gizmodo</source>
			<description>The quickening disappearance of the world’s glaciers isn’t just sad because they’re beautiful—which they are—or because complex ecosystems rely on them—which they do. It also spells disaster for communities who depend on them to live. Greenland, for instance, is home to some 56,000 people—most of whom are Indigenous—who depend on the ice for travel and hunting. As glaciers melt out, it could impact their way of life. Sometimes the threat can be even more acute; a glacier collapse earlier this year in the Himalayas unleashed a deadly flood. Of course, glacial melt everywhere is bad for those of us who live far away from them, too, because it contributes to sea level rise that threatens coastal communities.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Accounting problem could hamper the world&#39;s push to cut emissions</title>
			<link>https://www.stuff.co.nz/environment/climate-news/300287077/accounting-problem-could-hamper-the-worlds-push-to-cut-emissions</link>
			<source url="https://www.stuff.co.nz/environment/climate-news/300287077/accounting-problem-could-hamper-the-worlds-push-to-cut-emissions">Stuff.co.nz</source>
			<description>Scientists have identified a staggering 5 billion-tonne gap between greenhouse gas emissions acknowledged each year by the world&#39;s nations and the emissions calculated by independent models, an accounting discrepancy that threatens to complicate the already difficult task of resetting the world&#39;s climate trajectory.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&#39;Citizens&#39; juries&#39; deliver climate crisis verdict to Westminster</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/26/citizens-juries-deliver-climate-crisis-verdict-to-westminster</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/26/citizens-juries-deliver-climate-crisis-verdict-to-westminster">The Guardian</source>
			<description>In what is believed to be the first such exercise conducted across all parts of mainland Britain, the four citizens’ juries &#45; covering the Tees Valley, south Wales, Thurrock in Essex and Aberdeen &#45; all agreed the costs of climate change policies must not fall on low- and middle-income households.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MI6 &#39;green spying&#39; on biggest polluters to ensure nations keep climate change promises</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/mi6-green-spying-on-biggest-polluters-to-ensure-nations-keep-climate-change-promises-12286458</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/mi6-green-spying-on-biggest-polluters-to-ensure-nations-keep-climate-change-promises-12286458">Sky News</source>
			<description>Mr Moore, who is known as C, told Times Radio: &#34;Where people sign up to commitments on climate change, it is perhaps our job to make sure that actually what they are really doing reflects what they have signed up to. &#34;As somebody used to say - &#39;trust, but verify&#39;.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Brazil cuts environment spending one day after U.S. climate summit pledge</title>
			<link>https://news.trust.org/item/20210423205854-w4wy3/</link>
			<source url="https://news.trust.org/item/20210423205854-w4wy3/">Reuters</source>
			<description>Brazil's President Jair Bolsonaro approved a 24% cut to the environment budget for 2021 from last year's level, according to official numbers published on Friday, just one day after he vowed to increase spending to fight deforestation. Speaking on Thursday to the summit organized by U.S. President Joe Biden, Bolsonaro pledged to double the budget for environmental enforcement and end illegal deforestation by 2030.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Africans contribute the least to the climate crisis but suffer the most</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/africa-energy-climate-crisis-b1836560.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/africa-energy-climate-crisis-b1836560.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>For too long the UK has funded, and profited from, the expansion of fossil fuels in my continent of Africa.  While it was reaping the benefits of decarbonising its own energy system it was shackling poorer nations with dirty fossil fuel infrastructure, which the world must now move away from.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Changes to giant ocean eddies could have &#39;devastating effects&#39; globally</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/23/changes-to-giant-ocean-eddies-could-have-devastating-effects-globally</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/23/changes-to-giant-ocean-eddies-could-have-devastating-effects-globally">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The study, published in the journal Nature Climate Change, analysed the temperature and height of the ocean with the help of data from altimeters on satellites from 1993 until 2020... As well as absorbing about 90% of global heating since the 1970s, the ocean has pulled in about 40% of the extra carbon dioxide emitted into the atmosphere, mainly from fossil fuel burning, since the start of the Industrial Revolution... Solving the puzzle of how these ocean eddies were changing was &#34;one of the last frontiers&#34; in understanding how climate change could be affecting the ocean, &#91;Prof Matthew England, of the Climate Change Research centre at the University of New South Wales&#93; said.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change could cause &#39;irreversible impacts&#39; to lake ecosystems</title>
			<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-could-cause-irreversible-impacts-to-lake-ecosystems</link>
			<source url="https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-could-cause-irreversible-impacts-to-lake-ecosystems">Carbon Brief</source>
			<description>New research shows that lake &#34;stratification periods&#34; &#45; a seasonal separation of water into layers &#45; will last longer in a warmer climate. These longer periods of stratification could have &#34;far-reaching implications&#34; for lake ecosystems, the paper says, and can drive toxic algal blooms, fish die-offs and increased methane emissions.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Talk is cheap as world&#39;s largest polluters declare bold climate goals</title>
			<link>https://www.trtworld.com/life/talk-is-cheap-as-world-s-largest-polluters-declare-bold-climate-goals-46145</link>
			<source url="https://www.trtworld.com/life/talk-is-cheap-as-world-s-largest-polluters-declare-bold-climate-goals-46145">TRT World</source>
			<description>As climate crisis threats multiply, the leaders of top polluting countries gathered for an international climate summit but some still failed to pledge to ramp up their goals to reduce carbon emissions and slow global warming.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate crisis has shifted the Earth’s axis, study shows</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/23/climate-crisis-has-shifted-the-earths-axis-study-shows</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/23/climate-crisis-has-shifted-the-earths-axis-study-shows">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Some scientists argue that the scale of this impact means a new geological epoch &#45; the Anthropocene &#45; needs to be declared. Since the mid-20th century, there has been a marked acceleration of carbon dioxide emissions and sea level rise, the destruction of wildlife and the transformation of land by farming, deforestation and development.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>10 things we learned about Earth since the last Earth Day</title>
			<link>https://www.vox.com/22392485/earth-day-climate-change-environment-year-review/</link>
			<source url="https://www.vox.com/22392485/earth-day-climate-change-environment-year-review">Vox</source>
			<description>If anything, the worst public health crisis in a century has brought our understanding of our planet&#44; and our place in the fragile yet resilient web of life throughout it, into stark relief.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate scientists&#58; concept of net zero is a dangerous trap</title>
			<link>https://theconversation.com/climate-scientists-concept-of-net-zero-is-a-dangerous-trap-157368</link>
			<source url="https://theconversation.com/climate-scientists-concept-of-net-zero-is-a-dangerous-trap-157368">The Conversation</source>
			<description>We have arrived at the painful realisation that the idea of net zero has licensed a recklessly cavalier &#34;burn now, pay later&#34; approach which has seen carbon emissions continue to soar. It has also hastened the destruction of the natural world by increasing deforestation today, and greatly increases the risk of further devastation in the future.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Four steps this Earth Day to avert environmental catastrophe</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/apr/22/earth-day-environmental-catastrophe-policy</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/apr/22/earth-day-environmental-catastrophe-policy">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Today is Earth Day, which should provide us with an opportunity to pause and confront the awful predicament humanity faces. We eat microplastics, breathe pollution and watch other life-forms decline to extinction. We face intersecting poverty, health, climate and biodiversity crises. Our global predicament is that consumption by the wealthy is driving us towards planetary disaster&#44; yet billions live in poverty and need to consume more to live well. In this cycle&#44; any version of &#34;success&#34; only hastens catastrophe.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Central banks need to take action now on climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.ft.com/content/e5be5650-d880-48cd-b3f4-fdedeb41480e</link>
			<source url="https://www.ft.com/content/e5be5650-d880-48cd-b3f4-fdedeb41480e">Financial Times</source>
			<description>Central banks cannot solve this problem alone. But as Mark Carney said almost six years ago as then Bank of England governor&#58; &#34;Once climate change becomes a defining issue for financial stability&#44; it may already be too late.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate Change and Capitalism Are Forcing Chilean Farmers to Abandon Their Land</title>
			<link>https://www.thenation.com/article/environment/climate-change-chile-farming/</link>
			<source url="https://www.thenation.com/article/environment/climate-change-chile-farming/">The Nation</source>
			<description>Human-caused climate change is also contributing to the drought. Warmer air temperatures are shrinking glaciers that feed streams and rivers and disrupting rainfall patterns. A 2015 study found that climate change is to blame for around a quarter of the rainfall deficit in central Chile.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&#34;Big Words and Little Action&#34;&#58; Greta Thunberg&#39;s Passionate Letter on Why We Must Do More to Tackle the Climate Crisis</title>
			<link>https://www.vogue.com/article/greta-thunberg-letter-climate-change-earth-day</link>
			<source url="https://www.vogue.com/article/greta-thunberg-letter-climate-change-earth-day">Vogue</source>
			<description>The point is that we can keep using creative carbon accounting and cheat in order to pretend that these targets are in line with what is needed. But we must not forget that while we can fool others and even ourselves, we cannot fool nature and physics. The emissions are still there, whether we choose to count them or not.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>The Climate-Education Crisis</title>
			<link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-change-forcing-children-out-of-school-by-yasmine-sherif-2021-04</link>
			<source url="https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-change-forcing-children-out-of-school-by-yasmine-sherif-2021-04">Project Syndicate</source>
			<description>We need to start connecting the dots between these issues. By incorporating education aid into their broader climate agendas, governments can replace the vicious cycle of displacement, poverty, and insecurity with a new, virtuous cycle. Educated girls are powerful agents of change. With the right education, today’s marginalized and vulnerable young people can build tomorrow’s stronger and more resilient economies and communities.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>There’s no vaccine for climate change. Are we prepared for extreme weather to be our new normal?</title>
			<link>https://mothership.sg/2021/04/extreme-weather-pub-water-conservation/</link>
			<source url="https://mothership.sg/2021/04/extreme-weather-pub-water-conservation/">Mothership</source>
			<description>Just last month, the UN issued a sobering call on World Water Day for stronger efforts to address the global water crisis, as water scarcity is increasing to the point where more than half of the world’s population may be living in water-stressed areas by 2050.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>11 Foods That Are Already Being Impacted by the Climate Crisis</title>
			<link>https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-pictures/foods-most-affected-by-climate-change-1144590/gettyimages-86056867/</link>
			<source url="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-pictures/foods-most-affected-by-climate-change-1144590/gettyimages-86056867/">Rolling Stone</source>
			<description>In many cases, these changes mean that the foods that are part of a region&#39;s identity &#45; Vermont&#39;s maple syrup or Colombia&#39;s coffee &#45; will have to migrate as their ideal climate shifts, often further north. &#34;Napa Valley pretty much ends up in Canada not too long from now,&#34; says Lisa Goddard, director of the International Research Institute for Climate and Society at Columbia University.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Critics Warn Lawsuits by EU Fossil Fuel Giants Steal Billions From Public, Undermine Green Transition</title>
			<link>https://www.commondreams.org/news/2021/04/19/critics-warn-lawsuits-eu-fossil-fuel-giants-steal-billions-public-undermine-green</link>
			<source url="https://www.commondreams.org/news/2021/04/19/critics-warn-lawsuits-eu-fossil-fuel-giants-steal-billions-public-undermine-green">Common Dreams</source>
			<description>In addition to redirecting public funding from clean energy development to the coffers of fossil fuel corporations, critics of the ETC warn that the treaty has a chilling effect on climate ambition overall—prompting states to weaken climate policies in an attempt to prevent energy companies from claiming that certain measures do not meet the &#91;Energy Charter Treaty&#93;&#39;s unclear standard of &#34;fair and equitable treatment.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Dead Sea is dying. Drinking water is scarce. Jordan faces a climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://phys.org/news/2021-04-dead-sea-dying-scarce-jordan.html</link>
			<source url="https://phys.org/news/2021-04-dead-sea-dying-scarce-jordan.html">Phys.org</source>
			<description>Though Jordan is uniquely challenged, it's a preview of what the region faces as a whole. Middle Eastern nations top the list of most water-stressed countries, the World Resources Institute says.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&#39;Relentless&#39; climate crisis intensified in 2020, says UN report</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/19/relentless-climate-crisis-intensified-in-2020-says-un-report</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/19/relentless-climate-crisis-intensified-in-2020-says-un-report">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The report, produced by the WMO and partners, found that cuts in food production, transport and economic activity caused by the Covid-19 pandemic exacerbated the effects of extreme weather on communities. It said the temporary fall in new carbon emissions had &#34;no discernible impact&#34; on atmospheric concentrations.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>A68 iceberg that was once world&#39;s largest melts away</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/a68-iceberg-melt-climate-crisis-b1833310.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/a68-iceberg-melt-climate-crisis-b1833310.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Prof Luckman added that while the calving and demise of a single iceberg such as A68 cannot be directly attributed to climate change, &#34;the loss of ice around Antarctica, which has increased by a factor of five since the 1990s, is certainly a result of changes in ocean heat and circulation&#34;.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Watchdogs cry wolf as oil companies claim green barrels</title>
			<link>https://www.businesslive.co.za/bd/companies/2021-04-18-watchdogs-cry-wolf-as-oil-companies-claim-green-barrels/</link>
			<source url="https://www.businesslive.co.za/bd/companies/2021-04-18-watchdogs-cry-wolf-as-oil-companies-claim-green-barrels/">Business Live</source>
			<description>Oil company claims of clean fuels through offsetting are like tobacco companies &#34;saying they sell nicotine-free cigarettes because they paid someone else to sell some chewing gum&#34;, said David Turnbull, a spokesperson for Washington-based Oil Change International, an advocacy group opposing fossil fuels.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate situation is &#39;extremely urgent&#39; says US special envoy</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/video/climate-situation-is-extremely-urgent-says-us-special-envoy-12278898</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/video/climate-situation-is-extremely-urgent-says-us-special-envoy-12278898">Sky News</source>
			<description>John Kerry says countries are not doing enough to fight the crisis.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Why Spy Agencies Say the Future Is Bleak</title>
			<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/opinion/global-trends-intelligence-report.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/opinion/global-trends-intelligence-report.html">New York Times</source>
			<description>The world envisioned in the 144-page report, ominously subtitled &#34;A More Contested World,&#34; is rent by a changing climate, aging populations, disease, financial crises and technologies that divide more than they unite, all straining societies and generating &#34;shocks that could be catastrophic.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rise of atmospheric carbon dioxide continues unabated</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/apr/17/rise-atmospheric-carbon-dioxide-covid-climate</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/apr/17/rise-atmospheric-carbon-dioxide-covid-climate">The Guardian</source>
			<description>When carbon dioxide levels were last at this level, 3.6m years ago, sea levels were 20 metres higher and vast areas now covered in ice were forested. Land where many of our coastal cities now stand and much of our food is grown were deep under water. Large areas in the tropics would have been uninhabitable because they would have been too hot.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A New Threat to New York&#39;s Clean Energy Goals&#58; Bitcoin Mining</title>
			<link>https://www.nysfocus.com/2021/04/13/new-york-bitcoin-mining-threat/</link>
			<source url="https://www.nysfocus.com/2021/04/13/new-york-bitcoin-mining-threat/">New York Focus</source>
			<description>A decade ago, the bankrupt owner of the Greenidge power plant in Dresden, New York, sold the uncompetitive coal-fired relic for scrap and surrendered its operating permits. For the next seven years, the plant sat idle on the western shore of Seneca Lake, a monument to the apparent dead end reached by the state’s fossil fuel infrastructure. But today, Greenidge is back up and running as a Bitcoin mining operation. The facility hums with energy-hungry computers that confirm and record Bitcoin transactions, drawing power from the plant’s 106-megawatt generator now fueled by natural gas.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>New Google Earth feature shows 40 years of devastating climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/google-earth-update-climate-timelapse-b1831967.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/google-earth-update-climate-timelapse-b1831967.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>&#34;Our planet has seen rapid environmental change in the past half-century — more than any other point in human history. Many of us have experienced these changes in our own communities&#59; I myself was among the thousands of Californians evacuated from their homes during the state’s wildfires last year. For other people, the effects of climate change feel abstract and far away, like melting ice caps and receding glaciers,&#34; a Google representative said in the search giant’s announcement.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Therapists are reckoning with eco&#45;anxiety</title>
			<link>https://www.stuff.co.nz/environment/climate-news/300279032/therapists-are-reckoning-with-ecoanxiety</link>
			<source url="https://www.stuff.co.nz/environment/climate-news/300279032/therapists-are-reckoning-with-ecoanxiety">Stuff.nz</source>
			<description>There&#39;s growing recognition in the field of psychology that people are experiencing distress over climate change. More than 40 per cent of Americans felt &#34;disgusted&#34; or &#34;helpless&#34; about climate change, according to a survey published by researchers at Yale University. A 2020 poll from the APA found that more than half of respondents were somewhat or extremely anxious about the effects of climate change on their own mental health. Though not officially classified in the DSM-5, the tome therapists use to classify and treat mental illnesses, there&#39;s a name for this state of despair that has emerged from academic texts and media since as recently as 2007&#58; eco-anxiety.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>To save the planet, focus on corporate-tax free riders</title>
			<link>https://www.ft.com/content/663cba6f-391e-4789-908e-b560936f2eaf</link>
			<source url="https://www.ft.com/content/663cba6f-391e-4789-908e-b560936f2eaf">Financial Times</source>
			<description>Free riders matter in combating rising temperatures, because global emissions of greenhouse gases are the core problem. Countries and their populations know that if they make a special effort to be green, others will free ride or cheat in any deal, so there is no incentive to make the required effort. You can see the outcome clearly in the data. The concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere has not deviated from its steady upward march after 30 years of UN climate conferences.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate Research Station Abandoned Because It’s Falling Into the Sea</title>
			<link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/climate-research-station-abandoned-falling-into-sea</link>
			<source url="https://futurism.com/the-byte/climate-research-station-abandoned-falling-into-sea">Futurism</source>
			<description>Natural phenomena have always shaped and reshaped the coastline of Cape Cod. But the process has seemingly accelerated thanks to the impacts of global climate change, especially during recent storm seasons. At some points, according to the Guardian, up to six feet of land was getting swallowed up over the course of a single day.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Oil firm bosses&#39; pay &#39;incentivises them to undermine climate action&#39;</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/15/oil-firm-ceos-pay-is-an-incentive-to-resist-climate-action-study-finds</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/15/oil-firm-ceos-pay-is-an-incentive-to-resist-climate-action-study-finds">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The study tracks ExxonMobil, Chevron, Shell and BP &#45; four of the biggest &#34;carbon major&#34; oil companies &#45; since 1990. This was around the time the global public heard the first high-profile warning about the dangers of burning fossil fuels. Executives had been told of the threat many years earlier, but instead of working on a transition to cleaner, safer forms of energy, they ramped up production, played down risks and adopted public relations campaigns that misleadingly presented oil companies as part of the solution rather than the source of the problem.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Only 3 per cent of world surface is ecologically intact, research suggests</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/world-ecologically-intact-three-percent-b1831803.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/world-ecologically-intact-three-percent-b1831803.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Only 2.8 per cent of the world’s land surface is &#34;functionally intact&#34;, meaning there has been no loss of species to a point that would affect the healthy functioning of an ecosystem. This was 10 times lower than previous estimates. The research, published in the journal Frontiers in Forests and Global Change, also estimated estimated around 2.9 per cent of the world’s land surface can be considered &#34;faunally intact&#34; without any loss of animal species.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Wildlife in decline as report reveals shocking state of UK&#39;s woods and trees</title>
			<link>https://www.standard.co.uk/news/uk/wildlife-decline-report-state-uk-woods-trees-b929573.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.standard.co.uk/news/uk/wildlife-decline-report-state-uk-woods-trees-b929573.html">Evening Standard</source>
			<description>Climate change is affecting the pattern of the seasons, with spring occurring around 8.4 days earlier, impacting wildlife such as blue tits which can find their breeding cycles now mismatch their food supply for chicks. While native woods and trees can help curb carbon emissions and reverse declines in wildlife, failing to address the problems will undermine efforts to tackle both the climate and nature crises.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Green-collared jobs aren&#39;t going to create themselves &#45; the government needs a clear plan</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/green-jobs-climate-change-cop26-workforce-b1831241.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/green-jobs-climate-change-cop26-workforce-b1831241.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>If we look at the current workforce, more needs to be done to map out where we can repurpose skills and how to enable this shift to begin this year. Training on the job is crucial to support the transition but also re-focus skillsets towards net-zero roles. By being able to take time out of work to complete training and development alongside their current jobs, we can start to plug gaps in areas where skills can be transferred. It&#39;s a solution that can work for all people across different backgrounds and experiences.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change and the &#34;law of acceleration&#34;</title>
			<link>https://www.resilience.org/stories/2021-04-11/climate-change-and-the-law-of-acceleration/</link>
			<source url="https://www.resilience.org/stories/2021-04-11/climate-change-and-the-law-of-acceleration/">Resilience</source>
			<description>Climate scientists tell us we need not just a deceleration in growth of greenhouse gas emissions, but actual rapid declines to address climate change with any hope of success. Given how we think about acceleration, it’s hard to imagine that our global society will seek accelerated reductions in emissions as a primary goal.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>France approves ban on short-haul flights in climate push</title>
			<link>https://uk.finance.yahoo.com/news/france-approves-ban-on-some-domestic-flights-climate-change-135104389.html</link>
			<source url="https://uk.finance.yahoo.com/news/france-approves-ban-on-some-domestic-flights-climate-change-135104389.html">Yahoo Finance UK</source>
			<description>French officials moved late on Saturday to ban domestic flights on routes that are connected by train and can be travelled in less than two-and-a-half hours. The vote comes as governments around the world look at ways to lower carbon emissions and achieve net-zero targets. 
It forms part of a broader climate bill from France which looks to cut carbon emissions from 1990's levels by 40% by 2030.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Stability in the Middle East now depends on how serious we are about tackling climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/security-energy-climate-change-middle-east-b1828582.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/opinion/security-energy-climate-change-middle-east-b1828582.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>In the past, our predominant interests in the region were in counterterrorism and lucrative arms deals. The recent meeting between John Kerry, the US special presidential envoy for climate, and the UK’s own Cop26 president, Alok Sharma, demonstrated that the new common interest is climate change, and especially its link to security.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The &#39;30x30&#39; Campaign to Save the Biosphere</title>
			<link>https://www.worldpoliticsreview.com/articles/29565/the-30x30-campaign-to-save-the-planet-from-biodiversity-threats</link>
			<source url="https://www.worldpoliticsreview.com/articles/29565/the-30x30-campaign-to-save-the-planet-from-biodiversity-threats">World Politics Review</source>
			<description>Over the past two years, an extraordinary global campaign has emerged to protect 30 percent of Earth’s total surface from human exploitation by 2030. The members of this so-called 30x30 coalition, which now includes scores of governments, understand that climate change is only one half of the planet’s environmental crisis. The Paris Agreement, while imperative to curb greenhouse gas emissions, will do little by itself to save the planet’s collapsing biodiversity or preserve the massive ecosystems upon which humanity depends—and which we are fast degrading.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Those who worry about CO2 should worry about methane, too</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/04/03/those-who-worry-about-co2-should-worry-about-methane-too</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2021/04/03/those-who-worry-about-co2-should-worry-about-methane-too">The Economist</source>
			<description>The importance of tackling methane has become more apparent in the past decade and a half. After a plateau which began in 1999, concentrations of the gas in the atmosphere started rising again in 2007, a trend that continues to this day. At the moment, more than 300m tonnes are emitted every year as a consequence of human activity, and that rate is growing. As a result, methane concentrations are now more than two-and-a-half times what they were before the Industrial Revolution, and are rising faster than allowed for in all but the most pessimistic climate projections for the 21st century.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Could a House Work in a Post Climate Change Scenario&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.archdaily.com/959389/how-could-a-house-work-in-a-post-climate-change-scenario</link>
			<source url="https://www.archdaily.com/959389/how-could-a-house-work-in-a-post-climate-change-scenario">ArchDaily</source>
			<description>The residential units are intended for small-scale living; sustainable, self-sufficient, and technologically hyperconnected. To be built, each unit uses recycled materials of natural and local origin, following the logic of kilometer zero materials. Specifically, the architects propose the use of panels and laminates made with American agave wood, popularly known as "desert wood." Its fibers and roots can be reused to make thermal and acoustic insulation systems, thus avoiding artificial products.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change will hit &#39;endemic&#39; plants and animals the hardest, study warns</title>
			<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-will-hit-endemic-plants-and-animals-the-hardest-study-warns</link>
			<source url="https://www.carbonbrief.org/climate-change-will-hit-endemic-plants-and-animals-the-hardest-study-warns">Carbon Brief</source>
			<description>An endemic species lives exclusively in one geographic region. Areas of high biodiversity are often “overflowing” with endemic &#34;flagship species&#34; &#91;...&#93; The authors find that land-based endemic species are projected to be 2.7 times &#34;more impacted&#34; by climate change than non-endemic native species, and 10 times more impacted than introduced species.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Marine species increasingly can&#39;t live at equator due to global heating</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/08/marine-species-increasingly-cant-live-at-equator-due-to-global-heating</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/08/marine-species-increasingly-cant-live-at-equator-due-to-global-heating">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Analysis of the changing locations of almost 50,000 marine species between 1955 and 2015 found a predicted impact of global heating – species moving away from the equator – can now be observed at a global scale.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate disclosure could spark big investments&#58; US climate envoy</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/8/climate-disclosure-could-spark-big-investments-us-climate-envoy</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/8/climate-disclosure-could-spark-big-investments-us-climate-envoy">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>&#34;We have to make the invisible visible &#45; the transition risks that banks are carrying because they’re investing in high-carbon activities that over time are going to be phased out, and the physical risk, investments in highly vulnerable coastal areas, or in agriculture that could be affected by floods or by droughts,&#34; [Kristalina Georgieva, IMF Managing Director] said.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Carbon dioxide levels in atmosphere reach record high</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/07/carbon-dioxide-levels-in-atmosphere-reach-record-high</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/07/carbon-dioxide-levels-in-atmosphere-reach-record-high">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Prof Simon Lewis, from University College London, said: &#34;It is easy to forget just how much and just how fast fossil fuel emissions are affecting our planet. It took over 200 years to increase the amount of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere by 25%, and just 30 years to reach 50% above pre-industrial levels. This dramatic change is like a human meteorite hitting Earth.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Emotional leadership and environmental crises&#58; a view from nineteenth-century Vietnam</title>
			<link>https://blog.history.ac.uk/2021/04/emotional-leadership-and-environmental-crises-a-view-from-nineteenth-century-vietnam/</link>
			<source url="https://blog.history.ac.uk/2021/04/emotional-leadership-and-environmental-crises-a-view-from-nineteenth-century-vietnam/">On History</source>
			<description>In the nineteenth century court of the Nguyen dynasty, it would have been unimaginable to be emotionally detached from the environment, in part because the landscape was understood to be full of sentiment. Royal rule required responding to and mediating these emotional flows through sincere behaviour and ritual practice. Today we might discount the notion that rituals are efficacious in the natural world or that human beings can resonate with an emotional environment. And yet, in the current pandemic and climate emergency the idea of how nature &#34;treats us&#34; is more at play than ever before. In this sense, the problems faced by nineteenth century Vietnamese kings &#45; of how to connect with nature and utilise emotion effectively &#45; are ones we all share.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change&#58; Polar bears forced to eat seabird eggs as Arctic hunting ground shrinks</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/polar-bears-forced-to-eat-seabird-eggs-as-arctic-hunting-ground-shrinks-b1827744.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/news/polar-bears-forced-to-eat-seabird-eggs-as-arctic-hunting-ground-shrinks-b1827744.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Researchers looked both at predictions for climate heating and data on the increasing portion of the year that the bears&#39; must survive on their fat reserves. Earlier this month, a paper published in the journal Global Change Biology found that polar bears maintained highly specialized diets of soft blubber and flesh for hundreds of years &#45; even during previous periods of Arctic warming.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bitcoin Mining Could Use More Energy Than All of Italy by 2024</title>
			<link>https://www.vice.com/en/article/dy8amw/bitcoin-mining-energy-consumption</link>
			<source url="https://www.vice.com/en/article/dy8amw/bitcoin-mining-energy-consumption">VICE</source>
			<description>A team of researchers from the University of Chinese Academy of Sciences in Beijing, Cornell University in the U.S. and University of Surrey in the U.K. warns that if people continue to mine Bitcoin unchecked, the energy consumption associated with those activities could reach 297 Twh per year by 2024, more than the 290 TwH in electricity consumed by Italy in 2019.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Does Carbon Offsetting Really Address the NFT Ecological Dilemma&#63;</title>
			<link>https://hyperallergic.com/634236/does-carbon-offsetting-really-address-the-nft-ecological-dilemma/</link>
			<source url="https://hyperallergic.com/634236/does-carbon-offsetting-really-address-the-nft-ecological-dilemma/">Hyperallergic</source>
			<description>Critics say voluntary offset markets &#45; unlike mandatory compliance offset programs &#45; are largely unregulated, making it challenging to verify whether reductions actually occur. Even when working perfectly, some worry that they function as a form of &#34;greenwashing&#34; by allowing companies to continue burning fossil fuels and emitting CO2. A forest conservation project in Brazil backed by FIFA for the 2014 World Cup was suspended after loggers destroyed more trees than all the credits sold, ProPublica reported. </description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Global warming puts 99% of Great Barrier Reef coral at risk, study finds</title>
			<link>https://www.thenationalnews.com/world/oceania/global-warming-puts-99-of-great-barrier-reef-coral-at-risk-study-finds-1.1197755</link>
			<source url="https://www.thenationalnews.com/world/oceania/global-warming-puts-99-of-great-barrier-reef-coral-at-risk-study-finds-1.1197755">The National</source>
			<description>Coral bleaching in 2016, 2017 and 2020 has further damaged its health and affected its animal, bird and marine population, the International Union for Conservation of Nature said. Bleaching occurs when hotter water destroys the algae that the coral feeds on, causing it to turn white. The report also found that if Australia warmed up to 2°C, only 1 per cent of the reef is expected to survive.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Most countries are making progress on phasing out coal—but not fast enough to offset China&#39;s expansion</title>
			<link>https://energyandcleanair.org/most-countries-are-making-progress-on-phasing-out-coal/</link>
			<source url="https://energyandcleanair.org/most-countries-are-making-progress-on-phasing-out-coal/">Centre for Research on Energy and Clean Air</source>
			<description>Globally, the projected coal-fired capacity in 2030, if all proposed projects are realized and retirements aren’t accelerated further, is almost 2400 GW, while the amount of capacity consistent with the IPCC 1.5 degree pathways would be 1100 GW. An additional 1300 GW will need to be cancelled or retired: 450 GW in the OECD, 500 GW in China and 400 GW in the rest of the world, to meet the emission budgets consistent with limiting global warming to 1.5 degrees.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		
		
		<item>
			<title>How Big Meat Is Funding Climate Denial and Polluting the Planet</title>
			<link>https://earther.gizmodo.com/how-big-meat-is-funding-climate-denial-and-polluting-th-1846620142</link>
			<source url="https://earther.gizmodo.com/how-big-meat-is-funding-climate-denial-and-polluting-th-1846620142">Gizmodo</source>
			<description>The United Nations estimates that animal agriculture accounts for more than 14% of global emissions. A seminal 2018 report, which this new analysis builds on, found that the world’s top 35 beef and dairy producers alone account for 15% of all those emissions. One of the gnarliest issues with animal agriculture is, of course, methane produced from cows. Methane is a short-term greenhouse gas &#45; it doesn’t stay in the atmosphere as long as carbon dioxide &#45; but it is substantially more potent and can cause more damage while it’s in there. Research published last year found that global annual methane emissions increased 9% from 2000 to 2017—the equivalent of doubling the total carbon dioxide emissions of Germany or France—largely as a result of agriculture.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change is forcing Indians to migrate far from home</title>
			<link>https://lifestyle.livemint.com/news/big-story/climate-change-and-migration-indians-search-for-greener-pastures-111617348170986.html</link>
			<source url="https://lifestyle.livemint.com/news/big-story/climate-change-and-migration-indians-search-for-greener-pastures-111617348170986.html">Mint Lounge</source>
			<description>According to the Migration Data Portal, which provides comprehensive global migration statistics, &#34;in the first half of 2020 alone, disasters displaced 9.8 million people and remained the leading trigger of new internal displacements globally. Five countries accounted for nearly 75 per cent of the new internal displacements due to disasters in the first half of 2020 with India leading the pack, accounting for nearly three million people, followed by Bangladesh (2.5 million), Philippines (811,000), China (791,000) and Somalia (514,000).&#34; Delta regions that are home to 500 million people worldwide will contribute an inordinate share to such migration, since these areas are considered climate change hot spots, places where high levels of exposure to climate stressors coincide with high levels of vulnerability.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This is how badly climate change has hurt food production</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/2/this-is-how-badly-climate-change-has-hurt-food-production</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/4/2/this-is-how-badly-climate-change-has-hurt-food-production">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>The loss of productivity comes even as billions has been poured into improving agricultural production through the development of new seeds, sophisticated farm machinery and other technological advances. &#34;Even though globally agriculture is more productive, that greater productivity on average doesn’t translate into more climate resilience,&#34; said Ariel Ortiz&#45;Bobea, an author of the paper and associate professor at Cornell&#39;s Charles H. Dyson School of Applied Economics and Management. The damages to productivity growth aren’t evenly spread across regions. Warmer areas &#45; especially those in the tropics &#45; are more detrimentally affected. Ortiz&#45;Bobea said that coincides with many countries where agriculture makes up a bigger share of the economy.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>China sandstorms highlight threat of climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/03/china-sandstorms-highlight-threat-of-climate-crisis</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/apr/03/china-sandstorms-highlight-threat-of-climate-crisis">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Since 1978 China has been trying to combat encroaching sands from the Gobi Desert region by planting a series of forest strips through its northern areas. This &#34;Great Green Wall&#34; has been somewhat effective at reducing erosion and slowing desert expansion, but does little to knock down high-altitude dust blown in from afar.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Green Investing Is &#34;Definitely Not&#34; Going to Save Our Behinds</title>
			<link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2021/04/green-investing-definitely-not-going-to-save-us-climate-blackrock/</link>
			<source url="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2021/04/green-investing-definitely-not-going-to-save-us-climate-blackrock/">Mother Jones</source>
			<description>BlackRock manages about $7 trillion in assets and, with one of Wall Street’s biggest voices sounding the alarm about the need to deal with the climate crisis, the news was viewed as a pivotal moment for the financial community. But for &#91;Tariq&#93; Fancy, who now runs the digital learning nonprofit Rumie in Toronto, Canada, BlackRock&#39;s move, and the ones it has inspired, contain a fundamental flaw: the climate crisis can never be solved by today&#39;s free markets. &#34;It’s not because they are evil, it’s because the system is built to extract profits,&#34; he said.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Democracy against climate change</title>
			<link>https://voxeurop.eu/en/democracy-against-climate-change/</link>
			<source url="https://voxeurop.eu/en/democracy-against-climate-change/">voxeurop</source>
			<description>The campaign is a citizens initiative for carbon pricing in the EU, born after the suggestion of 27 Nobel Prize winners to &#34;shift taxes from labour to CO2 emissions&#34;. The text asks for revenues to flow into the ecological transition, while taxes on workers are expected to lower.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Climate change top challenge over the next decade, UNESCO global survey finds</title>
			<link>https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/03/1088812</link>
			<source url="https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/03/1088812">UN News</source>
			<description>The survey further showed that while 95 per cent of respondents extoll the importance of global cooperation in overcoming common challenges, only one in four felt confident that the world would be able to address these issues. UNESCO said that &#34;taken together, the results suggest not a lack of appreciation of the importance of multilateralism but rather a crisis of faith in its effectiveness.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Amazon Rain Forest Is in Worse Shape Than We Thought</title>
			<link>https://newrepublic.com/article/161686/amazon-rainforest-worse-shape-thought</link>
			<source url="https://newrepublic.com/article/161686/amazon-rainforest-worse-shape-thought">New Republic</source>
			<description>When you set fire to trees, for instance, as part of slash-and-burn farming or ranching, you&#39;re not just getting rid of a carbon-sucking machine. You&#39;re releasing methane, which is 84 times more potent than carbon dioxide and lingers in the atmosphere for a dozen years. You&#39;re changing the color of the earth’s surface from green to brown or black, which affects how the earth absorbs rather than reflects the sun&#39;s rays. And you&#39;re spraying black carbon into the atmosphere, which changes its reflectivity and traps more heat. All of these factors, the researchers found, work together in extremely complex and little-understood ways.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Climate change: Net zero targets are &#39;pie in the sky&#39;</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56596200</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56596200">BBC News</source>
			<description>&#34;The developed world has occupied almost 80% of the carbon space already, you have 800 million people who don't have access to electricity. You can't say that they have to go to net zero, they have the right to develop, they want to build skyscrapers and have a higher standard of living, you can't stop it,&#34; &#91;Raj Kumar Singh, India's minister for power&#92; told the meeting &#91;organised by the International Energy Agency&#92;.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>It took the Suez Canal crisis to highlight the scale of the polluting shipping sector</title>
			<link>https://www.climatechangenews.com/2021/04/01/took-suez-canal-crisis-highlight-scale-polluting-shipping-sector/</link>
			<source url="https://www.climatechangenews.com/2021/04/01/took-suez-canal-crisis-highlight-scale-polluting-shipping-sector/">Climate Home News</source>
			<description>It&#39;s not just the size of the ships; the world&#39;s fleet has quadrupled in size since the 1980s. That&#39;s increased the strain on our oceans by exacerbating underwater noise levels, harming whales and dolphins. It has caused the rise of plastic waste dumping, oil discharge and the shuttle of invasive species around the globe, causing the extinction of native plants and marine animals.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Decarbonisation in a fraught geopolitical landscape</title>
			<link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/energy/decarbonisation-in-a-fraught-geopolitical-landscape-76246</link>
			<source url="https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/energy/decarbonisation-in-a-fraught-geopolitical-landscape-76246">DownToEarth</source>
			<description>Inevitably, because the path to decarbonisation (and digitalisation) has already transcended the realm of run-of-the-mill economic competition to become embroiled in fraught geopolitics, attention has squarely turned onto the indispensable inputs that are required to produce them. Both the global decarbonisation of the economy and the fourth industrial revolution rely on rare earths and a growing number of other critical minerals (CRMs), such as lithium and cobalt, that are all highly geographically concentrated and vulnerable to disruption. Moreover, the amounts needed will skyrocket moving forward.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What can we do about climate migration&#63;</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/w3ct0xbl</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/w3ct0xbl">The Climate Question</source>
			<description>The intensification of conditions due to climate change means more people are being driven from their homes and land by sea level rises, storms, cyclones, drought, erosion, landslides, flooding and salinisation of the land. It's estimated that by 2050, one in every seven people in Bangladesh will become a climate migrant.
</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Melting ice sheets caused global sea levels to rise up to 18 metres, scientists say</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/melting-ice-sheets-caused-global-sea-levels-to-rise-up-to-18-metres-scientists-say-12262567</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/melting-ice-sheets-caused-global-sea-levels-to-rise-up-to-18-metres-scientists-say-12262567">Sky News</source>
			<description>New analysis of geological records show that at the end of the last ice age around 14,600 years ago, meltwater from the former North American and Eurasian ice sheets was actually actually driving the rise, rather than the oft-suspected Antarctic ice sheet.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Why are people not doing more about climate change?</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56500739</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56500739">BBC News</source>
			<description>We commissioned a survey of 1,009 Scots, conducted by Savanta ComRes, which suggests price is putting many people off making greener lifestyle choices.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What would different levels of global warming look like?</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2021/03/30/what-would-different-levels-of-global-warming-look-like</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2021/03/30/what-would-different-levels-of-global-warming-look-like">The Economist</source>
			<description>The purpose of pledges to stabilise temperature rise at close to 1.5°C is to avoid the worst of these consequences. But despite the commitments made in the Paris agreement &#45; and, in the years since, various countries’ plans to reduce their greenhouse-gas emissions to zero &#45; the world is still on track to exceed 2°C of warming. (Even if all countries meet their targets, climate scientists predict that temperatures will rise by 2.3°-2.4°C above pre-industrial levels by the end of the century.) A seemingly small difference in degrees will have a big impact on how habitable the world remains.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Elite minority of frequent flyers &#39;cause most of aviation's climate damage&#39;</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/mar/31/elite-minority-frequent-flyers-aviation-climate-damage-flights-environmental</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/mar/31/elite-minority-frequent-flyers-aviation-climate-damage-flights-environmental">The Guardian</source>
			<description>In the US, 12% of people took 66% of all flights, while in France 2% of people took half of the flights, the report says. In China 5% of households took 40% of flights and in India just 1% of households took 45% of all the flights.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Economists want &#39;drastic&#39; action to stop climate change&#58; Survey</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/3/30/economists-want-drastic-action-to-stop-climate-change-survey</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2021/3/30/economists-want-drastic-action-to-stop-climate-change-survey">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>The world saw more than 7,300 major natural disasters between 2000 and 2019, which killed some 1.2 million people and cost $3 trillion in damages, according to the UN Office on Disaster Risk Reduction. That compares with about 4,200 disasters, leading to 1.19 million killed and $1.6 trillion in losses during the 20 years previous, the data show.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Japan sees earliest cherry blossom since 1400s &#45; and scientists say it's down to climate change</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/japan-sees-earliest-cherry-blossom-since-1400s-and-scientists-say-its-down-to-climate-change-12260765</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/japan-sees-earliest-cherry-blossom-since-1400s-and-scientists-say-its-down-to-climate-change-12260765">Sky News</source>
			<description>Traditionally, cherry blossom season starts in early to mid-April with residents in Kyoto holding &#34;hanami&#34; celebrations underneath trees to watch the flowers bloom. The full bloom, or Sakura in Japanese, historically occurs on 17 April &#45; but in more recent times, warmer and earlier springs have meant earlier blooms, according to climate change experts.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Half a billion people may face heat of 56°C by 2100</title>
			<link>https://climatenewsnetwork.net/half-a-billion-people-may-face-heat-of-56c-by-2100/</link>
			<source url="https://climatenewsnetwork.net/half-a-billion-people-may-face-heat-of-56c-by-2100/">Climate News Network</source>
			<description>A new computational study in Geophysical Research Letters warns that the 1.5°C target could be passed by 2040, in just two decades. And with higher average temperatures over longer periods, there will inevitably be higher than average extremes of temperature, more often, for longer periods, and over wider ranges.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Renewables met 97% of Scotland&#39;s electricity demand in 2020</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56530424</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-56530424">BBC News</source>
			<description>Scotland has some of the most ambitious climate targets in the world, with its Climate Change Bill setting out a legally binding target of reaching net-zero emissions by 2045.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Last thing we need is a &#39;cosy consensus&#39; on climate crisis, warns Ed Miliband</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/mar/29/last-thing-we-need-is-a-cosy-consensus-on-climate-crisis-warns-ed-miliband</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/mar/29/last-thing-we-need-is-a-cosy-consensus-on-climate-crisis-warns-ed-miliband">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The summit this year is seen as a last chance to keep to the goals of the Paris agreement and also to limit temperature rises to well below 2C above pre-industrial levels, with an aspiration to stay below 1.5C within reach. It will be the UK&#39;s most important moment on the world stage for generations, he said, warning that the latest emission figures from the UN, which make clear the world is on course for a catastrophic 3C of warming, were being ignored by too many politicians. &#34;It is like these numbers are the embarrassing uncle we want to pretend does not exist &#45; so let’s talk about everything else, let’s talk about 2050, let’s talk about 2060 ... but we don’t have the luxury of time ... The pressure, the action has got to be now.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Britain decarbonised faster than any other rich country</title>
			<link>https://www.economist.com/britain/2021/02/15/how-britain-decarbonised-faster-than-any-other-rich-country</link>
			<source url="https://www.economist.com/britain/2021/02/15/how-britain-decarbonised-faster-than-any-other-rich-country">The Economist</source>
			<description>Although gas helped decarbonise Britain&#39;s grid, it is a hindrance when it comes to heating and transport. That is because Britain has one of the world’s most robust and extensive infrastructures for moving gas around; 85% of its 29m homes are heated with gas boilers. In Germany 47% are. Decades of investment in the gas grid mean that Britain&#39;s electricity grid is not as robust as it needs to be in order to carry the extra power required to replace gas in the heating of Britain’s homes. If it is to charge all the cars and run all the heat pumps, the grid will need to be upgraded at a cost of tens of billions of pounds.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>The hard truths of climate change — by the numbers</title>
			<link>https://www.nature.com/immersive/d41586-019-02711-4/index.html?utm_source=pocket-chrome-recs</link>
			<source url="https://www.nature.com/immersive/d41586-019-02711-4/index.html?utm_source=pocket-chrome-recs">Nature</source>
			<description>So far, there is little evidence that political leaders are willing or able to meet their collective Paris targets. Even so, some veteran climate experts see hope in the strikes, marches and other protests that are taking place around the world. &#34;Civil disobedience erupts when injustice has been collectively determined to be unbearable,&#34; says Christiana Figueres, who helped to usher in the Paris agreement as head of the UN climate convention in 2015. &#34;And that is where we are today.&#34;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Over 30 million people &#39;one step away from starvation&#39;, UN warns</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/mar/24/over-30-million-people-one-step-away-from-starvation-un-warns</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/mar/24/over-30-million-people-one-step-away-from-starvation-un-warns">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Acute hunger is being driven by conflict, climate shocks and the Covid pandemic, and, in some places, compounded by storms of desert locusts.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cutting Your Carbon Footprint Matters a Lot — If You’re Rich</title>
			<link>https://www.motherjones.com/environment/2021/03/cutting-your-carbon-footprint-matters-a-lot-if-youre-rich/</link>
			<source url="https://www.motherjones.com/environment/2021/03/cutting-your-carbon-footprint-matters-a-lot-if-youre-rich/">Mother Jones</source>
			<description>Individual responsibility has become something of a flashpoint in the climate discourse. On the one hand, oil companies love to harp on about personal carbon footprints as a way of distracting from their much larger contributions to the climate crisis, both through the fossil fuel products they make and their longstanding, ongoing efforts to delay climate action and misinform the public. At the same time, prominent journalists and scientists have waved off individual climate actions as a distraction from the systemic changes that are needed to solve the crisis—changes like overhauling our electricity and transit systems through governmental investments in clean energy, better regulation, and carbon pricing. They&#39;re joined by a growing chorus of climate justice advocates who rightly point out that asking poor people to make difficult dietary shifts or give up the car they need to get to work is completely unfair.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK government scraps green homes grant after six months</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/27/uk-government-scraps-green-homes-grant-after-six-months</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/27/uk-government-scraps-green-homes-grant-after-six-months">The Guardian</source>
			<description>The abandonment of the £1.5bn programme, which offered households grants of up to £5,000 or £10,000 to put in insulation or low-carbon heating, leaves the UK without a plan for tackling one of the biggest sources of greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>What Happened to a Climate Change Denier&#39;s 10-Year Wager?</title>
			<link>https://news.slashdot.org/story/21/03/27/1831204/what-happened-to-a-climate-change-deniers-10-year-wager</link>
			<source url="https://news.slashdot.org/story/21/03/27/1831204/what-happened-to-a-climate-change-deniers-10-year-wager">Slashdot</source>
			<description>In January of 2011, Slashdot reported on AccuWeather meteorologist Joe Bastardi&#39;s wager for climate scientists. He bet the earth would &#34;cool .1 to .2 Celsius in the next ten years, according to objective satellite data.&#34;... The wager would have come due in January of 2021. As it turns out, the linear trend of global mean temperatures shows the earth actually warmed by just over 0.5C over the period according to satellite data.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Dimming the sun'&#58; &#36;100m geoengineering research programme proposed</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/25/top-us-scientists-back-100m-geoengineering-research-proposal</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/25/top-us-scientists-back-100m-geoengineering-research-proposal">The Guardian</source>
			<description>&quot;The US solar geoengineering research programme should be all about helping society make more informed decisions,&quot; said Prof Chris Field of Stanford University, who was chair of the committee that wrote the report. &quot;Based on all of the evidence from social science, natural science, and technology, this research programme could either indicate that solar geoengineering should not be considered further, or conclude that it warrants additional effort.&quot;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The World Is Stuck With Decades of New Plastic It Can't Recycle</title>
			<link>https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-world-is-stuck-with-decades-of-new-plastic-it-can-t-recycle</link>
			<source url="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-world-is-stuck-with-decades-of-new-plastic-it-can-t-recycle">Quartz</source>
			<description>Recycling is not the solution. Only 9% of all plastic produced gets recycled—and even that low number is likely a gross overestimation. Plastic waste exported from the country where it was discarded counts as “recycled,” regardless of its actual fate. And virgin plastic is so cheap that there is no financial incentive for companies to use recycled plastic in their products. In short, plastic recycling is a myth—and always has been.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		

		<item>
			<title>Pollution from fossil fuel combustion deadlier than previously thought</title>
			<link>https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/hsph-in-the-news/pollution-from-fossil-fuel-combustion-deadlier-than-previously-thought</link>
			<source url="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/hsph-in-the-news/pollution-from-fossil-fuel-combustion-deadlier-than-previously-thought">Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health</source>
			<description>A new study found that fine particulate pollution generated by the burning of fossil fuels was responsible for one in five early deaths worldwide in 2018—far more than previously thought. Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health’s Aaron Bernstein said that the people most at risk are those “who can least afford it.”</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UK government falters in delivering green recovery</title>
			<link>https://energymonitor.ai/policy/green-deals/uk-government-falters-delivering-green-covid-19-recovery-plan</link>
			<source url="https://energymonitor.ai/policy/green-deals/uk-government-falters-delivering-green-covid-19-recovery-plan">Energy Monitor</source>
			<description>Meanwhile, the Climate Change Committee, the body that advises government on how to meet its statutory emissions reduction goals, has suggested the UK needs to scale up public and private investment to £50bn a year by 2030 to achieve its net-zero goals. Looking across the Atlantic, the Institute of Public Policy Research (IPPR) has suggested that, to mirror President Joe Biden’s $1.9trn stimulus proposal, the UK should embark on a recovery programme worth £190bn.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hundreds of millions of people could be affected by heatwaves within 30 years - study</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/hundreds-of-millions-of-people-could-be-affected-heatwaves-within-30-years-study-12254585</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/hundreds-of-millions-of-people-could-be-affected-heatwaves-within-30-years-study-12254585">Sky News</source>
			<description>Earlier this month, Oxford University researchers estimated that there had already been 1,500 UK deaths attributable to climate change events. Scientists linked the deaths to heatwaves in 2003 and 2018, which saw record temperatures broken in cities such as Glasgow and Belfast.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Small nuclear power plants no use in climate crisis</title>
			<link>https://climatenewsnetwork.net/small-nuclear-power-plants-no-use-in-climate-crisis/</link>
			<source url="https://climatenewsnetwork.net/small-nuclear-power-plants-no-use-in-climate-crisis/">Climate News Network</source>
			<description>There is a clear crossover between civil and nuclear industries in the US, the UK, China, Russia and France. This is made more obvious because of the few countries that have renounced nuclear weapons − for example only Germany, Italy and Spain have shown no interest in building any kind of nuclear station. This is simply because renewables are cheaper and produce low carbon power far more quickly.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How bad for the climate is bingeing Netflix?</title>
			<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/netflix-stream-binge-emissions-study-b1820762.html</link>
			<source url="https://www.independent.co.uk/climate-change/netflix-stream-binge-emissions-study-b1820762.html">The Independent</source>
			<description>Using the data, Netflix has revealed some stats on its emissions for the first time. The company says that one hour of streaming uses less than 100g CO2 equivalent (emissions from all greenhouse gases, not just CO2). Wired reports that this is similar to driving a car for a quarter of a mile, or running a 1,000-watt air-conditioning unit for 15 minutes in the US (and for 40 minutes in Europe).</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
  		<item>
    			<title>UK seeks to drill more oil and gas from North Sea</title>
			<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56503588</link>
			<source url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-56503588">BBC News</source>
			<description>Mel Evans from Greenpeace said: “This is a colossal failure. The UK will make a fool of itself in the run-up to hosting the COP26 global climate talks if our energy minister signs off on new oil and gas licences that serve to rip up the Paris Agreement (the world deal to hold global temperature rise to 1.5C)."</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Big banks’ trillion-dollar finance for fossil fuels ‘shocking’, says report</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/24/big-banks-trillion-dollar-finance-for-fossil-fuels-shocking-says-report</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/24/big-banks-trillion-dollar-finance-for-fossil-fuels-shocking-says-report">The Guardian</source>
			<description>A commitment to be net zero by 2050 has been made by 17 of the 60 banks, but the report describes the pledges as “dangerously weak, half-baked, or vague”, arguing that action is needed today. Some banks have policies that block finance for coal, the dirtiest fossil fuel, but almost two-thirds of funding is for oil and gas companies.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unpaid environmental damages from fossil fuels are a $600B annual subsidy</title>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/unpaid-environmental-damages-from-fossil-fuels-are-a-600b-annual-subsidy</link>
			<source url="https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/unpaid-environmental-damages-from-fossil-fuels-are-a-600b-annual-subsidy">Ars Technica</source>
			<description>The producers' slice of the pie comes in at $71 billion in 2018 and averaged $62 billion over the study period. Gasoline was the largest portion of that, averaging $25 billion, with coal and natural gas varying with the changing usage pattern. Here, the split was quite different, with gasoline and diesel coming in at under $50 billion, natural gas at about $20 billion, and coal at about $10 billion.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ending Fossil Fuel Subsidies the Wrong Way Could End Up Hurting the Poor</title>
			<link>https://truthout.org/articles/elite-led-efforts-to-end-fossil-fuel-subsidies-have-a-hidden-neoliberal-agenda</link>
			<source url="https://truthout.org/articles/elite-led-efforts-to-end-fossil-fuel-subsidies-have-a-hidden-neoliberal-agenda">Truthout</source>
			<description>If the dollar value of subsidies has indeed been inflated for political and ideological purposes, then the same can be said of the emissions reductions estimates that derive from them. The IMF maintains that, if users paid the “full price” for fossil-based energy, consumption would fall and a more efficient use of energy would eventually follow. But the relationship between prices, fossil fuel use, and emissions reductions is based on what economists call “elasticities.” Research has shown that the “price-demand ratio” can be quite pronounced when consumers have alternative energy options. But when alternatives don’t exist—which is often the case—increases in prices produce a “low to moderate” reduction in demand. According to the IMF, “Consistent, country-level models of how fossil fuel use responds to price reform are not yet available on a wide scale.” In other words, the IMF’s assertion that “getting energy prices right” will dramatically curtail energy use is politically convenient, but it is not always supported by the data.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>JP Morgan warns of end to human life in climate report</title>
			<link>https://www.telegraph.co.uk/environment/2020/02/21/jp-morgan-warns-end-human-life-leaked-climate-report</link>
			<source url="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/environment/2020/02/21/jp-morgan-warns-end-human-life-leaked-climate-report">The Telegraph</source>
			<description>According to JP Morgan's research, titled 'Risky business: the climate and the macroeconomy', the impact of climate change will be broad and devastating. The economists call on world leaders to introduce a global carbon tax to prevent a meltdown, saying no other measure is likely to be enough.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Climate Anxiety Is an Overwhelmingly White Phenomenon</title>
			<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-unbearable-whiteness-of-climate-anxiety</link>
			<source url="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-unbearable-whiteness-of-climate-anxiety">Scientific American</source>
			<description>Instead of asking “What can I do to stop feeling so anxious?”, “What can I do to save the planet?” and “What hope is there?”, people with privilege can be asking “Who am I?” and “How am I connected to all of this?” The answers reveal that we are deeply interconnected with the well-being of others on this planet, and that there are traditions of environmental stewardship that can be guides for where we need to go from here.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It’s Time to Replace Ambition with Adaptation</title>
			<link>https://forge.medium.com/its-time-to-replace-ambition-with-adaptation-945880f183f1</link>
			<source url="https://forge.medium.com/its-time-to-replace-ambition-with-adaptation-945880f183f1">Forge</source>
			<description>Facing a world that seems to get worse by the hour, an urgent climate emergency that is certain to dismantle our global supply chains in a way that makes Covid-19 look quaint, and a new understanding of how to live at a slower pace, we have to ask: Does following our personal and narrowly defined ambition, at the cost of all other skills and possibly our own health, make much sense anymore?</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bitcoin Is Terrible For The Planet. Now There Are Better Choices</title>
			<link>https://www.wbur.org/cognoscenti/2021/03/22/bitcoin-crytocurrency-environment-climate-energy-fred-hewett</link>
			<source url="https://www.wbur.org/cognoscenti/2021/03/22/bitcoin-crytocurrency-environment-climate-energy-fred-hewett">WBUR</source>
			<description>Bitcoin still commands strong support in libertarian circles, and that’s significant because right-wing ideologies are historically disdainful of government action to address climate change. David Golumbia’s "The Politics of Bitcoin" illuminates the deep connections between crypto-anarchist Bitcoin pioneers and the free-market fundamentalism that still pervades a substantial segment of the Bitcoin community.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Climate Crisis Is Worse Than You Can Imagine. Here’s What Happens If You Try.</title>
			<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/the-climate-crisis-is-worse-than-you-can-imagine-heres-what-happens-if-you-try</link>
			<source url="https://www.propublica.org/article/the-climate-crisis-is-worse-than-you-can-imagine-heres-what-happens-if-you-try">ProPublica</source>
			<description>So how, with our limited human minds, do we attend enough to make real progress? How do we not flinch and look away? The truth of what is happening shakes the foundations of our sense of self. It asserts a distorting gravity, bending our priorities and warping our whole lives. The overt denialists are easy villains, the monsters who look like monsters. But the rest of us, much of the time, wear pretty green masks over our self-interest and denial, and then go about our days. Then each morning we wake to a new headline like: “The planet is dying faster than we thought.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India Targets Climate Activists With the Help of Big Tech</title>
			<link>https://theintercept.com/2021/02/27/india-climate-activists-twitter-google-facebook</link>
			<source url="https://theintercept.com/2021/02/27/india-climate-activists-twitter-google-facebook">The Intercept</source>
			<description>For tech companies like Facebook, Google, Twitter, and Zoom, India under Modi has turned into a harsh moment of truth. In North America and Europe, these companies are going to great lengths to show that they can be trusted to regulate hate speech and harmful conspiracies on their platforms while protecting the freedom to speak, debate, and disagree that is integral to any healthy society. But in India, where helping governments hunt and imprison peaceful activists and amplify hate appears to be the price of access to a huge and growing market, “all of those arguments have gone out the window,” one activist told me. And for a simple reason: “They are profiting from this harm.”</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Fossilized plants discovered a mile beneath Greenland ice sheet</title>
			<link>https://newatlas.com/environment/fossilized-plants-greenland-ice-sheet</link>
			<source url="https://newatlas.com/environment/fossilized-plants-greenland-ice-sheet">New Atlas</source>
			<description>Finding these frozen plants may sound like an intriguing curiosity, but the researchers say there’s a concerning implication to the discovery. It suggests that the Greenland Ice Sheet is more susceptible to climate change than anticipated – which is a problem, considering it contains enough ice that, if it were to completely melt, it would raise sea levels by 7.2 m (24 ft) alone. Worse still, a recent report found that the ice sheet has lost 3.8 trillion tonnes of ice since 1992, and the rate is accelerating.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Soothe Yourself With a Picture Book About the Internet Dying</title>
			<link>https://www.wired.com/story/soothe-yourself-with-a-picture-book-about-the-internet-dying</link>
			<source url="https://www.wired.com/story/soothe-yourself-with-a-picture-book-about-the-internet-dying">WIRED</source>
			<description>Illustrated by Rinee Shah and written in the style of Genesis (as in the Book of, not the band), &#39;OFF&#58; The Day the Internet Died (A Bedtime Fantasy)&#39; invites readers to imagine weeks, decades, centuries without the internet. The characters take walks IRL; they play Minecraft with sticks and leaves; they get “way into” D&#38;D.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The economics of covering California’s water system with solar panels</title>
			<link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/the-economics-of-covering-californias-water-system-with-solar-panels</link>
			<source url="https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/03/the-economics-of-covering-californias-water-system-with-solar-panels">Ars Technica</source>
			<description>There are a number of things, however, that make these calculations more complicated than the economic analysis would suggest. For example, the cabling over the canals could potentially complicate maintenance, even if said maintenance wouldn't have to happen as often. And the canals aren't always located near sites that would be easy to connect to California's power grid. Unlike a more compact site, wiring up a long, stretched-out row of panels could add considerably to the cost.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Methane Spewing Mines Are as Bad For The Climate as Their Coal</title>
			<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-19/coal-mines-seen-posing-additional-climate-threat-with-gas-leaks</link>
			<source url="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-19/coal-mines-seen-posing-additional-climate-threat-with-gas-leaks">Bloomberg</source>
			<description>Global Energy Monitor examined potential methane releases at 432 proposed new or expanded coal mines, and found that at the gassiest of them the leaks could account for half of their total greenhouse gas impact. If all were built, about 13.5 million tons of methane would be released annually, doing the damage of an equivalent of more than 1 billion tons of CO2.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Oil firms knew decades ago fossil fuels posed grave health risks, files reveal</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/oil-industry-fossil-fuels-air-pollution-documents</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/oil-industry-fossil-fuels-air-pollution-documents">The Guardian</source>
			<description>In an internal technical report in 1968, Shell [warned] that air pollution "may, in extreme situations, be deleterious to health" and [acknowledged] the oil industry “reluctantly” must accept that cars "are by far the greatest sources of air pollution". The report states that sulphur dioxide, given off by the burning of oil, can cause “difficulty in breathing” while nitrogen dioxide, also given off by vehicles and power plants, can cause lung damage and that “there will be a clamor to reduce [nitrogen dioxide] emissions, probably based on suspected long-term chronic effects”.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>Global heating : the vital statistics from a warming world</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/ng-interactive/2020/oct/05/climate-data-dashboard-carbon-atmosphere-sea-level-arctic-ice</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/ng-interactive/2020/oct/05/climate-data-dashboard-carbon-atmosphere-sea-level-arctic-ice">The Guardian</source>
			<description>This page will track a selection of the planet’s vital signs, from carbon dioxide levels to Arctic sea ice, and act as a reference point. The graphs are fed from data sources including Nasa, the US National Snow and Ice Data Center and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. They will automatically update and follow the Earth’s climate trajectory, providing a visual representation of the climate crisis.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The perfect storm: Global food prices hit six-year high</title>
			<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/program/counting-the-cost/2021/3/13/the-perfect-storm-global-food-prices-hit-six-year-high</link>
			<source url="https://www.aljazeera.com/program/counting-the-cost/2021/3/13/the-perfect-storm-global-food-prices-hit-six-year-high">Al Jazeera</source>
			<description>Increasing demand from China, adverse weather conditions and pandemic-hit supply chains are all pushing up food prices.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Peer-reviewed research in psychology on the impacts of discussing difficult futures such as societal collapse</title>
			<link>http://iflas.blogspot.com/2021/02/peer-reviewed-research-in-psychology-on.html</link>
			<source url="http://iflas.blogspot.com/2021/02/peer-reviewed-research-in-psychology-on.html">IFLAS</source>
			<description>This paper presents a review of psychology research that can help people begin to assess the different ways they can responsibly support each other to talk about their thoughts and feelings on their perceptions of societal disruption and collapse, at home and abroad, due to environmental and climate change. It includes a summary of a review of published studies in psychology on matters of anticipating difficult futures, including vulnerability, disruption, disaster, suffering and mortality. The claims by both specialists and non-specialists that collapse anticipation is necessarily harmful to mental health and social engagement is shown to be theoretically and empirically weak.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Feeding cows seaweed could cut their methane emissions by 82&#37;, scientists say</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/cows-seaweed-methane-emissions-scientists</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/mar/18/cows-seaweed-methane-emissions-scientists">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Agriculture makes up about 10&#37; of emissions in the US, much of it from cows that belch, and to a lesser extent, fart out methane. This has led to some climate campaigners to urge people to eat less meat but the UC Davis researchers said that existing meat production could be made better for the climate by putting seaweed on the menu for cattle.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Net zero 'not enough' to combat climate change, Environment Agency warns</title>
			<link>https://news.sky.com/story/net-zero-not-enough-to-combat-climate-change-environment-agency-warns-12247271</link>
			<source url="https://news.sky.com/story/net-zero-not-enough-to-combat-climate-change-environment-agency-warns-12247271">Sky News</source>
			<description>Speaking at the Whitehall and Industry Group's Net Zero Roundtable, Sir James warned the increased frequency of extreme weather events such as flooding and droughts, along with coastal erosion and damage to biodiversity, was as a result of average global temperatures rising to 1C above pre-industrial temperatures.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>


		<item>
			<title>We’re Hurtling Toward Global Suicide</title>
			<link>https://newrepublic.com/article/161575/climate-change-effects-hurtling-toward-global-suicide</link>
			<source url="https://newrepublic.com/article/161575/climate-change-effects-hurtling-toward-global-suicide">New Republic</source>
			<description>A strange sort of faith lies at the core of mainstream climate advocacy—a largely unexamined belief that the very system that got us into this mess is the one that will get us out of it. For a community putatively committed to scientific empiricism, this is an extraordinary conviction. Despite reams of increasingly apocalyptic research, and despite 25 years of largely fruitless international climate negotiations, carbon emissions have continued to rise, and temperatures along with them. We are at nearly 1.2 degrees Celsius of warming already—more than 2 degrees Fahrenheit over preindustrial averages—and three-tenths of a degree away from blowing the Paris accord’s aspiration to limit warming to a still-calamitous 1.5 degrees Celsius. Scientists now expect us to hit that threshold in about 10 years, and large swaths of the Arctic have been in actual flames for two summers running, but most governments with the option to do so are still feeding the beast that got us here.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Revenge of the nerds&#58; Disaster risk reduction and climate change</title>
			<link>https://www.thenewhumanitarian.org/opinion/2021/3/18/revenge-of-the-nerds-disaster-risk-reduction-and-climate-change</link>
			<source url="https://www.thenewhumanitarian.org/opinion/2021/3/18/revenge-of-the-nerds-disaster-risk-reduction-and-climate-change">The New Humanitarian</source>
			<description>Investing in disaster risk reduction isn’t a matter of saving for a rainy day&#59;	it’s jerking the wheel to avoid the boulder that is quite clearly on the road ahead. People should not have to be starving, buried under rubble, or flooded out of their homes before the world pays attention.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It's unavoidable&#58; we must ban fossil fuels to save our planet. Here's how we do it</title>
			<link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/mar/09/its-unavoidable-we-must-ban-fossil-fuels-to-save-our-planet-heres-how-we-do-it</link>
			<source url="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/mar/09/its-unavoidable-we-must-ban-fossil-fuels-to-save-our-planet-heres-how-we-do-it">The Guardian</source>
			<description>Since we have already drawn down over 120 Gt of CO2 from this carbon budget, we have now less than 300 Gt left. Combining the proved fossil fuel reserves reported in British Petroleum’s Statistical Review of World Energy with CO2 emission factors from the IPCC yields 3,600 Gt of CO2 emissions. This means that we can only afford to burn one twelfth of the fossil fuels we have already found. And this does not account for any greenhouse gas emissions from the ongoing melting of permafrost. The Arctic region alone is estimated to have 1,500 Gt of carbon stored in its soils, some of which is already being converted to CO2 by microbes and released into the atmosphere.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Met Office&#58; Atmospheric CO2 now hitting 50&#37; higher than pre-industrial levels</title>
			<link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/met-office-atmospheric-co2-now-hitting-50-higher-than-pre-industrial-levels</link>
			<source url="https://www.carbonbrief.org/met-office-atmospheric-co2-now-hitting-50-higher-than-pre-industrial-levels">Carbon Brief</source>
			<description>As human-driven emissions have increased, the rise in CO2 has accelerated. It took over 200 years to reach a 25&#37; increase by 1986. By 2011 – 25 years later – the increase reached 40&#37;. Now after one more decade it is reaching 50&#37;.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Trillions For Oil, Millions For EVs&#58; The Big Lie Of Ineffectual Government</title>
			<link>https://jalopnik.com/trillions-for-oil-millions-for-evs-the-big-lie-of-ine-1846476419</link>
			<source url="https://jalopnik.com/trillions-for-oil-millions-for-evs-the-big-lie-of-ine-1846476419">Jalopnik</source>
			<description>Ignoring the fact that every dollar spent subsidizing oil diverts money away from other societally valuable enterprises &#45; say public health, mass transit or feeding the hungry &#45; the dollars are still staggering. Internationally, depending on the price of oil, governments provide up to $1 trillion in subsidies, each year. Add costs related to climate change and other despoiling of the environment, plus war and negative health impacts, and, according to a 2015 study by the International Monetary Fund, the unpaid costs of fossil fuels clock in each year at around $5.3 trillion annually &#45; or a breathtaking $10 million a minute. Don’t hold us to it, but that’s more money even than Jeff Bezos makes.</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Mediocrity Is The Enemy Of The Solution</title>
			<link>https://cleantechnica.com/2020/12/16/mediocrity-is-the-enemy-of-the-solution</link>
			<source url="https://cleantechnica.com/2020/12/16/mediocrity-is-the-enemy-of-the-solution">CleanTechnica</source>
			<description>Photosynthesis is only 1&#37; efficient. Solar panels are 20&#37; efficient. Thus, a solar panel needs 1/20th the land as a biofuel to produce the same energy. On top of that, an electric car uses 1/4th the energy as an internal-combustion engine car to go the same distance. Thus, a battery-electric car running on solar energy uses 1/80th the land as an ethanol-fueled car.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Aral Sea</title>
			<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aral_Sea</link>
			<source url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aral_Sea">Wikipedia</source>
			<description>Formerly the fourth largest lake in the world with an area of 68,000 km2 (26,300 sq mi), the Aral Sea began shrinking in the 1960s after the rivers that fed it were diverted by Soviet irrigation projects...  The Aral Sea region is heavily polluted, with consequent serious public health problems. UNESCO has added historical documents concerning the Aral Sea to its Memory of the World Register as a resource to study the environmental tragedy.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>S2E53: Paul Kingsnorth on the shared roots of climate crisis, transhumanism, &#38; immortality</title>
			<link>https://nori.com/podcasts/reversing-climate-change/S2E53-Paul-Kingsnorth-on-the-shared-roots-of-climate-crisis--transhumanism---immortality-era5om</link>
			<source url="https://nori.com/podcasts/reversing-climate-change/S2E53-Paul-Kingsnorth-on-the-shared-roots-of-climate-crisis--transhumanism---immortality-era5om">Reversing Climate Change</source>
			<description>Paul shares his take on capitalism versus distributism, describing how systems of radical local democracy would root us in community and prevent the kind of scale that leads to tyranny.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Industrial Fishing Creates More CO2 Emissions Than Air Travel</title>
			<link>https://time.com/5947430/bottom-trawling-carbon-emissions-study</link>
			<source url="https://time.com/5947430/bottom-trawling-carbon-emissions-study">TIME</source>
			<description>According to calculations conducted by the report’s 26 authors, bottom trawling is responsible for one gigaton of carbon emissions a year—a higher annual total than (pre-pandemic) aviation emissions. Not only does the practice contribute to climate change, it is extremely damaging to ocean biodiversity—the “equivalent of ploughing an old-growth forest into the ground, over and over and over again until there is nothing left” according to lead author Enric Sala, a marine biologist who is also National Geographic’s Explorer in Residence.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Buying a Tesla in Bitcoins cancels 4 times the CO2 savings for its whole lifetime</title>
			<link>https://medium.com/crypto-lucid/buying-a-tesla-in-bitcoins-cancels-4-times-the-co2-savings-for-its-whole-lifetime-c28b042e3b9a</link>
			<source url="https://medium.com/crypto-lucid/buying-a-tesla-in-bitcoins-cancels-4-times-the-co2-savings-for-its-whole-lifetime-c28b042e3b9a">Crypto Lucid</source>
			<description>Suppose you want to buy this car with gold. It would take 3 to 5 &#91;times&#93; less energy to mine this gold than to mine the same value in Bitcoins.</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
